<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parenting on Tinu Alikor</title>
    <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/parenting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parenting on Tinu Alikor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/parenting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mumgry</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG</url>
          
            <title>Mumgry</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Have you heard of the term Hangry? It’s a clever portmanteau of hungry and angry, and an adjective that describes being irritable due to hunger, a term to describe that feeling you get when you’re hungry, and about to knock someone the hell out if you don’t get some food fast!
Well I’ve felt like that often, so I’m known for carrying around snacks and planning my life around where the nearest eatery is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/two-happy-kids_hu8bd73f293d04bbc53f400c406222be67_1908490_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Now I&amp;rsquo;ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?! I remember before my daughter was born jokingly but seriously asking people with multiple kids for tips on how to cope with two kids….no one responded. At first I thought, that&amp;rsquo;s just rude really…a girl just needs some advice, and now I realise that everyone is full on blagging their way through parenthood and no one can offer any tips because some of their survival techniques are unconventional or tailor made to suit them, or they&amp;rsquo;re simply just surviving!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroin, carbs and a stable pay cheque</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Heroin, carbs and a stable pay cheque</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>“The three biggest addictions are heroin, carbs, and a stable pay cheque” according to Nassim Taleb.
I’m inclined to believe him! I’m presently trying to get a grip of two of these addictions…Thankfully I have never battled with heroin, the closest I’ve got to substance abuse has been a tea addiction! I didn’t even realise I was addicted until I decided to give it up for Lent….and the hulk appeared every morning instead of the amenable me….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Sonshine</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>My Sonshine</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>This one. This brilliant, energetic, bold, adventurous, talkative, loving, mischievous boy with endless curiosity is my biggest test. He’s the child you’ll find in the sandpit after a huge downfall of rain playing snow angels in the mud. He’s the one that could find puddles in the desert and could give a puma a run for its money. The one you’ll find moving furniture to scale the table, or pulling the blender out of the cupboard to see how it works, or trying to hang from the window ledge so he can see the bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolutely Fabulous</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 05:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/babies_hu9254ecaebb10959bdf27619441dc4657_438742_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG</url>
          
            <title>Absolutely Fabulous</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>I saw a post the other day that made me laugh…
“None of this new year new me bollocks, last year I was fabulous and next year I will be fabulous!”
Very amusing, and vaguely relevant to me, I’m fabulous some days, possibly two days a week, but honestly, I think it’s BS. Maybe not a new me, but a better version of myself wouldn’t hurt, perhaps like a software update!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adulting</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 16:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Adulting</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Last year I became a member of a club that no one wants to talk about. A club in which membership is one of the most painful experiences most will face in their lifetime and all are pretty much powerless to avoid. We found out we were expecting a baby in December 2017, excited and full of hope and expectation we celebrated.
 As tradition encourages we were hoping to share our good news after the first scan at 12 weeks….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail Like a Boss</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/images/feature_hu922ba9b63a8233a3c6308bd992b0acb5_4597736_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Fail Like a Boss</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School. Apparently he has passed his probationary period! Yay!! ! But a probationary period….so he can pass or fail? Eurgh…please tell me they’re not starting this already! He’s 2!!! He can’t fail!! Surely?
I then began questioning myself and why I took issue with the suggestion of a probationary period and the thought that my child may be rejected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planned Boob Strikes Are Ok</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 09:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/images/feature_hu9975dff1fa10e7614cba043485ce311b_267554_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Planned Boob Strikes Are Ok</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Emergency ones are not! In other words, choosing not to breastfeed is ok. Being forced to stop is not!
It’s National Breast-Feeding week!! Let’s talk food….or should I say food provision…..or should I say shame ridden, guilt provoking, nurturing, painful, stressful, bonding, life sustaining breastfeeding!
It can be all of these things and more, it is truly a personal experience and can be so different for each individual, provoking so many conflicting and often overwhelming emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Me a Priority</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/images/feature_hu275acd3f4b5175c7aad91a0d8cf92ccb_183840_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Make Me a Priority</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>I’m wearing sandals with ashy feet, an unironed t-shirt with a food stain or four, stretchy hareem pants and a multi coloured headscarf wrapped around sprouting doo doo plaits….and yes I left my house looking like this. Without even a second thought. Without even considering that I may be SEEN by someone who’s not partially sighted AND colourblind. And yes I still continued, offending my former self and every self confessed diva who looks upon me either with sympathy, disgust or that knowing smile from a fellow mum who’s also lost her mojo!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>