<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tinu Alikor</title>
    <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tinu Alikor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 06:01:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tinualikor.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/about/</guid>
      <description>Mother-of-two, Tinu Alikor, also known as Tee or Tin Tin, has written for publications including The Observer and interviewed world leaders for Sky News. She has worked for the BBC, most notably recorded and presented programmes for BBC Radio 4 and BBC 1.
London born and raised in a single parent home, but presently shuffling between Zurich and London with her brood, she has lived and worked globally and enjoys travelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/podcast/</guid>
      <description> Coming soon!! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech mums</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/tech_mums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/tech_mums/</guid>
      <description>A group based in Zurich Switzerland for parents to gain useful technical skills provided by expert tutors in the industry with childcare. Have you always wanted to learn to code? Build your own website? Learn a new skill? Challenged by finding time and childcare? This could be just what you need.
We are passionate about technology and excited about getting women into technology roles, hoping to change the tech environment and make it more flexible for women!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love yourself</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/love-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/love-yourself/</guid>
      <description>This blog is for everyone who contacted me in private or public about one of my previous blogs ‘ Freedom’. I was brought to tears by you reaching out to share your stories with me. I’m touched by the strength in your daily struggles and the memories that you hold on to. I’m inspired by you. Thank you for reaching out, thank you for sharing. Vulnerability is not weakness, it’s powerful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We’re all equal in the sky…</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</guid>
      <description>We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/freedom/</guid>
      <description>Growing up without a father I always wondered what happened between my parents. In my naivety and innocence I questioned what part I had played in my father leaving before I was 3, and what I could have done to get him to stay.
 At 16 I went in search for a father who had not responded to any of my phone calls or letters. Who had never contacted me on my birthday or even when he was told I had been undergoing a series of potentially life threatening surgeries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say Yes</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/say-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/say-yes/</guid>
      <description>We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/new-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Today, I’m diving head first into my blog. I’m just as clueless about the start as i am about the finish. But here I am hoping to share my journey with you and express myself creatively, prompted by change, displacement, fear, love, growth, freedom, happiness, adventure and an overwhelming feeling that this is what I’m meant to do….this is what I need to do, and for once it’s something just for me….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planned Boob Strikes Are Ok</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 09:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</guid>
      <description>Emergency ones are not! In other words, choosing not to breastfeed is ok. Being forced to stop is not!
It’s National Breast-Feeding week!! Let’s talk food….or should I say food provision…..or should I say shame ridden, guilt provoking, nurturing, painful, stressful, bonding, life sustaining breastfeeding!
It can be all of these things and more, it is truly a personal experience and can be so different for each individual, provoking so many conflicting and often overwhelming emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Me a Priority</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/make-me-a-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/make-me-a-priority/</guid>
      <description>I’m wearing sandals with ashy feet, an unironed t-shirt with a food stain or four, stretchy hareem pants and a multi coloured headscarf wrapped around sprouting doo doo plaits….and yes I left my house looking like this. Without even a second thought. Without even considering that I may be SEEN by someone who’s not partially sighted AND colourblind. And yes I still continued, offending my former self and every self confessed diva who looks upon me either with sympathy, disgust or that knowing smile from a fellow mum who’s also lost her mojo!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>