<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Tinu Alikor</title>
        <link>https://tinualikor.com/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Tinu Alikor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>It&#39;s not you it&#39;s me</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-not-you-its-me/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-not-you-its-me/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Self awareness</category>
            
                <category>Progress</category>
            
                <category>happiness</category>
            
                <category>Affirmations</category>
            
                <category>Reality</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-not-you-its-me/images/photoboth_huc18515d924251ced3558badb75757d83_799451_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>These words have chimed in my direction a few times.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;These words have chimed in my direction a few times. What they are likely to actually mean is, it is you and the truth is just too difficult or awkward to recite, so avoidance it is! We’re surrounded by euphemisms and indirect statements that don’t give us the reality we need to hear. I’m all for being gentle and if the white lie protects and restores then perhaps it’s ok for the greater good…for now. But too often little white lies are huge pink elephants in the room and the lies give us a temporary false sense of security and don’t help us to face the issues that we have or that we need to address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been in a situation where the reason being spouted by someone for a decision doesn’t feel genuine? Or someone is treating you in a way that you don’t feel you deserve? Or you’ve reconfigured a story to make it more palatable for your conscious to accept. ‘I was sacked because they don’t like the way I speak to the senior managers.’ Or they didn’t promote me because I’m different’. These could be translated to, ‘I’m often rude and arrogant and have an issue with authority’ or ‘I work in a corporate environment with a strict dress code but I’m embracing my individuality and if I want to show my tattoos and dye my hair blue, then that’s my choice’. Perception is key. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes however we find ourselves in unfair situations where we’re surrounded by dream killers and people that want to sabotage our advancement, I call them enemies of progress. An employer who is threatened by your potential, a partner who doesn’t feel adequate and strives to pull you down rather than improve their self esteem to create the balance they long for. It happens, shitty things happen sometimes and we end up in situations that we don’t deserve and find ourselves struggling to understand why. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes….just sometimes It’s us!!!!! We’ve put ourselves in a situation that is detrimental, or we’re behaving in a way that is incompatible with progress, we’re eating too much, drinking too much, procrastinating daily, not getting enough sleep, displaying a foul attitude, flying off the handle, not setting achievable goals, in fact not setting any goals at all, unhappily coasting, going nowhere slowly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have kids they’re a stark reminder of the movement of time. One day you’re embracing a newborn and the next you’re running after a sprightly toddler in what feels like the blink of an eye. Time waits for no one. And in seeing the movement of time you begin to realise how much of it we waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll respond to this dilemma within the context of dating, as I had several experiences that I feel helped me to face my demons. But this issue extends way beyond the dating scene and filters into so many aspects of life. This issue of being in complete denial, burying your head in the sand, hoping that something will change spontaneously, ignoring the red flags in your life, having what I call ostrich syndrome or simply being completely oblivious, sometimes referred to as unintentional blindness. I’ve had it, maybe you have too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a silly romcom once in my mid twenties that I wish I had seen earlier. Without being melodramatic the premise of the film changed my perception on so many things in my life and helped me to face reality. Not my version of reality, or what I hoped for, but what was actually happening. The film was titled ‘He’s Just Not That Into You’. Have you seen it? Major revelation so late on in life! Following heartbreak, self-loathing, questioning myself, hating the players and the game, asking myself why nothing seemed to be working and why I kept meeting the same ‘types’. Why hadn’t he called, why were our dates so sporadic and irregular? Why didn’t he want to hold my hand? Why don’t I know where he lives? The film helped me to confront bad boy questions like these, and subsequently helped me to apply the same brutal threshold to other areas in my life. If he’s not calling you, he just isn’t that into you…. if they’re not promoting you after 10 years of service, they never will. If you’ve been battling weight issues your whole life and still find yourself stocking up on doughnuts and cheeseburgers, the weight will not just disappear! It’s scary but liberating to finally see the light, acceptance is progress. Reality can be harsh but the real pain comes when you spend years in denial. What’s more painful…plucking out one hair at a time or doing a wax??! Arguably both hurt, both are trying to achieve the same goal, one prolongs the pain as it takes longer, which would you choose? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self assessment is what is saving me. The ability to self reflect and also ask for feedback from those I love and trust. I have more good days than bad days. I sometimes slip into a procrastinating exhausted hole but the hole is shallow and I can still see the light. I try and ask myself difficult questions everyday, some situations take me longer to face head on, but I keep trying, I keep showing up. As part of my Miracle Morning I say the following positive affirmations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am my own super hero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I respect my body and treat it with respect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I accept and love my body as it is and work to make it better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoy the process of reaching a healthy weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am getting stronger and healthier every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I clear away emotional and physical clutter to make room for success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I utilize my time to maximize my success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a woman who effortlessly gets things done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is safe for me to be a woman of success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am beautiful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am enough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am in charge of how I feel and today I choose happiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing your reality is not easy but it’s possible. First you have to face your reality and decide what you want your reality to be. Join me in making changes and creating your own happy place.  Face your reality or change it.  I’d love to hear your thoughts and experiences. Please comment, like and share if appropriate..&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>You Can Do It</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/you-can-do-it/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/you-can-do-it/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Positivity</category>
            
                <category>Confidence</category>
            
                <category>Happy place</category>
            
                <category>Dreams</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/you-can-do-it/images/slide_hue6992f1a4226151557dbb560cd55261e_295739_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>When people tell me they don’t make plans or set goals I have to do a double take.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;When people tell me they don’t make plans or set goals I have to do a double take. I’m truly bewildered by the concept of living without direction or measuring your own progress. Goals give you something to dream of, aspire to, work towards. They help you focus your energy and productivity on the areas you choose. They may be scary to some, but they give me purpose and drive. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/you-can-do-it/images/scared_hue127a2e285bc4d7b8c19b6ef6c6011c7_173643_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/you-can-do-it/images/scared_hue127a2e285bc4d7b8c19b6ef6c6011c7_173643_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/you-can-do-it/images/scared_hue127a2e285bc4d7b8c19b6ef6c6011c7_173643_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/you-can-do-it/images/scared_hue127a2e285bc4d7b8c19b6ef6c6011c7_173643_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/you-can-do-it/images/scared_hue127a2e285bc4d7b8c19b6ef6c6011c7_173643_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/you-can-do-it/images/scared_hue127a2e285bc4d7b8c19b6ef6c6011c7_173643_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes us so averse to setting goals and preferring to just go with the flow? Nothing wrong with a relaxed approach to life, but having no goals is essentially getting into a car with half a tank of petrol and no destination; you may enjoy the serendipitous journey but you’ll most likely be unprepared and eventually run out of petrol and potentially end up on the hard shoulder of a motorway going to Skegness, up the creek without a paddle as they say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/you-can-do-it/images/path_hu6288e988dfba3e9486888ed153342d9e_988450_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/you-can-do-it/images/path_hu6288e988dfba3e9486888ed153342d9e_988450_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/you-can-do-it/images/path_hu6288e988dfba3e9486888ed153342d9e_988450_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/you-can-do-it/images/path_hu6288e988dfba3e9486888ed153342d9e_988450_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/you-can-do-it/images/path_hu6288e988dfba3e9486888ed153342d9e_988450_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/you-can-do-it/images/path_hu6288e988dfba3e9486888ed153342d9e_988450_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent situations have reminded me of my mortality and given me the passion to enjoy every day like it was my last. I’m here to encourage you to step out and do something differently today. Challenge yourself to try something you’ve always wanted to, eat a new dish, go to a new park, swim in a new lake, dance to a new tune, travel to a new country. Don’t be bounded by people’s perception of you, what they think you can achieve, what they expect you to do, or even what you’ve conditioned your mind to accept you’re capable of. You are so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For everyone told that they can’t&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every exam they said you’d fail that you passed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every dress they said you shouldn’t wear but did&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every job they said you’d never get but did&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every journey they told you not to take but completed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every man they told you not to be with but happily married&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every apology you deserved but never got&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every battle you fought when no one else would and won&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for all those doubters…may they continue to motivate you to be your best. May you always have your glass half full, living your best life. May you continue to dream freely, and be intentional. Wishing you a limitless life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your dreams, your experiences and your stories no matter how big or small. Please like, share and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Mamas on the edge</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mamas-on-the-edge/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/mamas-on-the-edge/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Mental health</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Happy place</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/mumAndSon_hu358252306266c9178e090aa045e416f3_530939_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Last week was mental health awareness week.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Last week was mental health awareness week. Sadly as a society we seem to have difficulty accepting the diversity of mental illness, and our sensitivities and ignorance have alienated some of the most vulnerable and misunderstood. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a compelling documentary by Louis Theroux called Mothers on the Edge on BBC Two. Depicting an insight into the stories of mothers who found themselves facing mental illness. A fascinating programme which really highlighted the nature of mental illness and it’s indiscriminate, potentially destructive reach. If you haven’t already, it’s worth a gander. It told stories of women who were staying at a residential mental health facility with their babies being treated for various illnesses. Some with a history of mental health concerns and some whose first experience of their illness emerged when their babies were born. It told of women, just like me, living and hoping, working towards a future and through no fault of their own struck with sometimes unexplainable mental illnesses. It humbled me to think that this so easily could have been me. Mental illness doesn’t discriminate, it transcends class, wealth, social position, employment history, and notions of ‘strength’. When people speak of women on the edge I slightly recoil as I feel we’re all living on the edge of something… and sometimes the smallest and seemingly insignificant catalyst can push any of us over the edge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motherhood as I’ve documented in my blogs has been an experience I will treasure forever. It’s been beautiful and rewarding, and yet the hardest journey I’ve ever encountered and whilst I’ve never experienced mental illness I could identify with some of the emotions the women claimed to be feeling. Helplessness, anxiety, exhaustion to name a few. I saw myself in some of them and wondered what pushed them to the edge? Most of these feelings I guess are just part and parcel of motherhood… but when these emotions begin to overwhelm you and you literally feel like you’re drowning, it’s time to ask for help. At what point should you ask for help…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now…the time is now, it’s never too early to speak and be heard, to share your thoughts, your fears, the confusion that envelopes you, the debilitating anxiety that grips you. You’re not alone. I’ll be honest and say that the documentary made me tear up. When I thought about these women facing their demons, struggling in their daily lives, suffocated by their thoughts, I felt sad. Sad not only because of the compassion I felt and the poignance of the relationship between a mother and child, and the daily challenges, but because that could so easily have been me, or one of my loved ones… and I’m not sure I’d recognise the signs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in social media perfection, striving to show our best, put our best foot forward and ensure we keep it together at all costs, and when we can’t, insta doesn’t send help… facebook doesn’t give you a warm embrace and twitter certainly doesn’t wipe away your tears. And yet we continue to expect mothers to have it all ticking along, because Grandma had 8 kids and could balance 3 of them on her hip whilst ploughing the field. Grandma was awesome. Props to her! I on the other hand hate gardening and can barely balance one kid on my hip. I have it as all together as I can, regularly questioning my ability to keep all my balls in the air, and even more regularly deciding to put the balls down and just have a nap. I try, like we all do and have moments of vulnerability, despondence and darkness, sometimes no amount of self motivation will do, and we just need some help. So as we come to the end of Mental Health Awareness week, I implore you to consider the mothers who may need a little extra kindness, patience, compassion and a non judgmental ear. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself on the edge I hope you remember there are so many of us right next to you. Don’t look down and lose your balance, step away from the rim and keep your feet firmly on the ground. I hope you find a source of help and support, and get back to your happy place. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please comment, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow&lt;/a&gt;, like and share!, like and share. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Lost in Translation</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Travel</category>
            
                <category>Family life</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Risks</category>
            
                <category>Adventure</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Living in a country where English is the secondary or even third language has its ups and downs.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Living in a country where English is the secondary or even third language has its ups and downs. We are physically immersed in a language we have little comprehension of. Thankfully, our intuition is often strong, we’re able to muddle our way through most situations., and thankfully we seem to have the seventh sense, “get your arse out of here”, or “go ask someone you pillock before you end up requesting for bail”. Today has been one of those days that highlights just how lost in translation we are here in Switzerland! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way to the Accident and Emergency on the only day that suits our setup! No support means illnesses need to be scheduled on appropriate days where both parents are available, so the sick parent can be relieved of duties temporarily to seek repair, heaven forbid we’re both sick at the same time, if man flu is a contender, I lose….cue eye roll…so today is apparently a national holiday here in Switzerland. Perfect for me to get myself seen by a doctor. Enroute we’re waiting at a tram stop and no trams are showing up, but the electronic display is indicating there’ll be one along in 8 minutes….10 minutes later nothing….this is so unswiss, you could almost set your clock using the transport schedule as they’re usually so punctual!! ….but there’s no sign anywhere, I’ve made that mistake before, sitting at an out of service bus stop behind a large bright orange sign in German saying out of service….so I’m not making that mistake again!! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope this time it’s different, something’s going on….but no clue what!! Intuition and a large dose of impatience means we’re never caught out for long in a situation like this, but it’s oh so frustrating when apparently there’s a demonstration which has closed off the city centre, so we need to abort our plan and find another doctor! I bet that’s what all those annoying announcements were blaring out on the way! Typical….no bloody idea! I know a little high German, and that gets me by mostly. And I’ve considered getting private lessons but Swiss German is spoken out here and you can only really learn that on the streets…and it’s nothing like high German&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often ask me why we moved, are we home sick, what is it like living in a different country, do we consider it home yet? My answers to these questions often vary depending on who’s asking, why, and what time of the day I’m approached, but for the most part we are adventurers. We love exploring, travelling, learning and expanding our horizons and know that the world has so much to offer if we just open our eyes, and step out of our comfort zone. Adventures are stories that we can’t predict, they’re exciting, scary, risky, fun and open doors that we never thought we had access to and in that vein create the art of the possible. Possibilities create hope, they fuel passion and ignite a zeal that no one can quench. We live by the mantra that you only live once, and you should grasp opportunities with both hands and run. Opportunities don’t always approach you, waving and beckoning, opportunities also need to be created. Create opportunities and make things happen, say yes more, and do things that excite you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adventures don’t last forever, things change, life happens, and we ride the waves and keep it moving. We all need to pause sometimes, take stock, change direction, re-evaluate where we are and where we’re trying to get to. We win some, we lose, and that’s ok. it’s ok to pause,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set ourselves apart from the crowd by choosing courage over comfort, love over solitude. Our risks don’t always pay off, but that doesn’t matter, we keep trying, keep hustling, keep showing up. We love the thrill of the journey, the memories we create, the lessons learnt, the history created. We wouldn’t trade it for a stable paycheck or loyalty points. Stability suits most but our priority is to live, and sometimes these two components are incompatible. Our foundation is strong so a few branches pruned and splintered along the way is fine. Keep your core strong, lean into possibilities, and block out all the noise. It’s in blocking out the noise of the concrete jungle that you’ll truly begin to understand that we are all one, sometimes no need to even translate, just be. Be you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What adventures do you dream of? Made any plans? I’d love to hear from you. Please comment, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;, like and share!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Sh*t Happens</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/sht-happens/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/sht-happens/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Toilet training</category>
            
                <category>Toddlers</category>
            
                <category>Timing</category>
            
                <category>Milestones</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/sht-happens/images/featured_hu1e72b72676a051160fdff6055cb6e7ad_3284024_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Apologies for the radio silence! We have been doing life for the last three weeks, and boy has it been intense!</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the radio silence! We have been doing life for the last three weeks, and boy has it been intense!! Spring has well and truly sprung and we’ve started a new season of our own. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/sht-happens/images/featured_hu1e72b72676a051160fdff6055cb6e7ad_3284024_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/sht-happens/images/featured_hu1e72b72676a051160fdff6055cb6e7ad_3284024_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/sht-happens/images/featured_hu1e72b72676a051160fdff6055cb6e7ad_3284024_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/sht-happens/images/featured_hu1e72b72676a051160fdff6055cb6e7ad_3284024_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/sht-happens/images/featured_hu1e72b72676a051160fdff6055cb6e7ad_3284024_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/sht-happens/images/featured_hu1e72b72676a051160fdff6055cb6e7ad_3284024_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days after arriving back from our break in Austria we all came down with a nasty stomach bug! It’s pretty difficult to maintain tranquility when you’re regularly discarding the contents of your gut! And as parenting goes it’s all for one and one for all! When ones sick it’s usually just a matter of time before the whole clan have got it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as we had the all clear I decided that if I didn’t take the lead on toilet training and just get on with it, my son will be the first teenage boy still asking for a nappy change! It’s been one delay after the other, well meaning advice to put it off as apparently too many changes cause disruption and confusion….and renditions of constipated toddlers in therapy sent me into a cold sweat…. sigh… so because our lives are full of change…. there’s never been a ‘good’ time!! I just needed to get on and do it!! And after months of agonising over the whole process….figuring out if he was ready…asking friends for advice, reading a few articles and even getting one of those scary exploitative parenting books that should be burnt not published….I just got on with it….and dived head first, thankfully not literally into the sh*t that awaited me…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m totally like a girl scout…I like to be prepared, and know what I’m getting into. For some reason toilet training just scared the sh*t out of me, excuse the pun, but the thought of a toddler throwing tantrums and relieving himself on my cashmere blanket in protest just brought me out in a rash. And while toilet training can be tough, depending on your child it’s not as bad as you might invision! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly I’d like to address this concept of waiting until they’re ready!…Ready??! Ready to do what exactly? Get a mortgage, get an inappropriate piercing, what exactly do they need to be ready for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/sht-happens/images/josh-transport_hu743b71a648831ae99a81341aeaa573d3_307338_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/sht-happens/images/josh-transport_hu743b71a648831ae99a81341aeaa573d3_307338_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/sht-happens/images/josh-transport_hu743b71a648831ae99a81341aeaa573d3_307338_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/sht-happens/images/josh-transport_hu743b71a648831ae99a81341aeaa573d3_307338_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/sht-happens/images/josh-transport_hu743b71a648831ae99a81341aeaa573d3_307338_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/sht-happens/images/josh-transport_hu743b71a648831ae99a81341aeaa573d3_307338_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now some kids notice their parents and family members using the toilet, they’re curious, some find nappies uncomfortable or are simply fed up with the feeling of being wet, I get it, these are possible signs….but and I may be a little controversial here… when you reach a certain age and the child’s level of comprehension is at a point of clearly deciphering and identifying poos and wees, it’s more about if the parents are ready rather than the child!! That week we returned from holiday…I was ready. I was not going back. No matter what!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toilet training can be exhausting, time consuming and frustrating. No one likes change, and ditching nappies is life altering, and if your kid is as strong willed as mine, the transition isn’t necessarily going to be seamless. If I could have paid someone to do it for me, I would have….no Fear Of Missing Out here….but alas I haven’t quite got it like that, and as I’ve told you before, my husband is from a region in Nigeria that prides itself on being prudent, so I’ve spent the last two weeks, tiptoeing around our apartment dodging glistening puddles in obscure places. Last week he decided to secretly relieve himself on my duvet… yep that was a pleasant surprise. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had full on cataclysmic tantrums, he fully articulated on a daily basis that he did not want to use the toilet and that was that. I was slowly losing hope and my sanity, picturing myself being found by my husband when he got home from work rocking in a corner clutching disinfectant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we all have that straight talking friend that doesn’t mince their words and just tells it as it is. Everyone needs at least one! Mine gratefully gave me a brief list of essentials. Portable potty, spare clothes and some kind of reward to positively reinforce the wins! She said it could take a while, some kids a few days, some a few months….manage your expectations. Night times are hormonal and one day something will just switch and his nappy will be dry in the mornings. Well it’s true….it’s taken us the best part of 2 weeks and we are now, dry, day and night!!! We had “poos go to pooland” on loop, yes there is an app for this… and my son thinks it’s brilliant. Essentially you send poos to pooland…toddlers love it, go figure… So I can smugly say that I have run out of dettol, my home doesn’t smell like a zoo and I have a toilet trained toddler in my midst!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what have I learnt from poo gate… know your child, adapt your strategy to suit your child’s personality and temperament. You won’t get a magic epiphany of flashing lights and deep voices announcing your child is ready… you’ll just know when the time is right for both you and your child, and whatever you do don’t look back! We stopped and started at least twice because we thought he wasn’t quite ready, probably doing more harm than good and creating unnecessary confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start the process with healthy optimism with a large dose of realism. It’s not easy, but it’s also not as tough as you imagine! You will be putting multiple loads of laundry on daily…deal with it, you will be cleaning up poo and wee multiple times a day…but there is light at the end of the toilet! They get it or give in eventually! Just go for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toilet training like so many milestones in life, can appear daunting and insurmountable. But once you take the step and start you’ll be surprised at the outcome. Hindsight is 20:20 do something you’ve been procrastinating over, you’ll be glad you just got on with it! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your comments and stories! Thanks for reading! Please like, share and follow me.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Friends without benefits</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/friends-without-benefits/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/friends-without-benefits/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>friendship</category>
            
                <category>relationships</category>
            
                <category>self-esteem</category>
            
                <category>loneliness</category>
            
                <category>give</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/friends-without-benefits/images/penguin_hudae307c9a0849413286c08697d41aec2_912408_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>My mum always used to say if you show me your friends I’ll show you who you are.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;My mum always used to say if you show me your friends I’ll show you who you are. I never really used to take any notice, it sounded like an old irrelevant proverb designed to spoil my fun and coerce me into getting rid of my ‘colourful’ friends. The ones who never had a curfew, never got grounded, wore the shortest skirts to school and allowed to eat crisps for breakfast. I guess by natural elimination some people just don’t stick in your life. Friends can be for a season or a reason, or simply promoted to family, and they just become part of the furniture. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good friend apparently is like a good bra, supportive, makes you look and feel good and is close to your heart. A bad friend is not necessarily ‘bad’ but perhaps just not right for you. A person whose interests always seem to come first, who’s unavailable, unattainable, insincere, dishonest, selfish, competitive or even disloyal. A bad friend like any bad relationship is a manifestation of low self esteem. If you value yourself, your progress, your emotional well-being and development you’ll identify friends without benefits and excuse yourself from the equation. It’s easier said than done, I know, unfortunately it’s not as easy as finding a bad egg…bad friends don’t always float to the surface. Sometimes we hold on to precious memories, grasping on to history and nostalgia and discounting behaviours we know to be detrimental because often it’s easier to ignore than call it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up as an only child I never feared loneliness. I was used to flying solo and my own company was all I had most days. Although there were times when I longed for some companionship, growing up learning how to enjoy my own company meant that I didn’t force relationships, I have always been content, and by default I welcome people into my life who bring love, support, joy, humour, resilience and attributes I lack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/friends-without-benefits/images/holding_hands_hue8f27423ba7926c500c37e8cb35f54b1_229375_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/friends-without-benefits/images/holding_hands_hue8f27423ba7926c500c37e8cb35f54b1_229375_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/friends-without-benefits/images/holding_hands_hue8f27423ba7926c500c37e8cb35f54b1_229375_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/friends-without-benefits/images/holding_hands_hue8f27423ba7926c500c37e8cb35f54b1_229375_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/friends-without-benefits/images/holding_hands_hue8f27423ba7926c500c37e8cb35f54b1_229375_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/friends-without-benefits/images/holding_hands_hue8f27423ba7926c500c37e8cb35f54b1_229375_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been the friend, the confidant, the trustee, the devotee, the supportive one, the ride or die, the hold her hair back she can’t control the vomit, the skirt in knicker situation cunning rapid remover, the spinach in teeth quiet highlighter, the bouncer, the cock blocker, the goggles with no beer, the leave work early we have a serious problem, the he’s dumped me lets go and paint the town red, the cheer leader, the party friend, the oprah friend, the friend in good times and bad. Friends have been like weight for me, I’ve shed a few pounds and gained a few over the years. But thankfully I’ve maintained a healthy balance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you become a parent your friend circle changes drastically. Your focus changes and friends without children often feel a divide and less commonality. It’s a natural change, motherhood requires some mummy backup, even with the best will in the world, a friend with no kids may not fully understand your new position, is unlikely to be able to answer questions about teething, colic, or breast feeding and won’t be awake for the night time feeds…unless she happens to be at Garage Nation…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real friends stick with you, through all of life’s changes, they roll with the changes in dynamics, schedules, priorities and just fit in like nothing really changed, when so much has. They accept that you are fundamentally still you, and now just happen to have children. My friend circle has evolved over the years and I’ve been blessed with truly beautiful people who’ve been like a sports bra in this marathon called parenting, hoisting me up, strapping me in and preventing whiplash. I’m open to building meaningful friendships with people who are givers. Takers need not apply. If we were all givers we would be surrounded by friends who burst at the seams, over loaded with love. We do ourselves a disservice by entering relationships seeking out what we can gain. Rather we should consider what we can offer. What can we give? How can we improve someone else’s world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are friends that stick closer than a sister. A friend that has your back no matter what, who loves you without condition, celebrates with you in achievements, mourns with you in hard times and who loves you enough to correct you when you’re wrong, and fights to keep your friendship blooming. As a woman I am acutely aware of my need for a tribe, to belong to a solid group that I can rely on, who empower each other and encourage one another to make their dreams a reality. Spending hours without adult company with wheels on the bus on repeat, it’s easy to get lost in the thick of it, so it’s essential to have friends who keep you grounded and present. You deserve to be surrounded by love, and if you doubt that love is the intention then perhaps you should reconsider the companion. Sometimes your circle decreases in size but increases in value, and that’s ok, it truly is quality not quantity. Cherish the friends you have, don’t be afraid to make new ones and be a giver not a taker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! I’d love to hear your thoughts and feedback. Please like, share and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Flying with babies</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/flying_with_babies/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/flying_with_babies/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Travel</category>
            
                <category>Travel tips</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/flying_with_babies/images/flight_hu2d54c1b84a3a7556dc20ca8ce0fc2933_5590305_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I’m planning my next trip to the UK…this time flying solo with my two munchkins.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I’m planning my next trip to the UK…this time flying solo with my two munchkins. If I said I’m shitting it, that would be the understatement of the year! I am absolutely dreading it, but I’ve got no choice! My husband has started a new job and I’ve got commitments to attend. I’ve not had the best flight experiences when travelling alone with my first child, so who knows what’s going to happen when I rock up to check in with another one in tow! If you see me on CNN… you know the deal…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the apprehension over the flight, and the levels of incompetence I’m about to face, I’m thinking positive vibes only, hoping that I encounter kindness and compassion. I’m excited to be going home for a few days, seeing some friends and family and eating my way through deliveroo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can pack for a flight with my eyes closed I’ve done it often enough. Here are a few of my must haves, that you can consider if you’re planning a flight with children:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You’re likely to be feeling like you’re carrying everything but the kitchen sink! Ask yourself if what you’re packing is a must have or a nice to have. Nice to haves stay at home, you’ll be grateful for having less baggage! Your carry on will be in the overhead locker during the flight. Try to pack essentials in a smaller additional bag that fits in your carry on, that you can easily grab and stow under your seat. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Give your kids their own backpack with their own items. It gives them a sense of ownership, and helps you out a little. Don’t get sucked into these cute, awkwardly shaped suitcases designed to get kids ‘excited’ about travel, but essentially end up being carried by the parent. They’re annoying, cumbersome and don’t hold much. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Change all nappies before you board. If you’re lucky and it’s a short haul flight you may never have to experience trying to change a nappy in those ridiculously sized toilets on board, barely large enough for one human, let alone a parent trying to change a nappy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bring a change of clothes for you and the baby(ies) I’ve forgotten to take a change for myself once and ended up covered in a virgin mary and baby puke. The smell was not becoming I can tell ya!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Snacks…you can never have enough snacks. Preferably ones that can be resealable and aren’t too messy, if you’re Marie Kondo in the making decant your snacks into containers for toddlers. I like to live on the edge, decanting isn’t for me… &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distractions - Stickers and a colouring in book for children aged 1 year and upwards. Variety is the spice of life. Depending on the duration of your flight, bring a few options, and don’t bring them all out at once! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yawning and swallowing activate the muscles that open your eustachian tubes and helps equalize the pressure between your ears and the airplane cabin, to avoid that blocked sensation. Depending on the age of the child - take one of those fruit pouches the child can suck on during take off and landing. Breast fed babies, stick a boob in their mouth during take off and landing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Muslins and wipes. Can any parent live without these with an under 2 year old??! Take a few and at least two packs of wipes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blanket in case it gets abit chilly on the plane. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re keen on screens make sure you’ve downloaded your kids flavour of the month to your device, and don’t forget to charge up the device and pack the charger!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A baby carrier is really useful whilst travelling through the airport, especially at security. Trying to open a pram whilst holding a baby can be challenging, a baby carrier solves this problem. It’s also really useful if you are travelling with more than one child. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take a foldable pram you can either take on the aircraft and stow in the over head lockers, or a one piece foldable pram that can be taken to the door of the aircraft. And make sure you empty your pram basket before you leave home. It’s easy to forget all those miscellaneous items we throw in the bottom of the pram on a daily basis. Finding an argos catalogue. a bucket and spade and wellies at security is not fun!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Separate your liquids in hand luggage. No doubt if you’re travelling with tots you’ll have some form of liquid. To make life a tad easier when going through security have them all in one section of your bag so you can easily pull out for examination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with everything check with your airline carrier to ensure you’re travelling with items that are acceptable in their policy. And never be afraid to ask for help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basque in the joy that you can’t lose your toddler on the flight! Comforted by the inevitable truth that no matter how tough the journey sooner or later the plane will land! Ignore tutting passengers, and try and enjoy your flight. We can do this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your tips for flights, especially with more than one child.  I need it!! Thanks for reading! Please like, share and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Freedom Day</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>MyFreedomDay</category>
            
                <category>discrimination</category>
            
                <category>pregnancy</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>freedom</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/freedom_hu72824833961529480145661fda384d45_219928_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>If it doesn’t have Lycra in it and requires ironing, it’s dead to me.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;If it doesn’t have Lycra in it and requires ironing, it’s dead to me. I’m somewhere in between a size 12 and in denial. No idea what my style is right now. Comfortable? Functional? Clean? Or maybe just not publicly naked?! I can’t legitimately wear maternity clothing anymore….although that stretchy waistband gives me life most days! So for now I’m going with it! Baggy is totally in. Bed hair chic is back and I’m rocking it like it’s 99. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiger marks are appearing in some obscure places but I’m loving the life tattoos. These battle scars are epic and the war has been won!! Well yes I’ve won, I have two beautiful children and I fought through the sickness, the exhaustion, the aches, the doubts, the tests, the sleepless nights, the bladder with a mind of its own, the garlic aversions, the breathlessness, the mumgry moments on the London underground during rush hour, and of course… the labour. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labour… the event that’s pencilled into your diary as a definite, with no definites, no calendar invite needed, this is your party baby!  There’s no opting out of this one, no deferring, it’s the inevitable…that baby is coming to join the world by any means necessary. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t give labour much thought initially. I attended a prenatal class, watched documentaries, my husband banned me from watching as I cried over every episode and read a couple of articles. But nothing really prepared me for the day it all happened. For medical reasons I was told that I may have to have a caesarean section. No one could really explain why, just that it was ‘best’. I spent months of the pregnancy with a small hope that I may be able to give birth naturally, but content with having a C section if that was best for both me and the baby. I have nothing against c sections, it’s just that I’ve spent the majority of my life in and out of hospital, and been on the operating table more times than I care to remember. I take surgery very seriously, and if there’s a path that safely avoids that route, I’ll take that thank you very much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day I went into the emergency maternity unit as I couldn’t feel the baby moving as I had before. I was checked over and thankfully all was fine. Before I left, the doctor asked me if I had made a decision on whether or not to have a c section. I reiterated that I still didn’t quite understand why I couldn’t give birth naturally and if this was still an option I’d like to take it. The doctor told me that if I gave birth naturally I would end up having an emergency c section and that in those instances the doctors primary objective is to get the baby out quickly. According to her if in this emergency organs are damaged or arteries cut, that’s just collateral damage I’ll have to accept! Through tears of fear in that cold examination room, I signed the consent forms she shoved in front of me and agreed to have the c section. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C section day arrived… I had my bag packed and my husband and I went to the hospital to meet our baby. The consultants did their early morning rounds before the day began. The consultant introduced himself and asked me how I was and what I was there for. I laughed and said ‘I’m here to meet my baby, and you’ve booked me in for a c-section I don’t even want’. It was a teaching hospital, and surrounded by a group of students they all gawked at me. The consultant then sat on my bed and asked me what I wanted… I explained what had happened and how throughout my pregnancy no one had explained anything to me and I felt invisible, I even had to write my birth plan myself as the midwife said I didn’t need one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one knows how labour will go for anyone, and why was I any different? Unless there’s a clear medical reason that someone can actually explain to me I would rather not have surgery. The doctor smiled, and said ‘you don’t have to do anything you don’t want to do’. He told me to go home. I went home and a week later gave birth to my son naturally. Whether it was possible or not, someone believed I had the right to choose. He empowered me that morning and gave me my voice back. He gave me the freedom to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years later, pregnant again, I  faced similar attitudes and an air of disconnection that I couldn’t quite put my finger on. Last pregnancy I pretty much lived in the hospital, going in weekly for check ups towards the end and being treated like a glass shoe. This time I’ve been seen a handful of times for the mandatory scans and checks, nothing more nothing less. As I’ve given birth naturally once before there was no question as to my ability to do so this time, with the obvious disclaimer that anything can happen during labour! This time around no consultant checks, again no birth plan. Bewildered by the eerie sense of isolation I just got on with it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into labour in the middle of the night, awoken by feelings I’d had a dodgy burrito. Went back to sleep more irritated than in pain…clearly I don’t know what contractions feel like, as this apparently was the start of labour for me. I eventually gave into the discomfort and got dressed to go and get checked out at the hospital, during which the pain increased and I realised I was in labour. We got an uber to the hospital and I was literally struggling not to have the baby in the back seat of the car! We arrived at the hospital, it was quiet… just a dozing security guard who although manning the entrance to a maternity unit seemed mythed that a woman had arrived in the middle of the night in labour…cue eye roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband found a wheelchair and a nurse and I was taken in. I felt a certain sense of relief, that I was in safe hands and that they knew what they were doing, and that it would all be ok. As the pain increased and I begged for someone to help me and give me some pain relief I realised that this may not be the case. I was examined and they quickly assessed I was already 8cm dilated. I kept shouting that the baby was coming, at least give me some gas and air…they insisted on moving me to another room on a different floor! I got to the designated room and told to relax it would ok. I begged for gas and air and none came. I remember in that moment being silent and realising I was on my own. It felt like an out of body experience. I started concentrating on my breathing, focussing on slowing down and blocking out the noise of the panicked midwives. They were fumbling around trying to find the baby’s heartbeat. Amidst the confusion they finally gave me gas and air, my daughters head popped out, they all looked visibly shocked and the rest is history. No one was listening to me, I felt invisible and vulnerable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 14 is #MyFreedomDay. Every woman deserves to be heard. To have the freedom to make informed choices about their bodies, to be listened to and understood. To be given the power of autonomy over their fabric, their mind, their uterus. Freedom to decide what’s best for me and my baby. When you take away a woman’s freedom, you strip her of her dignity, you extinguish her power, you make her invisible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women often like to share labour stories. When you’ve had a child it’s almost a right of passage, a conversation that creates bonds. So many people have asked me to share my story, so many have stories that hurt to relive. Labour can be traumatic for some, life changing for all. I don’t know why my cries were ignored, or my wishes mocked, but I hear all too often of the plight of black women in labour and it makes my heart cry. If it had not been for the consultant who sat down and listened to me, my story would have been very different. We may be strong, but we deserve to be heard, everyone deserves this freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>It&#39;s ok not to be ok…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Mental Health</category>
            
                <category>Isolation</category>
            
                <category>Life</category>
            
                <category>Journey</category>
            
                <category>Healing</category>
            
                <category>Communication</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_alone_bath_hu2579916eee37f6a01e86a0a116d41ca4_1661153_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Hey how are you?
I’m good, how are you?</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hey how are you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m good, how are you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so easy to give these knee jerk responses to a casual question we hear daily. And I’m by no means suggesting an episode of verbal diarrhoea with boundless content every time someone asks how you are at the supermarket checkout! That would be weird! But when you’re in a safe place…and if you don’t have a safe place, get one! A safe place, where you can be yourself, a person whom you trust. A real answer is just what the doctor ordered. Honesty breeds healing and progress and gives light to those dark areas in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hey how are you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m exhausted, hungry, fed up, disappointed, lonely, depressed and anxious. I got a parking ticket yesterday, I’ve got this lingering toothache. I haven’t had a shower in two days. The laundry hasn’t been done, I’ve run out of detergent and milk but forgot to get some in the last shopping trip, so no tea for me today, I can’t be dealing with black tea. My job is thankless and monotonous, and my boss hates me. The kids have given me a cold, so now my nose is streaming and as if I’m not already sleep deprived enough I’m coughing like a chain smoker on helium at night, wheezing and breathless. I’m overdrawn on my overdraft, dealing with family conflict, and I think my wife is having an affair. with her personal trainer. We’ve been secretly doing IVF and the pressure of the failed cycles is mounting, I’m not sure our relationship can endure this battering. We have one last attempt left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m having a bad hair week, this afro is about to get another big chop if it ain’t careful, and I’ve gained about 50 pounds in the last month. I need to book a GP appt for myself, I’ve had this persistent problem and I need a solution not a placebo… but I’m hoping it will just go away if I leave it long enough…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning and it took me longer than normal to convince myself to face the world. Everyday it seems to be getting more difficult. I’ve called in sick a few times at work, but I can’t pull a sicky on life. But my response as always if you care to ask is… I’m fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if you can relate to any of this, but whatever your challenges and hurdles, whatever is keeping you up at night. It’s ok not to be ok. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see you holding everyone up, holding it all together. Trying to be solid like an ox. Putting on a brave face. Being the foundation that everyone needs, being the rock that you need. Putting everyone before yourself. I see you. I feel you. Carrying the weight around your neck. I see you in the small hours nursing, dreaming of sleep, writing your to do list in the dark, by the light of your phone, responding to messages you’d forgotten you even had from last week. I see you awkwardly compressed between a rock and a hard place on your daily 2 hour commute. I see you, working in a job that daily robs you of your joy, quietly stuck in commuter pain, sandwiched between optimism and hopelessness surrounded by people who need to become familiar with deodorant. Overheating, overworked, underpaid and underappreciated. Wondering when the cycle will end. Hoping for deliverance, escape, or the luck of the Irish when that euro millions advert comes on. I see you doing the daily school run, sprinting from the car to the school gates, reciting the list of chores in your head as you head back to the car, praying for a day off. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You pick yourself up when things get tough. People sometimes ask you how you are but rarely listen for the truth. You make excuses for your nearest and dearest, no one seems to care enough, and you’re alone, firefighting and trying to keep your head above water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we were honest about how we are feeling if not for public scrutiny, at least for ourselves then maybe we’d find the strength to face them and stop saying we’re ok, for fear of burdening others, being shunned by others, being misunderstood, or simply ignored. Or maybe sometimes it’s easier to just pretend it’s not happening and maybe it will all just go away…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rarely… things rarely just disappear. Sometimes verbalising your truth brings it into reality, shit gets real when you start talking about it. Talking is good. Talking is freedom and relief. Talk to the right people, find solutions and support. But whatever you’re going through, however tough or impossible it may seem, there will be an end. I hope you surround yourself with light and love. That you find beauty in ashes. Believe it or not, your worst day to someone else is a dream come true. This week has been exhausting for me on so many levels. I’ve had to push through so much pain to get stuff done. I felt drawn to write this post for you to know you’re not alone. Don’t give up, and speak up. It’s ok not to be ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find someone to talk to, who’ll listen, someone you trust who cares, call the Samaritans or just message me, privately…you’re not alone, be heard.  Thanks for reading! Please like, share and follow me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-instagram&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Mumgry</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Love</category>
            
                <category>Relationships</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Marriage</category>
            
                <category>Anger</category>
            
                <category>Communication</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>Have you heard of the term Hangry?</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of the term &lt;strong&gt;Hangry&lt;/strong&gt;? It’s a clever portmanteau of hungry and angry, and an adjective that describes being irritable due to hunger, a term to describe that feeling you get when you’re hungry, and about to knock someone the hell out if you don’t get some food fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I’ve felt like that often, so I’m known for carrying around snacks and planning my life around where the nearest eatery is. I can pretty much describe anywhere I’ve been in the world in relation to good food. Sorry not sorry. I hate being hungry and am blessed to live comfortably enough to never have to experience this feeling unless I’m caught out somewhere remote or just lose track of time and there isn’t a drive through in sight. I’m a self confessed hangry person. Like I need food and am just distracted by it’s absence to the point of vexness, so I just don’t go there and prepare like a girl scout as it’s not a pretty site!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to think I’m pretty level headed and don’t have any known conditions that affect my ability to respond proportionately to situations. I’m rational, logical, don’t suffer fools much but I’m generally patient…ish. … or at least that’s what I thought! Until I got married and had babies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_395x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 395w,
          /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 790w,
          /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_1580x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 1580w,
          /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_2370x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 2370w,
          /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_3160x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of the saying, ‘hell hath no fury like a woman scorned’? I’m not so sure it’s comparable to an angry mum! Now I’m coining a new word. &lt;strong&gt;Mumgry!&lt;/strong&gt; I can’t be the only one to have felt this silent rage creeping up when your partner is snoring whilst your exhausted body struggles to stay awake and feed the baby? Or when he forgets to load the dishwasher after you cooked dinner, did the laundry, hoovered and painted the Sistine chapel, and says he’ll do it in the morning. It’s that uncontrollable urge to throw a heavy implement at someone you love because for that split second you are seething and just wish they understood the pressure you feel, the exhaustion you’re experiencing and the complete and utter overwhelm that is engulfing you. It’s a time when you feel like your brain has gone to mush, when you can’t remember if you put diesel or petrol in the car. When you breastfeed on demand in a taxi and rush out of the taxi with your boob out until you get home, and no one tells you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know the statistics but I’m pretty confident that one of the biggest factors resulting in relationship breakdown is the arrival of children. It changes the dynamics of your partnership. It really separates the men from the boys, and the women from the girls. It exposes your ride or die for the sweet talk he’s been spinning for years. He’s not ride or die, he’s let me sleep or I’ll die! The realisation that this sexy man whom you gave up your uterus for, is now the object of your dissatisfaction and in fact the focus of your vehemence is a little unnerving and can swerve out of nowhere. Even the most laid back of couples can have their mumgry moments. It’s usually a completely understandable response to something that just pushes you over the edge, but because of the new baby and the sleep deprivation people think you’re losing it or are in some hormonal abyss. Hormones may have a huge part to play in it, but it’s also just a whole lot of change and a whole lot of exhaustion, mixed in with expectations, trying to maintain a somewhat functioning household and the fact that sometimes people are just sleep walking into family life and not pulling their weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women tend to be the primary care givers, regardless of the life they had before children, and even those who made more money than their partners unfortunately can’t hand over child bearing duties, and alot of the time the gender stereotypes and society’s perception of the ‘norm’ results in women staying at home, men getting insignificant time off for paternity leave and women left holding the baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow we’ve allowed society to tell us that we’re better at nurturing and that essentially gets men off the hook. Maternal instinct doesn’t come naturally for everyone. Most of us have to work at being mums. We learn on the job and it’s tough even for Mary Poppins understudies. But we do our best, and always show up, which is half the battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do we keep mumgry under control? Just like my detailed planning required to avoid hangry moments, I too need to work on the cues for mumgry ones. And share the trigger points with my partner so he knows what the deal is. So whether it’s chores, finances, sex, socialising, or you’ve simply got beef over hogging the remote control, it’s all fixable, if you both want it to be fixed. Children are an amazing gift that come with unfettered joy and challenges, remind yourself of the love it took to have them and put maintaining that love high on your to do list, above the laundry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing your focus is definitely key. Being comfortable is great, but don’t be complacent. Don’t take your partner for granted, don’t assume anything. Make time for each other. Everyone wants to be heard, understood and loved. Communicate! Write a list of weekly chores and divvy them up. Put it somewhere you can both see. If you both write it the onus on whose responsibility it is to ensure they’re completed changes. It’s our responsibility. If we fail, we fail together, and we can ease the mental load on women just a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this post, breastfeeding, coughing and full of cold and trying to eat my breakfast. I say that the cough I have is causing me some pain in my stomach. My husbands response is, ‘great babes, those are the muscles where you’re supposed to have abs, you’re building your pack back!’ I can just feel another mumgry moment coming on, so I’m about to play some classical tunes and finish this up! Wishing you light and love and laughter and no police cautions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your mumgry moments and if you’ve got any coping mechanisms please share! Thanks for reading! Please like, share and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Happy Valentines Day</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Valentine</category>
            
                <category>Love</category>
            
                <category>Relationships</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
                <category>Self Love</category>
            
                <category>Marriage</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Yesterday I found out the hard way that the Swiss don’t do Valentines Day.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I found out the hard way that the Swiss don’t do Valentines Day.  I walked around a local shopping centre with the kids (first time in months) hoping to purchase a card, and not a fluffy teddy or heart shaped balloon in sight.  Strange? Refreshing? I’m not entirely sure how I feel about that. I don’t care enough about Valentines Day to really have an opinion.  Maybe that in itself speaks volumes…. Despite my nonchalance, I trudged through the annoyingly brightly lit shopping mall like someone who hasn’t seen daylight for some substantial time.  A journey that should’ve taken me a maximum of 15 minutes ended up being an afternoon of stopping, eating, playing with random chairs, jumping off said random chairs, eating some more, nappy changes, breastfeeding and a small but unwelcome tantrum about Brexit… actually it was about nothing obviously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually found a semi appropriate card.  Something about love on the front, in English, no text inside. Bish bash bosh!  Thanks, that’ll do!  To be honest, I wasn’t going to buy a card this year, I’ve been feeling like I’ve been dragged through a hedge backwards for some time and the exhaustion and relentless schedule is starting to take it’s toll.  Do you ever feel like you’re sleep walking?  Fire fighting, satisfying a conveyor belt of demands and it just doesn’t stop.  I’ve been shouty, impatient mum for a few days now.  Zero patience with a toddler is like putting washing up liquid in a car engine.  So my frame of mind at present has no room for love hearts and cuddly toys.  A priceless present for me would be an uninterrupted bath with my favourite scented candles…. somehow I’ll make this happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is love even when he doesn’t take the bins out, when he sleeps through your sleepless nights with the baby and is still apparently knackered.  Love is pushing through the grey matter that fogs your mind and relationship  when the mental load is taking its toll and for once you just wish you didn’t feel like you do it all in military style, forward thinking, back thinking, planning, executing, packing, cooking, cleaning, feeding. Love is sharing the load, being equally knackered, dribbling with exhaustion together in harmony. We love every day, silently over the weetabix,  patiently during laundry days, loudly in the supermarket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever your situation, love begins with you. Love you, appreciate you.  Buy yourself flowers, get a new frock, get some whipped cream and marshmallows on that hot chocolate, crack open a bottle of red, enjoy a yummy plate, binge on a box set, have a bubble bath, book a mani pedi, go for a nice walk, do whatever makes your heart sing and your mind at peace.  You are loved, you are cherished, you are worthy of love. Whatever you do today, show some love, appreciate the one you take for granted daily, and most importantly, do something you love and love yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please add a comment below, like, share and follow me on instagram, twitter and facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Get Lippy 2019</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Lipstick</category>
            
                <category>Confidence</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy-pout_huac9749c397c0ad2fd8521412fe21b4f3_250809_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I’m not great at following trends! I’d like to think I’m individual and try not to get swept away with fads and to be honest I’m about as ‘on trend’ as John McCririck or a stale Jaffa cake.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I’m not great at following trends! I’d like to think I’m individual and try not to get swept away with fads and to be honest I’m about as ‘on trend’ as John McCririck or a stale Jaffa cake. Now I’m 35 I care less what people think, I wear what I like , rarely wear make up and generally enjoying the not giving a damn phase. Spending time with my family, sharing, loving, connecting rather than succumbing to the narcism that is gripping the world. I do however love to get dressed up when I have the opportunity and in remembrance of my party days, dancing on bars, crowd surfing (I never managed to pull that off successfully) falling into taxis, falling out of ubers and generally making magical hungover memories I’d like to master something I’ve never got the hang of. Lippy!! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never had the confidence or inclination to wear it, but recently on my journey to improving my confidence and getting involved with self care, I have admired so many who wear lippy with pride! It’s amazing how it can change your entire look and elevate you from casual to ‘oh hello’ in a few pouts! But it does take some confidence to wear it and that’s what I’m working on! Whilst I’m working on my groove, in tandem I need to find decent lippy to try and would love to see you with your favourite lippy on to give me some inspiration! So join me please and  #getlippy2019. Just post a picture of yourself with the hashtags #getlippy2019 and tell me what lippy you’ve got!! I can’t wait to see them all, share with others, the more the merrier! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#getlippy2019&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/two-happy-kids_hu8bd73f293d04bbc53f400c406222be67_1908490_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Now I’ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?! I remember before my daughter was born jokingly but seriously asking people with multiple kids for tips on how to cope with two kids….no one responded. At first I thought, that’s just rude really…a girl just needs some advice, and now I realise that everyone is full on blagging their way through parenthood and no one can offer any tips because some of their survival techniques are unconventional or tailor made to suit them, or they’re simply just surviving!! Whatever your ‘methods’ I salute and chest bump you with passion.  It ain’t easy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well…. I am three months into having two children, just when I thought I had got the shower routine mastered, got my hair out of doo doo plaits and ditched the stained hareem pants, I go and have another child! This new addition was never going to propel me into more self loving and uninterrupted ‘me time’. I now have even less time, am even more exhausted… if that’s even possible and actually considered sitting in my double pram whilst the toddler was at nursery, pulling the hood down and having a kip next to the baby the other day… I was that tired. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I have no real tips as such there are a few things that I wish I had known and that have helped me ‘survive’ so far. So I’m sharing in the hope that even one parent out there receives some light and love from this post, even if it is just a warm virtual bear hug reminding you, you’re not alone! We’re all just fumbling around in the dark hoping not to cause any irreparable damage! And we are essentially doing great, we just need reminding of that occasionally! Please share things that work for you too! Every little helps!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, my top ten suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a baby carrier - I never used one with my first child. I never really needed to! I had the luxury of not having to regularly multi task whilst holding my son, so although I had one only used it a handful of occasions. When you have more than one child, a baby carrier is like air! Fundamental!!! You’ll need your hands free to do stuff, tend to your other child, household stuff, whatever, but in those early stages casually sitting breastfeeding or cuddling your newborn for hours isn’t always possible. Look for your nearest sling library and try before you buy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a decent bag. Notice I didn’t say baby bag. If you find a fit for purpose baby bag that works for you then run with it, but you really need a bag that’s big enough for what you need, accessible, and can be attached or hung on your pushchair with ease. If you buy a large bag you can purchase inserts for each child to differentiate between their things, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always carry a water bottle and food (not just for the kids!) - rehydrate and feed yourself too!! Whether you’re breastfeeding or not, a fuelled mummy is a happier mummy. Water is essential especially when breastfeeding. I remember getting headaches in the first few weeks of my daughters birth when I was dehydrated. Easy resolution! Drink!! And I don’t mean cocktails! As for eating, I had a habit of just eating in between meals, eating my sons left over food and sometimes being too tired to have my own meal once the kids are sleeping. This isn’t sustainable and you need to make sure you’re looking after yourself. So batch cook if it’s easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid to ask for help. My husband and I have always done everything ourselves due to geography, which has put a strain on us both as we seldom get time out. But now we have 2 children we actively welcome opportunities to get help and in the first 2 months of my daughters life I received help with my toddler to ensure he was stimulated daily, happy and engaged. Asking for help from your loved ones is not a sign of weakness or inability to cope. It really does take a village to raise a child. Put your village on speed dial and get them involved!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do your best to schedule your kids naps as close together as possible. Nap time is sacred. My son no longer naps. I know, I cried about it too, but if he did I would be taking this on board! Try and be consistent with bedtime too. Children love routine and once they know what to expect you’ll have an easier time getting them to comply. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find distraction techniques for the older child. Have quick go-to toys and games that your child loves to keep him/her occupied if you need to attend to the younger one. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get out of the house! Yes I know it sounds like a logistical nightmare and it can be the first couple of times when you work out what works for you, and literally ‘how’ to get you all clothed and fed to leave the house! But… once you get past the chaos, it will feel like you’ve reached nirvana! The fresh air and change of scenery will do wonders for your mental health and the children will feel better too! 
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sleep when they sleep. If you manage to get both kids sleeping simultaneously….grab your duvet and get involved! The washing, cooking, laundry, phonecall, can wait!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Date night. In-between feeds, nappy changes, projectile vomit, nursery runs and reruns of paw patrol remember how it all began and make some time for the love that started it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make time for yourself at least once a week. Even if it’s just half an hour of uninterruption. Do something you enjoy! Read a book, paint your nails, have a hot bath, go to the cinema, go for a swim. Whatever floats your boat, make time for it. You will always have lots to do, the list is endless, but if you make time for the things that are important to you and make them a priority rather than a ‘nice to have’ the rest of your time will be filled with the daily responsibilities and you’ll feel better for the little moments you made time for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Ten ways to improve confidence</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Self Improvement</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Success</category>
            
                <category>Risk Taking</category>
            
                <category>Confidence</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>1. Believe in yourself You need to be your own cheerleader.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-believe-in-yourself&#34;&gt;1. Believe in yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be your own cheerleader. Focus on the things you’re great at. Trust your own abilities. Remember the things you have achieved so far and use those memories as a foundation for the things you’d like to achieve in the future. Don’t be afraid to be heard. Your opinion is valuable and counts &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-silence-your-inner-critic&#34;&gt;2. Silence your inner critic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self deprecation needs to stop. When someone says you look great, say thank you. When someone congratulates you on a good job, again say thank you. Sometimes to silence the inner critic you need positive voices around you shouting louder! If you have no friends to reinforce Your good qualities and give you positive constructive feedback, then listen to energising talks, podcasts, videos, audio books, fill your spirit with so much positivity that the niggling inner critic will soon be drowned out… and reconsider your friendship circle! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-follow-through-with-what-you-say-you-will-do&#34;&gt;3. Follow through with what you say you will do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop procrastinating. Under promise and over deliver at first if you have to. But whatever you do, follow through. Differentiate between reasons and excuses. The more you get stuff done the more credible you will feel. It’s really as simple as that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-educate-yourself-stay-current&#34;&gt;4. Educate yourself - stay current.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge really is power and the more information you have the less you’ll feel like an imposter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-visualise-your-goals&#34;&gt;5. Visualise your goals &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create mind maps and mood boards. Someone once said to me ‘if you can see it you can have it’. Visualising your goals will make them more tangible, and on your road to a more confident you, make your vision of yourself a reality, but paint the picture first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-dress-to-impress-yourself&#34;&gt;6. Dress to impress yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason when you look good you feel good. When you put on your best you feel like you’re on the road to world domination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-monitor-your-progress&#34;&gt;7. Monitor your progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidence grows with progress, it’s really as simple as that. If you monitor your progress you can see just how far you’ve come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-be-shameless-and-stay-in-your-lane&#34;&gt;8. Be shameless and stay in your lane&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think less about what people think. Most people don’t have their ish together and are just faking it until they make it. Don’t worry about what others are doing or not doing! Don’t use other people as your benchmark for success. Just be you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;9-take-risks&#34;&gt;9. Take risks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risk takers are history makers. Heard of the saying he who dares wins? Risks are not for the faint hearted but to really grow in confidence you have to do things that scare you, and in stepping out of your comfort zone, you’re winning already. It takes confidence to take risks and be bold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-do-more-of-what-makes-you-happy-and-you-re-good-at&#34;&gt;10. Do more of what makes you happy and you’re good at&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidence is reinforced by joy. Be happy and confidence will exude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, please feel free to get in touch. I’ll be posting a new blog every Monday morning. You can follow me using the links on my site. Have a great week!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Heroin, carbs and a stable pay cheque</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Poetry</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Children</category>
            
                <category>Individuality</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>“The three biggest addictions are heroin, carbs, and a stable pay cheque” according to Nassim Taleb.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The three biggest addictions are heroin, carbs, and a stable pay cheque” according to Nassim Taleb.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m inclined to believe him! I’m presently trying to get a grip of two of these addictions…Thankfully I have never battled with heroin, the closest I’ve got to substance abuse has been a tea addiction! I didn’t even realise I was addicted until I decided to give it up for Lent….and the hulk appeared every morning instead of the amenable me….and the headaches….awful, throbbing migraines. But I’m proud to say I went cold turkey and I am 5 years clean and haven’t looked back! I am now content with a satisfying cup of decaf….rock and roll!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_395x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 395w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 790w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_1580x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 1580w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_2370x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 2370w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_3160x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two main forms of carbohydrates are sugars, such as fructose, glucose, and lactose, and starches, which are found in foods such as starchy vegetables,grains, rice, breads, and cereals. The body breaks down (or converts) most carbs into the sugar glucose, which is absorbed into the bloodstream. In my eyes carbs are a necessary part of a balanced diet, but in excess carbs are evil, tasty morsels of doughy sweet pleasure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be a UK size &lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;⁄&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;, without making any effort. I was one of those people, you loved to hate as it took no effort to consume a few Big Macs and a side of nuggets and still look like I was about to run a triathlon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I stupidly made an impulsive online purchase, completely in size denial. A gorgeous size 8 skirt…..what decade was I size 8?! Oh how the mighty fall, that ship has sailed and lost at sea! I’m not sure if it’s age, post baby body or simply that I’ve used up my quota of taking the piss out of human physiology but I now have to actually think about what I eat, and the muscle memory has &lt;strong&gt;left the building.&lt;/strong&gt; So carbs are not a friend, and my love of bread, and pasta, and pizza and rice, and fries and yams and all of the beautiful carbs of the world are becoming my nemesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst breastfeeding I think I eat my body weight in carbs daily. It’s a seriously uncontrollable craving and a bowl of lettuce and quinoa just won’t cut it. So I have no plans to give up carbs, but definitely need to reconsider how much I consume and find myself some satisfying alternatives. I’ll be blogging about these alternatives as and when I find them. If you know of any please share! I’m not going to promise to cut out carbs but I will be more carb conscious and to that effect I’ll aim to reduce my intake significantly! She says as she runs to grab her imported custard creams!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbs and my attachment to a stable pay cheque…both arguably equally as destructive to my waistline. I’ve spent the majority of my adult life addicted to the high of getting my pay at the end of the month it has paralysed me into falling for the mythical safety net. It’s reassured me into almost sleep-walking into retirement in a job I’d rather not be doing, tolerating treatment I don’t deserve, second guessing my worth and relegating my dreams to mere fantasy. We all need an income, and we can’t all be entrepreneurs. There’s no shame in the stability and comfort of a regular pay cheque. But if your dreams are keeping you awake at night and your hands are itching to create your destiny you may be on the road to beating the pay cheque addiction. I’m confident I’ll always be able to find a job that will pay my bills and enable me to survive….but I won’t always have the passion and energy to take risks that could result in me creating my own destiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scarily, the first month of the year is already almost over… That’s one twelfth of the year essentially done and dusted. I’ve only just finished writing my goals for the year, so I’ve missed 27 opportunities to work on achieving them. Yes it is that granula to me! Luckily I have plenty of days to make up for it, to stay focused and make my dreams a reality and I’m ready to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year has already brought our family challenges that appear insurmountable and draining the energy we started with, but as our glass is always half full and even half full we’re willing to give a sip or two to those in a drought, we are persevering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addiction is real, cold turkey isn’t for everyone. I’m a rip the plaster off kind of girl with a high pain threshold and minimal patience. Know yourself. Do what’s best for you. Make yourself a priority. But don’t let addiction of any sort rule your life. Take back the control, and make life enhancing choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, please feel free to get in touch. Before the arrival of my daughter I posted every Monday morning…once I come out of this sleep deprived funk, I’ll be posting regularly again(almost there!)! Please follow me on Medium, instagram, facebook and twitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to join Tech Mums, please join the facebook group&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>About</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/about/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/about/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
            
        
          
         

            <description>Mother-of-two, Tinu Alikor, also known as Tee or Tin Tin, has written for publications including The Observer and interviewed world leaders for Sky News.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[


  &lt;figure&gt;
   
      &lt;img
        srcset=&#34;
          /about/images/tinu_hue56be48886851b13b3998893a32010b3_863281_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /about/images/tinu_hue56be48886851b13b3998893a32010b3_863281_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /about/images/tinu_hue56be48886851b13b3998893a32010b3_863281_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /about/images/tinu_hue56be48886851b13b3998893a32010b3_863281_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /about/images/tinu_hue56be48886851b13b3998893a32010b3_863281_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w&#34;
          sizes=&#34;
            (min-width: 830px) 790px,
            100vw&#34;
        src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/about/images/tinu_hue56be48886851b13b3998893a32010b3_863281_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tinu Alikor&#34;/&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mother-of-two, Tinu Alikor, also known as Tee or Tin Tin, has written for publications including The Observer and interviewed world leaders for Sky News.  She has worked for the BBC, most notably recorded and presented programmes for BBC Radio 4 and BBC 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London born and raised in a single parent home, but presently shuffling between Zurich and London with her brood, she has lived and worked globally and enjoys travelling.  A writer, presenter, artist, food lover, entrepreneur, project manager, tech enthusiast, afro advocate and blogger who after 10 years of service in government, is currently in her toughest gig to date…motherhood!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve spent so long people pleasing, being selfless and putting other interests before my own….  now, whilst my parenting responsibilities remain I’m daring myself to just be me and make me a priority.  Join me on this shameless, limitless journey to finding my happy place, and proving that YOU CAN do anything you put your mind to”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog and podcast will be both a portfolio of personal work, and a platform for guest writers, offering an insight into the extraordinary lives of ordinary people. Please get in touch if you’d like to be featured!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Podcast</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/podcast/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/podcast/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
            
        
          
         

            <description> Coming soon!! </description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[

&lt;h3 id=&#34;coming-soon&#34;&gt;Coming soon!!&lt;/h3&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Tech mums</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/tech_mums/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/tech_mums/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
            
        
          
         

            <description>A group based in Zurich Switzerland for parents to gain useful technical skills provided by expert tutors in the industry with childcare.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[

&lt;p&gt;A group based in Zurich Switzerland for parents to gain useful technical skills provided by expert tutors in the industry with childcare. Have you always wanted to learn to code? Build your own website? Learn a new skill? Challenged by finding time and childcare? This could be just what you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are passionate about technology and excited about getting women into technology roles, hoping to change the tech environment and make it more flexible for women!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-objectives&#34;&gt;Our objectives:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To get more women in technology

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100 women in tech positions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 women embarking on technology start ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To positively influence businesses to be more family friendly

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 companies implementing flexible working practices. eg. job share and remote working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our facebook group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/techmums/&#34;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/groups/techmums/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch this space…&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>My Sonshine</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Poetry</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Children</category>
            
                <category>Individuality</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>This one. This brilliant, energetic, bold, adventurous, talkative, loving, mischievous boy with endless curiosity is my biggest test.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;This one. This brilliant, energetic, bold, adventurous, talkative, loving, mischievous boy with endless curiosity is my biggest test. He’s the child you’ll find in the sandpit after a huge downfall of rain playing snow angels in the mud. He’s the one that could find puddles in the desert and could give a puma a run for its money. The one you’ll find moving furniture to scale the table, or pulling the blender out of the cupboard to see how it works, or trying to hang from the window ledge so he can see the bus. He’s the one that can climb a mountain and still not tire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s the one you have to watch, I have ears and eyes everywhere. My patience is being challenged daily, but I know he’s just being a child, inquisitive, curious, testing the colours of life, testing boundaries, testing the physical integrity of every fixture in the apartment and excited by everything he encounters. It’s exhausting but beautiful to see and I am finding ways to nurture this passionate and inquisitive mind and channel his energy into producing something great, and just let him be. For truly great he will be. Wise, compassionate, loving, strong, sincere, motivated and kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s the one that will eat broccoli just so that his sister doesn’t cry. That asks me multiple times during the day if I’m ok. Who says I love you at every opportunity, and tells me I’m beautiful. And whose kisses and hugs are unrivalled warm embraces that feel like hot chocolate on a cold day. I wouldn’t have him any other way. My sonshine.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Absolutely Fabulous</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 05:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Podcasting</category>
            
                <category>Women In Tech</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/babies_hu9254ecaebb10959bdf27619441dc4657_438742_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>I saw a post the other day that made me laugh…</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I saw a post the other day that made me laugh…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“None of this new year new me bollocks, last year I was fabulous and next year I will be fabulous!”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very amusing, and vaguely relevant to me, I’m fabulous some days, possibly two days a week, but honestly, I think it’s BS. Maybe not a new me, but a better version of myself wouldn’t hurt, perhaps like a software update! I don’t want to put myself under any undue pressure….believe me, I’m already precariously balancing several bits of Swedish china at once, but without any pressure how do you move forward? Improvement is growth and staying fabulous takes a bit of work! I just need to find the right amount of pressure that’ll kick me out of bed to get stuff done but won’t leave me feeling like the soggy lettuce I found in my fridge this morning, if I drop the ball sometimes. I haven’t made any new years resolutions because I have genuinely been overwhelmed with ‘stuff’, to do lists, trello boards, survival lists, breastfeeding, laundry, nursery runs, cooking, cleaning, answering my 2 year olds repeated questions on underground trains and if mummy is having another baby? And did I say laundry already?! Laundry is a full time occupation in itself with a newborn and toddler! The washer and dryer are regularly abused by us, my husband is the family expert on this, I have more of a fly by the seat of your pants approach semi conscious and bundling heaves of milk and mud stained items of clothing in for saving… long live the washer and dryer….if anyone’s deliberating, separate washer and dryer gets a thumbs up from me if you have the space it’ll change your life! Middle aged confessions of a mum… No need for resolutions, just live, set goals achievable and stretching, and ambitious if you feel the urge, and be kind to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind there’s so much I want to do, but I really need to ace the basic getting the kids ready in under 2 hours and maintain my demeanour routine before I start trying to conquer the world! Or do I? I mean what am I really waiting for? Waiting for perfection before I take on something I’m passionate about sounds counterintuitive, or like a well versed delay tactic…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So….in pursuit of happiness and progress, not a tick boxing exercise or a fake fad or an overzealous binge diet, I am starting a new project! I am continuing my blog once a week channelling my thoughts and sharing my journey and soon I’ll be recording a podcast. Returning to a former passion I had the pleasure of finding in my teens with BBC Radio 4 when I recorded programmes and audio diaries. I’m looking forward to learning how to record, it feels like a natural progression from blogging, I’m in the process of researching, getting the right equipment and creating my structure and format. I have a few ideas I’m excited about and looking forward to putting it in to action. Watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may know I’ve been living in Switzerland with my husband and now two children. Housewife with the mostess… parenting like a supply teacher who should consider retiring. Finding my way through local culture, far from where I call home and the people I love, starting a new chapter in the land of cheese, orgasmic chocolate and fancy watches. The biggest change for me has been getting used to what being a housewife means. Or perhaps defining what we &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; my role to be and what we &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; my role to be, and getting it to fit with my passions and my desired direction. I’m jack of all trades, master of most. Like most parents I can’t have a day off, I don’t get sick leave. I don’t have it all together, and running seamlessly….but I do have the drive and passion that fuels my exhausted body to teach myself how to make meat pies for my 2 year old at 1am because we can’t get them out here… Yes I did that last night… so basically Beyonce is right &lt;strong&gt;we run the world!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second project this year will be something that’s close to my heart. Married to a techie, I’ve grown to love tech more and realise just how much it influences our daily lives. I’m motivated enough to function on minimal sleep and love technology, but most of all I love people and getting the best out of them. And I’ve had the pleasure of meeting awesome women out here, some who just like me followed their spouse across water, land, or just a car park to pursue a dream. Fully supporting the husbands career and building a home often means that some women are unable to fulfill their own goals and realise their own passions. Coupled with a system here that encourages women to stay at home, getting back to work after having a baby or just being a homemaking spouse can sometimes be a tall order, and even taller for us foreign folk, the expat crew. So I’m setting up a coding school called Tech Mums with childcare here in Zurich, Switzerland!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_395x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 395w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 790w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_1580x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 1580w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_2370x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 2370w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_3160x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Mums will be a place where mums can learn a new skill, invest in their career, network with like minded parents and professionals, socialise, update their skillset&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and get back to work if they choose! I had the pleasure of being a part of a similar initiative in London called Mums in Technology, and found it to be invaluable, supportive and groundbreaking. I am excited to be starting a project that inspires me to get more women in technology here in Switzerland! Lean into the sisterhood and stay fabulous…I want to inspire and be inspired. To create a welcoming, nurturing environment where mums can come and be themselves, gain a friend, gain a hobby, gain a skill and get the tools they need to kick some arse into a career they can thrive in…let’s go!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Be the change you want to see</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 06:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>New Year</category>
            
                <category>Feminism</category>
            
                <category>New Year Resolution</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I gave birth to my daughter not so long ago…and my life changed.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I gave birth to my daughter not so long ago…and my life changed. All of a sudden I feel the need to be the woman my daughter will respect and look up to. A woman of integrity and good standing. A woman she’d be proud to call her mum. I didn’t quite feel the same when I had my son. Yes, I felt the basic maternal pull of wanting to be a good role model and parent, and keep him happy and create a nurturing loving environment for him. But this awareness of my daughter, a woman in the making, in a world where we have fought for equality tirelessly and still argue over the gender pay gap and general sexism, I fear that I have brought her into a world that won’t give her the chance she deserves. But I want to teach her to take what she deserves and throw away the notion that you get what you’re given and to wait politely for your turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to equip her with the tools to make the best of every situation. To thrive even in arid conditions. To be a lover not a hater. I want her to be resilient, strong, feisty, unrepentant in truth, strong willed and vivacious. To be herself, authentic, unapologetic, fierce and loving. To see her unairbrushed, undiluted beauty. I want her to feel entitled to success, to belong if she chooses, to banish any emotions of imposition, to set her own standards, dance to her own beat and to enjoy every moment as if it were her last. I need to lead by example…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2019 is moments away…a new year, full of new opportunities, new hope, new challenges, new adventures. I’m excited, and apprehensive and eager to embark on a new chapter. I’ve been a stay at home mother for almost three years. Enjoying the fruit of nurturing the growth of my children and balancing my need for personal satisfaction with my responsibilities as a mother and wife. I’m enjoying this stage in my life and preparing for my next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going into this year putting the pains and mistakes of 2018 behind me, learning as I go. Allowing doors that need to be closed to stay firmly shut, looking forward to new doors being open. Finding new zeal and passion for progress, and making me a priority. Grateful for loyal friends whose love is without condition. Looking forward to continuing raising my children in love and peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, may you find joy, and may your dreams find you. May you be the change you want to see. May you find peace in your decisions. May you find vision helpers and people who truly have your back. May your husband replace the toilet roll occasionally, and take the rubbish out without complaining. May your boobs recover from breastfeeding and may postpartum hair loss be a myth, may you get some precious sleep without being shocked awake with a chubby finger in your nostril. May your glass of prosecco always runneth over. May you find the strength to make the changes you need and the resilience to plan without fear of failure. And mostly may you remember just how wonderful you are and have the potential to be, and simply be thankful for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t create your life first and then live it. You create it by living it not agonising over it! Whatever your situation be the best version of yourself! May this year be a year of doing, and living. Happy New Year! Be intentional…&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Adulting</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 16:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Miscarriage</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Children</category>
            
                <category>Pregnancy</category>
            
                <category>Fertility</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Last year I became a member of a club that no one wants to talk about.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Last year I became a member of a club that no one wants to talk about. A club in which membership is one of the most painful experiences most will face in their lifetime and all are pretty much powerless to avoid. We found out we were expecting a baby in December 2017, excited and full of hope and expectation we celebrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As tradition encourages we were hoping to share our good news after the first scan at 12 weeks….we never got to 12 weeks… in fact we never got to 3 weeks We experienced a miscarriage on Christmas Eve last year. I spent the holidays putting on a brave face, trying to behave like nothing had happened, for my sanity, for my son, for us. Inside I was distraught, I rarely get a moment to myself, but when I did, I found myself sobbing, feeling an overwhelming sense of grief. Confused as to what had happened. What had I done wrong? Why had this happened? Did I run too fast for the bus? Did I over exert myself carrying shopping? Did I check the date on that yoghurt that I ate yesterday? Will this consuming fear of going to the toilet ever subside? Will I ever feel like me again? Will this feeling that my body has let me down ever go away?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pregnancy is beautiful and inspiring, and wonderful. Bursting with hope, expectation and dreams. Carrying a life, growing a life, sustaining and nurturing a life is beyond description. Your life changes the moment you read that pee stick, the moment you realise that a life is beginning to take shape. Your imagination begins to run away with itself. Names, hair colour, eye colour, is it going to be a boy or a girl, who will the baby look like, what colour scheme will the nursery have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent 5 gruelling hours waiting to be seen in a soulless hospital in Switzerland that resembled a burnt down housing estate in Peckham. I sat in the cold waiting room watching my son play with the water dispenser and throw all the leaflets neatly piled on the table in the bin, as he joyfully sang ‘tidy up tidy up’ .When I was called in the doctor asked me if I was sure I had been pregnant and did I feel pregnant? That question was like someone sucker punched me in the abdomen…what did she mean was I sure??! Would anyone lie in this situation?!!! She examined me and sent me home as though I had complained of a common cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among women who know they’re pregnant, it’s estimated about 1 in 8 pregnancies will end in miscarriage. 1 in 8 is a shocking statistic considering I only know two people who’ve told me they have experienced miscarriage. I’m not sure why we don’t talk about it, but I wish we did. I wish we spoke about our fears and shared our experiences. It makes us stronger, comforted, better equipped, and helps us to put things in perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got pregnant again, I wish someone told me it was normal to be anxious, to fear going to the toilet daily. To worry yourself into a state of immobilisation. Talking and sharing helps. Someone may find comfort in your story, someone may be going through the same pain and feel lost and alone. Miscarriage isn’t shameful, or embarrassing…it happens to so many of us…men feel it too…it’s out of our control… and takes life altering strength to keep on when you just want to disappear. I share this because I am not ashamed, I am proud that we found strength to persevere, we found healing and I’m grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up I didn’t know if I would ever have children, I guess I never dreamed it would happen. Some spend their lives dreaming and hoping and one miscarriage after another their hopes disappear. There is fulfilment without children, there are so many wonderful opportunities and experiences in the world. Focus on what you have, your blessings, what makes you happy, what makes you smile. There are so many unwanted children that need a home, not enough of us consider adoption. And not all of us are meant to be parents…that’s ok too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I’m in week 8 of being a mother of two….still yet to wake up feeling like I know what I’m doing, or even should be doing….thought that might have happened by now… I’m so grateful for my daughter, she’s an absolute gem. Sleeps, eats, shits, repeats. What more could I ask for?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s pretty much a model baby, she’s not the problem, it’s me and trying to work out how on earth I am going to keep two under 3’s alive! My toddler has been ok ish….he’s absolutely in love with the newborn, surprisingly the novelty hasn’t quite worn off yet and he doesn’t think we’re taking her back for a refund! I’ve heard some scary horror stories of toddlers and ‘welcoming’ a new born and thankfully we haven’t had to manage that kind of jealousy. He hasn’t attempted to throw her in the bin or put her in the toilet…so we’re good!! Parents of multiple children, I salute you! Single parents of multiple children…I prostrate…are you even human?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My toddler does however think he’s the newest member of WWF and that my daughter is a potential prop for his wrestling, so the majority of my day is spent keeping the toddler at bay from the newborn, boisterous hugs and belly flops are not welcome! I’m still telling my toddler that the baby’s cot is not the most ideal place for his supersize noisy ambulance and isn’t really the most appropriate place to practice diving from…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than bucket loads of patience and repeating ‘be gentle’ and ‘soft hands’ like it’s going out of fashion there are a few things we did to try and prepare our loving toddler for the arrival of his sister. Firstly, everything we could change we changed at least 4 months before she was born. From the stories I’ve heard of toddlers battling for attention and displaying negative behavioural responses to new siblings it just seems like a human. emotionally charged response to a huge change, a change in hierarchy, a change in attention, focus, time, routine. So implementing these changes in stages and trying to remove the connection with the arrival of the new baby seemed liked the best solution. We changed my sons bed, moving him out of his cot and into a bed. We started using a double pram with just him in it. We put him into nursery a few days a week and generally talk about the baby in gentle conversations about his role as a big brother and how important he will be. So my son doesn’t associate any of those changes with the arrival of his sister. She hasn’t ‘taken’ anything that used to be his. Change can create resentment and hostility and that’s what I wanted to avoid. Now I need to work on ensuring that now she is here I create regular one on one time with my toddler. Mummy and Joshua time, where the baby isn’t hanging off my boob, and Joshua gets undiluted Mummy time. The baby sling is my new best friend. I can see this being a very steep learning curve…any tips throw them my way!!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>I Do…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Love</category>
            
                <category>Marriage</category>
            
                <category>Relationships</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
                <category>Friendship</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/images/feature_hu37a066ceaef65215736dc63427c4303c_1755211_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I thought I’d introduce my other half properly as I’m sure he’ll be featuring in some of my blogs and it’s only polite to give you a brief low down on the man that is the pepper in my stew, custard on my crumble, my Mr Big.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I thought I’d introduce my other half properly as I’m sure he’ll be featuring in some of my blogs and it’s only polite to give you a brief low down on the man that is the pepper in my stew, custard on my crumble, my Mr Big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started this post initially wanting to introduce our benetton backgrounds but then it struck me that I’m not adequately equipped to really do it justice as we were both born and bred in London and pie and mash are in our veins with a hint of egusi and flying fish. But diverse we are, my parents are Nigerian and husband’s background stems from Barbados, Nigeria and the UK. Despite this eclectic mix which we hold with pride, we’re both fundamentally Londoners, the melting pot that is the big smoke. And currently global citizens of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just happens that my husband Madu spent the first three years of his life in a small village in Nigeria with his parents. The rest of his formative years were in London, but somehow he’s managed to embody the essence of a southern Nigerian man with little effort! Definitely more nature than nurture! An interesting mix of genetic tendencies and perhaps a desire to belong. It’s funny it’s difficult to define a Londoners cultural identity, it can be a blur of complimentary or sometimes opposing ideals, but whatever the composition we love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met online and have been literally inseparable since our first date in Mango Room. From surprise evenings out in West End to an impromptu week long road trip adventure on one of my work stints in Jamaica. Six months after meeting he quit his job and flew out to propose…we haven’t looked back since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday my blender gave up the ghost and I almost cried, it’s been good to me and lasted more years than I care to admit, but owning a blender is synonymous with being a Nigerian. And now I’m in a culinary abyss without it. My other concern is that if I don’t replace it sharpish, so close to Christmas I’ll end up with a new blender from Madu as a present…romance isn’t dead, he’s just pragmatic and Igbo(!) At least that’s what he tells me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s a loving, gentle, technology obsessed man who prides himself on being current, always aims for the best and can negotiate a pay rise with slick aptitude and unrivalled confidence. He taught me to love me more, believes in me when I don’t believe in myself. And encourages me to pursue my dreams. That’s a pretty basic but beautiful asset to have, someone who’s always in your corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, his confidence borders arrogance at times, he sometimes has a problem with authority, is very opinionated and isn’t scared of being fired for what he believes in. His level of maturity needs to step up a few notches as risks don’t just affect him anymore, and we’re no longer in batchelor territory. Every decision impacts his family. Unemployment is not a word I enjoy discussing over my spag bog, but it’s a conversation I’ve had with him one too many times. But because he is who he is, he knows he can get another well paid job relatively easily….but is that the point? Marriage puts you in situations that you just can’t run away from. It forces you to face another persons bad habits and shortcomings head on. There is nowhere to hide. And once you have children the dynamic further alters as you do all that you can to put them first and maintain a stable loving environment. Being told by your husband that he’s job hunting in your 34th week of pregnancy isn’t fun. But apparently it’s all going to be ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marriage is a complex fusion of hearts and minds. Where Mars and Venus align and two attempt to become one. Where perfectionist Polly is confronted with dirty Daves dirty laundry scattered in obscure parts of the home, often next to the laundry basket….strangely it never quite makes it in. Where unintentional blindness is actually a serious condition. Where multi-tasking is apparently a female attribute and replacing the bog roll is a job that requires deep commitment. A friend of mine once said to me that people often forget that marriage is a journey not a destination. And that’s spot on. It’s a work in progress, a marathon, not a sprint. I’m lucky to have married my best friend, as inscribed on his wedding band, my ride or die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If people were honest about how tough marriage can be, many would probably avoid it or feel less defeated if it eludes them. Marriage is beautiful and life changing and all consuming, and frustrating and exposing. It’s choosing someone to be vulnerable with, to laugh with and ride the waves of life with. It truly is in sickness and in health, through the good times and the bad. It takes resilience, patience, forgiveness and a sense of humour you didn’t know you had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember the last time I went to the toilet alone. And that’s not just my two year old who barges in on me. Lock the door I hear you say! Yes I would if we didn’t have those annoying child safety door stoppers to stop my son from losing precious digits in the hinges! But seriously…can a girl just go in peace?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had any dignity when we got hitched, and I’d like to think I did! It soon evaporated during child birth. A wonderful, eye watering, life altering experience that stripped me back to my core. Madu was an awesome birth partner, attentive and supportive, although confronting me with photographic and video evidence of the birth of our son without my knowledge almost got him fired, apprentice style! We’ve just been blessed with the arrival of our beautiful daughter, here’s my husband having an obviously much needed rest after I’ve given birth(!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a rule when dating years ago, as soon as I liked someone enough to grace them with a second or third date I would ensure I orchestrated a dress down meet up where I wore minimal make up, casual clothes and my hair was in it’s original afro form. I’d do this occasionally if we continued to date and I hadn’t frightened them with my Erykah Badu vibes! I wish more women did this, and they would perhaps be more likely to attract partners that are less superficial! Waking up to put on a full face before your partner wakes up is crazy behaviour. I’d love to hear from women who actually keep this up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This evening my husband wouldn’t let me finish a sentence and just kept interrupting me. I found it rude and annoying, so as he did it repeatedly I just stopped talking, as clearly he’d prefer to hear the sound of his own voice, so why spoil it for him(!) Then he says I’m harping on about him interrupting me, and just get on with what I have to say….my response to that contains many expletives none of which are suitable for print….marriage gives you a level of patience you didn’t know was possible. And teaches you to forgive even when the other person doesn’t deserve it. It pushes you to prioritise your union and count to a million before you bail. It prevents you from throwing heavy objects at your husband when he jokes about saving money by manually expressing milk rather than buying one of those “over rated pumps”. Marriage is for the mature, the selfless and the committed. Loving someone without condition, loving someone who ate the last import only hobnob and cunningly and perhaps cruelly left the packaging in the cupboard, so you had no idea they were even finished….yes people do that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marriage is full of light and wonder, comfort and hope. It has renewed my faith in humanity and given me joy beyond measure and two beautiful children. I’m still understanding what being a wife means, this year I asked for a wife for Christmas…everyone needs a good one! We’re enjoying the learning and the journey. so that’s us the Alikor’s, hopelessly devoted and grateful to have each other.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Too much choice?</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/too-much-choice/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 07:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/too-much-choice/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Love</category>
            
                <category>Relationships Love Dating</category>
            
                <category>Compromise</category>
            
                <category>Decision Making</category>
            
                <category>Life</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/too-much-choice/images/feature_huf3d7d8729afc8d08aa5a2d237dcd9a56_2987805_790x0_resize_box_2.png" />
          
         

            <description>Are we the generation that just have too many options?</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Are we the generation that just have too many options??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One where we dismiss potential partners with a quick flick, could easily go on a date a day if our schedules permitted and take pride in our mantra of choosing not to ‘settle’. Now what exactly is settling??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To settle actually means to resolve or reach an agreement about (an argument or problem). But in this modern age when we refer to settling in a relationship context we deem it to be negative and unsatisfactory. Let’s just go over this again….to settle is to reach an agreement or resolve and argument or problem. So if your problem is loneliness but your list of must haves includes a shiny full head of hair, and Bob comes along with a receding hairline who makes you laugh and texts you sweet nothings daily, then you’ve found a potential resolve to your problem. Is this settling? Now…how important is this hair issue…? Is it a deal breaker?? Will you have sleepless nights thinking about Bobs hair shedding on his pillow? Will you cringe every time you have to imagine running your hands through his non existent mane…? The world’s ending I know….I mean don’t get me wrong, I like a good head of hair along with the next girl. But if my problem is loneliness and I find a good man with follicle issues I’m going to snap that man up and go and hug a wig in the hair shop if it makes me feel better. If this is settling….according to the millenial Oxford definition, then I’m a settler and proud!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Settling” in a relationship context according to the urban dictionary means accepting significantly less than you want, because you don’t think you can get what you want. Apparently it doesn’t have anything to do with being “better” than the other person, but it does imply that you’re not actually passionate about the person and are simply taking what you can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this is where I disagree, and feel it to be more about perception. Having a list of 5 requirements in a partner and finding Bob only has 3 out of the five could be deemed as “settling”. If you perceive you have drawn the short straw and should in fact strive to find the holy grail and tick all 5 boxes then yes that is settling and will possibly leave you feeling discontent, unhappy and dissatisfied. However if your list of 5 requirements is admittedly unreasonable at best, or even mythical and on reflection they don’t mean much to you, then passing on the potential for love is a loss. What really matters to you? What do you regard as a game changer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Settling is letting go of the things that are not important to you. The stuff that you can live without. It’s not compromising, or being defeated by fear. It’s changing your perception and saying yes more! Dating is such a minefield in this day. We swipe till our fingers hurt and have lost the art of conversation and getting beneath the hood, (no pun intended). We imagine our lives pictured in fairytales that make us hold out for the glass slipper when actually we’d be more suited to some comfy pumps. I’m all for having high standards and waiting for the ‘one’ but the truth is sometimes we can get caught up in the noise of apps and social media, and lose sight of what really matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you remember who you were before you were told who to be? Who to like, what to like? What to expect, what to achieve? How to achieve it? Finding the person whom you can’t live without can be a tall order, but if you get rid of the noise of perfection and settling, the journey may be a little easier. It’s so easy to sleep walk in to situations, but today I’m asking you to open your eyes and take the reigns back. It’s never too late to strive for what you want, don’t be overwhelmed or intimidated with the blur of choice that surrounds you. Only one person matters and that’s you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a jungle out there, there’s no denying that. In every sphere of life we have options and the decisions we make colour our path and provide the hinges to the doors that open and close in our lives. My wish for you is to find peace, happiness and contentment. Pursue what you want with vigour and passion. And settle for nothing less than your happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Dreams Don’t Expire</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 07:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Dreams</category>
            
                <category>Hopes And Dreams</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/images/feature_hud963163ef20da0887dddfc3ae1a095c2_492555_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>When I was 8 if you had asked me what I want to be when I grow up my answers were as colourful as my prized Care Bear lunch box…pilot, lawyer, doctor, painter, architect, ballerina, astronaut, UN leader, journalist, news reader, butcher, baker, candlestick maker…and I truly believed I could be any one of those on any given day, and perhaps moonlight in one I was less keen on in the evenings!</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;When I was 8 if you had asked me what I want to be when I grow up my answers were as colourful as my prized Care Bear lunch box…pilot, lawyer, doctor, painter, architect, ballerina, astronaut, UN leader, journalist, news reader, butcher, baker, candlestick maker…and I truly believed I could be any one of those on any given day, and perhaps moonlight in one I was less keen on in the evenings! Cute? Ambitious much?! Or even perhaps ridiculous? Like most children I was a dreamer, with boundless priceless possibilities in my mind. Innocent desire that had no limitations. That had no concept of can’t, no glass ceilings, or iron doors, or gender pay gaps or concept of discrimination, or insecurities. Just dreams. Dreams that I loved to picture, that gave me drive, motivated me to do my homework, gave me a goal, a purpose and a passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m in my 30s I’m not sure I have space for my dreams right now. Time to dream, or the energy to pursue them. But I need to make space. Space to imagine the impossible, to conjure up paths full of adventure, of hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I the only one who’s shelved my dreams? The only one who’s decided dreaming is for kids, adults don’t dream, they get real. Life is real, and when the reality of its fabric hits you, the dreamer fairytale is squashed. What a travesty! What’s the point of living if you can’t dream? What happened to that gooey feeling when you think of all the possibilities and hopes? What happened to the energy you felt when someone asked you what you wanted to be when you grew up? Just because you didn’t make it to the Bar or aren’t a famous West End dancer, that doesn’t mean you should stop dreaming. A dream changed is not a dream lost. We can just pivot…can’t we… aim for the moon and hit the stars…aim for something…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do we stop trying to fulfil our dreams? Fear of not living up to those dreams? When did dreams get old? Maybe in adulthood we rename dreams ‘goals’? Maybe it’s easier to comprehend. When did we start trying to apply the SMART criteria to dreams? Specific, measurable, achievable, results-focused, and time- bound! Don’t confine your dreams to principles. Dreams are glorious, and big and seemingly unachievable, and uplifting and scary. We need them! They keep us alive, motivated , focused and inspired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine Charlotte Philby has just announced completion of one of her life’s dreams! A spy novel she’s been working on! What an achievement! What a feeling to have started and finished! To have accomplished and reached the peak of one of your wild imaginations! Awesome and inspiring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going back to the drawing board of dreams and writing up new ones and rehashing old post-its that have been relegated to a notebook I bought in 1991. I’m bringing back dreams! They push me out of my comfort zone. Big dreams are like big knickers, we all need them even if we don’t admit it! I’m not ashamed of my big knickers, I’m not ashamed of my dreams. One day I’ll be sharing completion of my big dreams too and celebrating even the small wins with glee! If your dreams don’t scare you they’re not big enough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share your dreams with those you love. Once you vocalise them they become tangible and possible. Dreams can change and evolve, but don’t crush your dreams or let others. Don’t give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t create your life first and then live it. You create it by living it! Not agonising over it. Try letting go of perfection today and dream! Dream because you deserve to be free to think the impossible. Because dreamers are doers. Because sometimes we’re surrounded by walls and restrictions, and dreams elevate us into a beautiful realm of possibilities. Let go of perfect and dream. I’d love to hear your dreams!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Fail Like a Boss</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Failure</category>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Fear Of Failure</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/images/feature_hu922ba9b63a8233a3c6308bd992b0acb5_4597736_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School. Apparently he has passed his probationary period! Yay!! ! But a probationary period….so he can pass or fail? Eurgh…please tell me they’re not starting this already! He’s 2!!! He can’t fail!! Surely?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then began questioning myself and why I took issue with the suggestion of a probationary period and the thought that my child may be rejected. ‘Rejection’ is so emotive! Are we so sensitive that the thought of being measured or challenged makes us inherently uncomfortable? Is failing at something a conclusive label? What’s wrong with failing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son may not be best suited to a particular environment or activity depending on his disposition, but fail…? No no no….I’m a great believer in exposing children to as many new experiences as you can and letting them decide what they enjoy, or have an affinity for. I don’t want to be pushy or overbearing, just trying to find a balance between being encouraging and of course being protective and having his best interests at heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many of us pre-empt what we think our children can handle, we allow our own characteristics to define our children’s potential. We often label them, and spend their formative years projecting ourselves on their blank canvases, before they can even pronounce the word ‘fail’. In trying to protect them we confine them to our own limitations. Sometimes we confuse genuine care with control and fear. Finding the right balance is not easy…like most aspects of parenting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not big on wildlife and nature. I’m in awe of the beauty of the world and intrigued by animals…and have had the pleasure of experiencing some truly breathtaking sights all over the world. But whilst I love an adventure, and have been known to get stuck into spontaneous excursions, white water rafting, zip lining and (indoor) skydiving, I’m Nigerian, my mum would slap me if I voluntarily threw myself out of a plane. But I’m more comfortable reclining in an air conditioned vehicle observing the various spectacles than being knee deep in dirt swatting away creatures that quite possibly could send me into a panicked state of hyperventilation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So roughing it in campsites, sharing a bathroom and using toilet facilities that involve holes in the ground are just not my thing. But of course I don’t want to inflict my princess ways on my child. He’ll learn some grit from me, but not the kind that’s suitable for any bush tucker trial. So I’m trying my best to put my own sensibilities aside and allow my son to learn and grow, and experience the world through his own lens. And that’s what parenting is all about. Trying not to screw your child over with the sometimes messed up issues you may have whilst keeping them alive and happy! Tall order!
Have you ever been so afraid at failing at something you decided not to try at all? Is the fear of failure so strong that it surpasses the fear of regret or stagnation? I’m not sure why we’re so fearful of failing, personally I’d rather fail quickly and move on than paralyse myself into not trying at all. I guess I have more of a fear of regret than a fear of failure. Failing is ok, it means you had the guts to try and that in itself deserves a pat on the back. Failure should be followed by a personal debrief, what went wrong? How can you avoid it in the future? It’s ok to fail, but failing to try is a waste of your potential. And you have potential!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m altering my perspective and promoting failure, as it is in the trying that we truly become great. I want my son to grasp opportunities with both hands and I’ll try my best to stand behind him and cushion if his falls. Falling is ok, as long as you get up again. And it doesn’t matter how many times you fail, keep rising, and don’t stop trying.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Love yourself</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Self Love</category>
            
                <category>Self Healing</category>
            
                <category>Bullying</category>
            
                <category>Positivity</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/images/feature_hu8bc1fff2af24458dba8e5250014f41bc_145314_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>This blog is for everyone who contacted me in private or public about one of my previous blogs ‘ Freedom’.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;This blog is for everyone who contacted me in private or public about one of my previous blogs ‘ Freedom’. I was brought to tears by you reaching out to share your stories with me. I’m touched by the strength in your daily struggles and the memories that you hold on to. I’m inspired by you. Thank you for reaching out, thank you for sharing. Vulnerability is not weakness, it’s powerful. Freedom in your mind and thoughts, freedom in your choices, freedom in your movements, freedom in your memories, that’s what I strive for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever you choose to do, please don’t suffer in silence. So many people are hurting in isolation. Facing mountains they cannot climb alone. Confronting battles they don’t know how to navigate. Someone somewhere can help. Talk, be heard, share… nothing is insurmountable and although it may seem like it sometimes, you are not alone. Sometimes you just need to reach out, cry, scream, whisper…just be heard. You deserve to be heard, valued and appreciated.You’re stronger than you give yourself credit for, but you don’t need to carry the weight alone. A problem shared is truly a problem halved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the unfortunate experience of being bullied for just over a year some time ago. I let someone make me believe I was inferior, worthless and incapable, and once a voice is prominent enough, allowed enough volume, and persistent it becomes the only noise you hear. Abuse can come in so many forms…all are unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emotional abuse is like an undetected gas leak. You often don’t see it coming or realise when it’s escalating. It’s difficult to even quantify its impact but the trail of destruction is undeniable. When I think back to those dark days when I didn’t want to get out of bed or eat…when the smallest feat seemed impossible, when I almost took a woman out for pushing me on the Northern Line, and cried when I dropped a bag of percy pigs, I genuinely thought I was losing the plot. I remember someone telling me how much I had changed and asking me what had happened to the Tinu he used to know? I had no idea? What had happened? Where had she gone?? Had she left the building? Had I really changed so much? I hadn’t noticed….but one day through a blur of mascara I turned off auto pilot. I decided to actually look at myself in the mirror. It felt like I was staring for hours, I just didn’t recognise myself. I was a hollow resemblance of the confident girl who interviewed Tony Blair in her teens, and gave Ann Widdecombe a run for her money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had allowed someone to impose their own self hatred on me. I believed her. I don’t know why my self esteem was so low but it was, and the consequence was years of self doubt, low confidence and an impenetrable imposter syndrome. I’m in recovery now, I removed myself from the situation and have started some serious kumbaya sessions listening to kick arse Ted talks and getting my mojo back. I didn’t see it coming, and I didn’t recognise just how bad it was as I was actively avoiding every reflective surface and hiding in my own shadow. That’s how I believe the bullying went from a few snarly throw away comments to a barrage of painful, insensitive relentless attacks. I stopped looking in the mirror. I was ashamed of what I had become, and in running away from it I was only making matters worse. Bullies thrive on victim isolation…don’t be a victim and please look at the beauty you see in the mirror before you don’t recognise the person staring back at you. Love yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep coming across these new social media phrases, ‘self love’, ‘living my best life’ and ‘self care’ essentially they all mean the same thing…be good to yourself, but what does it mean to you? Everyday I’m choosing to love me. I’m doing something ‘selfish’ that makes me happy and makes me a priority. Today I painted my nails, yesterday I bought a bottle of root beer and didn’t share it! And I loved it….so rock and roll! Whatever your situation is, the daily choices you make paint your life’s canvas. I constantly remind myself of the advice given on aeroplanes…put your own oxygen mask on first. You can’t help anyone if you cut off your own supply. So I encourage you to do abit of self hugging and loving today. Make a point of doing something for yourself everyday, no matter how small or seemingly insignificant, and take time to look at you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling trapped and stagnant is a painful position to find yourself in. Claustrophobic, suffocated, helpless, directionless. But there’s a light at the end of every tunnel. And you can create that light…don’t wait for someone to hand you a torch. A well known proverb describes hope perfectly, “Just when the caterpillar thought the world was ending, it turned into a butterfly.” Hope is an expectation, and my hope for you is that you harness the strength within you to move forward. That you see your glass half full and change your perception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scars are the best tattoos. They represent battles fought and won. They tell a story, your story. Stop hiding your scars and show them with pride. You are winning. Every night my son and I pray and go through positive affirmations. If you ask him, he’ll say he’s a winner…and that he’s always on top. If a two year old can do it, so can you! You are a winner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you can’t fly then run, if you can’t run then walk, if you can’t walk then crawl, but whatever you do you have to keep moving forward.” ― Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>We’re all equal in the sky…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Travel</category>
            
                <category>Discrimination</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Disability</category>
            
                <category>British Airways</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/feature_hu9ac72fe668a507003fd0f28db21e8729_1160980_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>So my most recent flight from Switzerland to London has taken me awhile to recover from.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;So my most recent flight from Switzerland to London has taken me awhile to recover from. I am a seasoned traveller who isn’t easily flustered. I plan my route, prepare my luggage and get going! Saying this being a black female, with mobility issues travelling with a toddler whilst pregnant puts a slightly different spin on the situation and its this I’d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m always trying to do it all, juggling, balancing plates on my head whilst spinning wheels in my palms…I’m the consummate multi tasker. Like most, you just get on without considering the extent of the task you’re embarking on. If it’s got to get done, you just do. Having a toddler who doesn’t always fit nicely into my trello board of actions and more often than not actually seems to purposely sabotage my zen goals, just makes my multi tasking all the more challenging and sometimes fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I forget to add that I have mobility issues too….?! Yep I have scoliosis and had a major op on my leg so walking long distances carrying luggage isn’t possible for me unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve got a few things making life a little more colourful it seems but I still need to get from A to B. I do everything within my power to prepare for the trip, and even requested for mobility assistance when booking my flight. On a previous journey I had been reprimanded…yes reprimanded for not requesting assistance for both myself and my son, as they sent one person to assist me and despite my booking clearly being for myself and my 2 year old son, they apparently assumed he’d manage to get himself to the gate and just meet me there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this time I was ready, I prudently booked assistance for both of us. I arrived at check in with ample time. I reminded them I had requested assistance and was told to wait in the waiting area for assistance to arrive. I waited…..and waited…..and waited…..sorry did I forget to say I have an active two year old?!? And waited….nothing….feeling a little anxious about the flight time, I went back to the desk and asked for an update and reminded them I was still waiting. I was told that the flight had been delayed and they had no idea when the plane would arrive, and that someone would let me know…..a series of ambiguous statements after waiting for almost 2 hours with a toddler….no one informed me of any changes to the flight time and rather some half an hour later, assistance arrived. She took one look at me and abruptly told me she wasn’t there to run after my baby!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now….please enlighten me…. a pregnant passenger with mobility issues travelling with her baby requests for assistance and this is the response?! I told her I had not expected anyone to ‘run after my child’ and simply needed one person to push me in the wheelchair and another to push his pram. Or be transported in one of those buggy carts. I would have happily had my son on my lap but apparently health and safety regulations do not permit this, so what other option do I have?! She said that isn’t going to happen, and I burst into tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was the hormones, maybe it was the frustration. I feel like I am constantly at war with the world. Fighting to prove that I can do it all, and sometimes I just can’t….and when I ask for help, I really need it…..and if it’s offered and then taken away with such humiliation I’m lost. That day I was lost. What do I do? I always work on the premise that you just need to learn to deal with things yourself. Lower your expectations of people and get on with what you need to do…I plan for disappointment daily. I plan for having to do it all…. but when a company pretends to offer a service that means that for once I can plan for someone to help me, and at my most vulnerable I realise that once again I’m on my own, I’m reduced to tears. I cried because had this happened two hours before I would have somehow got myself and my son to the gate. I would have walked at a pace I can manage, taken breaks if I needed to and just got on with it. But with no time to get through security and then walk to the gate I felt helpless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing they had reduced me to tears somehow they managed to get another person to push my son in the pram whilst I sobbed in the wheelchair. But it was too late. Whatever shred of dignity I had when I arrived had been reduced to the size of the wet boarding pass I held in my hand. They left me at the plane entrance, no staff helped me board the flight, a passenger kindly helped me with my hand baggage, whilst the air stewards looked on. It wasn’t heavy, but I am unable to even reach the over head lockers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On arrival at Heathrow it didn’t get much better. Again no assistance disembarking with my hand luggage and toddler. I left the plane and mobility assistance was waiting at the entrance. I told the assistant my son had a buggy that was usually brought to the plane entrance. The buggy arrived and she asked me to carry it to the mobility transportation! Carry it??! How on earth can I carry it?! I am asking for assistance and you expect me to carry a large buggy?!! I told her I can’t do that as it’s too heavy, and if she’d give me a moment I can unfold it and simply push it. To which she rolled her eyes and waited. Again no assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the transportation and I put my luggage and my son on the buggy cart, again no assistance. She began to drive and it soon became apparent that all of the lifts were surprisingly out of service! She stopped the cart and said that we had to walk. I saw several other passengers being driven in buggy carts over take us and I wondered what route they were taking and why their assistant had not demanded they walk? Surely we are all going to the exit? I was exhausted by now and asked her if she could ask one of her colleagues if there was another way she could take to avoid us having to walk. She reluctantly did so, and lo and behold there was another route!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am dumbfounded as to how @Britishairways and both Zurich and Heathrow airport handled my situation. The guidelines are unclear so expectations are hazy. The training given to staff dealing with passengers with mobility requirements needs to be revised. Unfortunately this is not an isolated incident and I and many have experienced poor customer service because of requesting for mobility assistance. The grey area the airports and airlines seem to be ignoring is how to handle passengers with mobility issues and dependants. How to help pregnant women if needed. Why do airlines have conflicting regulations? Which policy takes precedence? The airline or the airport?! If it’s at the discretion of airline staff whether to assist with hand baggage or not, should I simply not travel with hand baggage?! Travelling without hand baggage with a baby is an impossibility by the way…or should I hope that the air steward has woken up on the right side of bed today and isn’t offended by my stained hareem pants?! If I can’t physically put my hand luggage in the overhead locker and the staff are not obliged to assist me, what happens next?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One too many bad experiences on British Airways. The consequence of these ‘errors’, ‘oversights’ even blissful ignorance, is that it robs people of their dignity. It exposes our differences rather than celebrating our similarities. It creates fear and anxiety where just a small hand of help can change so much. Airlines and service providers need to be consistent in their approach to all that seek mobility assistance, and all that are less able or vulnerable for whatever reason. Consistent in their policy making and create confidence in our expectations. I rarely ask for help, but when I do, I really need it. Discrimination isn’t ok, it’s real, demeaning, demoralising, and whilst so many commentators on the subject have no real experience I unfortunately live it every day. When will it get better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People talk about discrimination like it’s just a hot topic, or an awkward can of worms they’d rather not consume. Debate is great, but please stop telling me about your best friends, hairdressers, neighbour who’s from Eritrea, or that cashier at Tesco’s you love with Downs Syndrome. It mocks our daily struggle and reminds me that we have come so far and yet have so much further left to go. Rather listen, be honest and sincere if you lack understanding and desire to break down barriers, and support the fight for injustice. Don’t succumb to the faux pax minefield, just let your integrity speak for itself and lets stand together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mum always said to treat others how you’d like to be treated. As simple as it sounds, we all need to try a little bit harder to engage this way and treat everyone like humans. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Freedom</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Single Moms</category>
            
                <category>Abandonment</category>
            
                <category>Mental Health</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
                <category>freedom</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Growing up without a father I always wondered what happened between my parents.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Growing up without a father I always wondered what happened between my parents. In my naivety and innocence I questioned what part I had played in my father leaving before I was 3, and what I could have done to get him to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 16 I went in search for a father who had not responded to any of my phone calls or letters. Who had never contacted me on my birthday or even when he was told I had been undergoing a series of potentially life threatening surgeries. He had stayed distant and unconcerned like someone who had left an old umbrella on the tube. I could envisage myself as one of those girls with ‘daddy issues’ and wanted to try and change ‘My Story’, I didn’t want this abandonment to define me, if that was even possible…so armed with a microphone, digital recorder and BBC Radio 4 producer I went looking for a man who wasn’t lost. His address hadn’t changed in 20 years, but in my eyes he was lost. And he had lost. I found him in Lagos, Nigeria and being the Jeremy Paxman I am asked him everything I’d ever wanted to know in concise detail. But nothing really made sense, could it ever? I’m not sure I prepared myself for less than satisfactory responses. But what could he possibly have said that would make it all ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could write a letter to my younger self, I’d tell her, you did nothing wrong. That adults sometimes make decisions that affect children negatively in response to their own emotional and physical needs. I would tell her that sometimes life happens in such a way that circumstances create a gulf that cannot be breached, and people sometimes can not find the strength, maturity or motivation to bridge that distance. That sometimes relationships don’t work, and children are collateral damage. Created with love or lust, but sometimes a painful afterthought in the transaction that is separation. Sometimes differences can’t be embraced. Sometimes destiny can’t be diverted. Sometimes people just can’t forgive and forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would tell my younger self, that parents are just human, flawed and facing the journey of life with an incomprehensible and selfish desire to be happy, at whatever cost, often with an out of date road map or a faulty sat nav. Parents do their best at the best of times and scrape through with a could do better, or simply just shouldn’t have bothered at their worst. I would tell her, you are enough. You did nothing wrong. The family he chose to raise instead of you did not win. His choice illustrates his short sightedness, his inability to responsibly find a way to love you all. His weakness, not yours, his failures not yours. And for every tear you have shed the pool of hope has grown. It’s made you stronger, more thoughtful, resilient and caring. Your story isn’t a guilty secret, it’s a beacon of hope. You have overcome adversity and shone through the fog, pursuing your dreams with courage. You can do anything you put your mind to. You can be anything you choose. Remember that those that helped create you are simple vessels and sometimes their part is fleeting and temporal. The day I found true forgiveness is the day I really became free. Free of the pain of not knowing, free of not understanding, free of the burden of unanswered questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mum found a way to raise me alone and always praised my father. She created a home that was our normal, and ensured my perception of my father was always good. She told me stories of how they met, what a good man he was and how much he loved me. Maybe that was her way of coping too. The positive reinforcements despite the reality of his absence helped me to find forgiveness. And one day in my mid 20s he turned up sick and unannounced at the Euston concourse and came to find me. Too little too late, but a gesture of love nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a child of my own, everything has changed. My mental and emotional freedom mean so much more, as I’m conscious of how my behaviour and insecurities could impact my child. I understand the flawed behaviour of parents as I see my own daily, but now even more cannot comprehend the choice to abandon a child. Finding that freedom and release of negativity in your memories is a remarkable step to healing, no matter what has caused your pain. It’s all part of your journey and everyone’s path is different. Just be open to freeing your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgiveness is personal and painful, but liberating and essential. It doesn’t mean forgetting, it just means you’ve let go….and that is awe inspiring and powerful, and uplifting, and the best gift you can give yourself. Try it….you’ve got nothing to lose and freedom to gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So whatever your situation, free yourself from the burden of holding on to pain that will only create wounds that can take a lifetime to heal. Let go of that bitterness, resentment, disappointment, regret, anger. Find somewhere to put it to rest. I hope you find peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Say Yes</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Travelling</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Marriage</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/images/feature_hu2dbd46e9711a6edef913096b4e75ada8_231367_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it. It wasn’t on my bucket list of countries to visit, I’m not a big chocolate fan and my interest in cheese is variable. But move here we did, to the beauty that is Zurich, following some research and a passion to try something new, live unapologetically and say yes more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband is like a used sales man who could sell a written off fiat punto as a limited edition collectors item. Not that I’m likening Zurich to a clapped out motor… more like high spec Range. So I was sold… changed my work contract to give me supplementary leave, sorted out all my boring admin and packed up our flat and crammed what I could in suitcases, storage and the rest just got trashed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scarily final, we arrived in a country I’d never even visited weeks after having surgery on my leg. I was still on crutches and struggled to push the pram and walk at the same time. But somehow I did. Physio at its best! We stayed in temporary accommodation for months! Small bedsit type apartments that I thought were better suited to a bachelor on a stag than a family of 3 attempting to set up home…note to self, ‘do not leave husband in charge of booking accommodation’. We applied for permanent apartments in the notoriously competitive Swiss housing market and were rejected countless times. Our housing applications read like arse kissing resumes, frustratingly detailed and intrusive, and yet still not good enough….blood anyone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After months of sleeping on broken beds, showering with flip flops on and cooking pasta in someone else’s pot above my sons travel cot, I’d had enough. Having no fixed abode was not only stressful because of the size and lack of amenities, having an active toddler rattling around in a non baby friendly apartment hitting his head on every sharp edge available was eye watering. I couldn’t register for anything as we had no fixed abode, I was in nomadic limbo. I told my husband I was going home until we found somewhere to live that had a bath I could bathe our son in, and four hobs on the stove, and a freezer…yes I am that girl….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Home is wherever you hang your hat baby’….’as long as we’re together we’ll be happy’…”save your lyrics for R Kelly, call me when we’ve got somewhere to live babe….and I love you too”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I took my son back to London, gratefully returned to our bath and four hobs, and kept on the search for somewhere permanent in Switzerland. I did viewings via Facetime whilst my husband sauntered around the empty apartments showing me the layout, pretentiously wearing a suit to portray the ‘right image’… cue eye roll. Months later we were successful and finally got a break! We signed the contract and were given the keys to our first home in Switzerland! It didn’t tick all of my boxes but compromise is a large pill that must be swallowed fast when your options are limited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a place to call home. Relieved and settled, I can now start to make connections with people and I have found my son a nursery and local activities. It’s taken us a year of blood sweat and tears, but we did it. There were times I wanted to give up. I questioned our assessment of the pros and cons and just wanted to be able to find my hair straighteners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;&#34;
    srcset=&#34;&#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switzerland is a beautiful country, designed for efficiency, and ideal for young families. It’s charm lies in exploring its breathtaking postcard landscapes and relaxed bubble of safety. The Swiss are reserved, non-confrontational and polite, and yet display an air of frost that ensures that after pleasant introductions you keep your distance. If you’re young free and single I think there are more exciting places to savour, and if you hate recycling I’d give it a wide berth! I have never spent so much time contemplating what to do with rubbish! And my cardboard folding skills are still not up to scratch. Yes they expect you to fold cardboard and tie it neatly in piles for collection on specific days….are you still awake!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expat community is large and welcoming, and embraces new comers with enthusiasm, helpful suggestions and friendly recommendations. Switzerland lives on Facebook groups and old barely functional websites. So if you’re craving taramasalata at 2am or need an acupuncturist with a clinic overlooking the lake, someone somewhere will kindly point you in the right direction! My husband enjoys his job and my son loves it here, now I just need to find my place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving here has meant I’ve not been able to work, I’ve put my career on hold to raise our family and get us settled. I’ve been fiercely independent my whole life, the concept of being a housewife despite having a role made me question my worth, and left me feeling vulnerable and itching to do something. Is that what I really want to do? Is it a means to an end? Can I raise a family and still have a thriving career? How do I balance work and childcare? Can i return to my job? The hours were long, travel commitments can be unfavourable and will I be able to afford to work and pay for childcare?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motherhood often forces you to reassess your choices, your career path and your dreams. Flexible working is no longer a buzz term, it’s something I really need to find, and make it work for me. It’s ok to want to fulfill your dreams and it’s ok to not know where to even begin. But it’s not ok to be riddled with regret and ‘what ifs’. I encourage you to join me in daring to dream, and live your life to it’s fullest potential. Live the best life for you…you are unique and beautiful for your situation. I’m looking for my passion, taking opportunities that arise and simply saying yes! Yes is where the adventure begins!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>New Beginnings</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Blogger</category>
            
                <category>Journey</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Today, I’m diving head first into my blog.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m diving head first into my blog. I’m just as clueless about the start as i am about the finish. But here I am hoping to share my journey with you and express myself creatively, prompted by change, displacement, fear, love, growth, freedom, happiness, adventure and an overwhelming feeling that this is what I’m meant to do….this is what I need to do, and for once it’s something just for me….between me and you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So who am I??! Million dollar question! I’m a work in progress, an unfinished genuine article, curry without the mango chutney, tasty but missing that je ne sais quoi. My street cred expired with my last library card, circa 1999, RIP. My son of course will think I’m the coolest thing since Tupac and Biggy, I’m working on sustaining that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am human, direct, thoughtful, sensitive but resilient. unconfident at times but opinionated, seemingly quiet but fiery. I am a contradiction personified, my background is complex but simple, I bleed red just like everyone else, and my eyes give away my thoughts every time…just the way I like it. I won’t be taking up poker anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Educated in a girls school, no interest in boys or girls for that matter until I was at university. Penises are my preference, relationships were a distant goal on my vague checklist of things I’d like to consider doing with my life. Just not that interested I guess or just busy. Tomboy extraordinaire with the scars to prove it turned princess with shin pads. Born and raised in a religious single parent home in London, my boundaries were clear and rarely contested. University catapulted me into a world I never knew existed. It was like releasing an amputated hungry dog amongst chickens. Restrained but ravenous. It gave me a taste of freedom that I had longed for, and I knew that I had to do everything within my power to maintain this light. For freedom is light. And that I did. Moved out of home a few years after returning from university and haven’t looked back since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born with a condition called scoliosis, and living with being different my whole life, I’ve learnt to celebrate my uniqueness, push through my insecurities and challenges and make sure ‘can’t’ is permanently removed from my vocabulary. There are so many things people didn’t expect of me, low expectations just fire me on to prove them all wrong. I can and will do anything I put my mind to. Nothing can stop me but me….and If I stop it’s a choice not a weakness. I’ve lived my life optimistically, hoping for the best, living for the best, seeing the best and having the best. Long may it continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been married for 3 years and have a son, and baby on the way. I currently live in Switzerland following a whirlwind romance (apparently), epic honeymoon and baptism of matrimonial fire. My husband is a diamond, he shines when I shine. He’s the epitome of a geeky Flinstone with a hint of Hackney swag. Think Sheldon with the flavour of Nottinghill Carnival. The perfect balance for me. We’ve been literally inseparable since the day we met. Nauseatingly loved up, opposite but cut from the same cloth. He brings balance to my life and loves me like no other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we Brexited and left Theresa to sort herself out and end this hockey cokey with the EU, whilst we enjoy the heidi hills and embark on an exciting adventure. It’s been a year since we took the plunge and left Saveloy for Swiss chocolate! And what a year it’s been!! A year of finding our rhythm, finding our place, finding us. An exciting and daunting mix of surprise and the unknown, celebration and grief. Perpetually lost in translation but surrounded by the safety of Swiss etiquette and morality. Moving country is not for the faint hearted. in fact moving country with a baby puts hairs on your chest. We love it here and yet occasionally miss the familiar hustle and bustle of home. Strangely it’s the food I really miss…can a girl just get an eggs benedict please….somewhere?!!! Feeling stronger, more capable, and simply grateful for life. Finding happiness on the way to where we want to be, we’re risk takers. Blessed with the passion and zest for life that motivates us to prefer trying than failing to try at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yes i currently live in beautiful Switzerland, billy not a lot of mates in the ex-pat community, all of a sudden I’m a professional turned housewife still looking for my inner Nigella to burst out. Struggling with finding a balance, still scratching my afro when filling out the occupation section of admin forms, but enjoying the beauty of the life I have with my best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the kind of girl who never really fit in, and stopped trying to a long time ago! Growing in confidence, perfecting my ability to give less of a shit what people think. Making my own rules and enjoying breaking them when needed. Setting my own standards. Creating my own manual. No idea what tomorrow holds but looking forward to you joining me, navigating it with integrity and fun. Looking for new interests, reviving old ones, cooking like a boss who really enjoys good food, with no time to make it! Window shopping online for my fashion fix, celebrating my natural curls and nervously looking forward to 3 becoming 4! Lets go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Planned Boob Strikes Are Ok</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 09:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Breastfeeding</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Baby</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/images/feature_hu9975dff1fa10e7614cba043485ce311b_267554_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Emergency ones are not! In other words, choosing not to breastfeed is ok.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Emergency ones are not! In other words, choosing not to breastfeed is ok. Being forced to stop is not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s National Breast-Feeding week!! Let’s talk food….or should I say food provision…..or should I say shame ridden, guilt provoking, nurturing, painful, stressful, bonding, life sustaining breastfeeding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be all of these things and more, it is truly a personal experience and can be so different for each individual, provoking so many conflicting and often overwhelming emotions. It’s one of the ways we can feed our babies and its benefits are promoted and preached far and wide. At a life changing, stale milk perfumed time, faced with an overwhelming amount of information, advice, advertisements, exhausted by all the physiological changes, sleep deprived and possibly still recovering from and reliving birth trauma, welcoming a new baby can seem like a crazy rollercoaster!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s the problem? Why does the subject of breastfeeding evoke so much tension, frustration, anger, disappointment, passion, loneliness, abandonment, insecurity and guilt? Why are so many women quick to defend themselves and not simply unapologetically declare their choice?! Who are they fighting against? Why are so many made to feel selfish and inadequate, why do we still not understand the true mechanics behind breast feeding? And why are we so obsessed with ‘normal’ we ignore the possibility that we each have a new normal and babies don’t just automatically fit predefined routines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a documentary on Dispatches about Breastfeeding presented by Kate Quilton. It was very informative about the benefits of breastfeeding, giving a balanced and non emotive view of the nutrients provided by both breastfeeding and formula feeding and essentially highlighting some of the reasons for the UKs decline in breastfeeding. It is now among one of the 10 countries in the world with the lowest breastfeeding rates, according to UNICEF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are libraries of information out there preaching about the various benefits and many women proudly breastfeed their babies for as long as they can. And yet &lt;strong&gt;so many feel let down by a system that promotes breastfeeding but doesn’t provide sufficient support to enable women to be successful at it.&lt;/strong&gt; Aside from medical reasons that prevent a woman from being able to breastfeed and those that choose formula as a preference, a woman who chooses to breastfeed needs support. Support from professionals, support from loved ones and support from the community.
Professionals who declare that breast is best should make it their duty to equip women with the tools, support and education women need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loved ones need to provide moral support, love, patience and non judgmental encouragement.
The community as a whole needs to change its perception on breastfeeding and stop insisting mothers should breastfeed in toilets and other unsavoury corners! Would you eat your sushi in the toilet?!
When I had my son, I had read a little about breastfeeding in one of the hundreds of prenatal leaflets given to me during pregnancy. I had seen women breastfeed but hadn’t given the reality a second thought. I attended an NCT class which bought me the best mummy friends I could ask for and during which I gained about 95% of my life’s baby knowledge crammed into a few days of eye watering, informative details. We were even introduced to a lactation specialist and given a breastfeeding hotline to call if we had any questions! Brilliant! I swiftly removed Nandos from my speed dial list and replaced it with my new breast friend! Aptly I called her the Milk Nurse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son was a natural, no latching issues thankfully, no tongue tie to contend with and literally shuffled around until he found my breast as soon as he came out of the womb! Hurray, that was quick! And scarily easy….no no no…..how wrong I was…..
I spent days and nights in pain as he fed. Reciting the words of my Milk Nurse in my head — &lt;strong&gt;‘if it hurts you’re doing something wrong’&lt;/strong&gt; I changed position, changed breast, got him to re-latch and no joy. It still hurt like someone was piercing my nipple with a hot iron. I persevered and finally got an appointment to see a midwife who showed me that he was incorrectly latched on to my breast. Oh….ok….silly me(!) Not enough areola in his gob! But by now my nipples were already raw with pain, and newborns have a relentless feeding pattern, giving your body no time to heal! So &lt;strong&gt;I slapped on the nipple cream like my life depended on it&lt;/strong&gt; and just hoped it would be ok. It got easier, and my high pain threshold combined with blind determination got me through….just. But memories of those isolating moments bring tears to my eyes and I can completely empathise with any woman who says &lt;strong&gt;‘enough is enough’&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those small hours of the morning when you’re trying to feed a hungry baby, exhausted and in pain with no one to help, advise or encourage you a decision has to be made. And &lt;strong&gt;choosing your sanity isn’t selfish&lt;/strong&gt; or weak, or pathetic, or whimsical, it’s essential to being a healthy, good mother. There isn’t enough support to ensure that women are not faced with the pressure of choosing to ‘give up’. I suspect more women would feel less bitter about the whole breastfeeding conversation if their decision was truly a choice, rather than feeling defeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those who breastfeed with ease, or who were able to establish a pattern and push through the initial discomfort, the hurdles don’t stop there. Many women are faced with a society that all too often frowns upon breastfeeding in public, judging them for publicly displaying their assets, as if their primary goal is to become the latest flasher on Clapham Common or compete with Kim Kardashian. Many of those who continue on the breast feeding path, are put off by public judgment, passive aggressive demands to ‘cover up’, disapproving eyes, insensitive requests to nurse in the toilet or sit where you can’t be seen, and quit before they are ready to. All because Mr Jones’ suppressed sexual frustrations and prudish background are confusing him with the nurture of a mother. Nothing wrong with abit of pent up frustration Mr Jones and no one scorns a private prude, but keep that archaic nonsense to yourself, and let a mama feed her baby in peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately there is no question that &lt;strong&gt;fed is best!&lt;/strong&gt; I don’t think anyone could really argue with that. The issue in my mind is that we as women want to give our children the best start in life and if health professionals say that this happens to be breast milk, most do everything within their power to make this happen. The problem is, it’s seldom that straightforward. Health concerns, low milk supply, early return to work and a barrage of other obstacles including lack of support and low confidence often mean breastfeeding just doesn’t happen for a lot of women. It’s this I wanted to really discuss, why are we so emotionally affected by someone telling us that breast is best and if for whatever reason we are unable or choose not to follow this route, we feel guilty, hostile towards those that even suggest that we are inadequate parents and vulnerable about our ability to provide for our child? Why do we care that breast is best? It’s a fact, but formula still provides a baby with nutrients that it needs for healthy development, so let’s change the narrative, stop shaming women who can’t or won’t and start supporting all mothers to grow healthy, happy babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women give themselves such a hard time about everything, and dissect every aspect of parenthood comparing notes with other parents, following advice from forums, friends and foes. Any increase in breast feeding has to be &lt;strong&gt;community inspired, community driven and community led.&lt;/strong&gt; It needs to remove the negative badge it’s adorned for too long and remodel itself in the current environment it’s supposed to serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We all need to support each other more, lean into the sisterhood, however you feed your beautiful being we’re all on the same side of knackered.&lt;/strong&gt; Shed the guilt. Empower yourself with the facts about breastfeeding. Scream for help until you’re heard without delay. Be confident in whatever feeding choice you make. And do what gives you peace and keeps you and your baby well and nourished. Fed is truly best, and all women need support no matter how they choose to feed their baby. What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Make Me a Priority</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Priorities</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Parenting Advice</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/images/feature_hu275acd3f4b5175c7aad91a0d8cf92ccb_183840_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I’m wearing sandals with ashy feet, an unironed t-shirt with a food stain or four, stretchy hareem pants and a multi coloured headscarf wrapped around sprouting doo doo plaits….</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I’m wearing sandals with ashy feet, an unironed t-shirt with a food stain or four, stretchy hareem pants and a multi coloured headscarf wrapped around sprouting doo doo plaits….and yes I left my house looking like this. Without even a second thought. Without even considering that I may be SEEN by someone who’s not partially sighted AND colourblind. And yes I still continued, offending my former self and every self confessed diva who looks upon me either with sympathy, disgust or that knowing smile from a fellow mum who’s also lost her mojo!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I literally don’t even know when this happened?! When did I stop caring what I look like, and put my sons needs before my hygiene and self appearance!?? What has happened to me?? I don’t even bother to look at myself in the mirror some days! Clothed and brushed teeth is the bar that I’ve maintained for awhile. And I’m not feeling it!!!! I caught myself in the mirror the other day, on a nursery day when I had a few hours for myself. The recent heatwave prompted me to look for a skirt that I could still shoe horn my pregnant frame in to….until I saw my legs and was high kicked in the face by chewbacca’s not so distant relative. My 20 year old self would have slapped me and told me to get reacquainted with hair removal fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m trying to find my way back to me, at the very least a groomed version! Perhaps not to the twice weekly manicures but to something that resembles the girl who would proudly sip cocktails on a roof terrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motherhood is beautiful and all consuming, and quite possibly my hardest chapter so far, but I wouldn’t change it for anything. I want to live a life I’m proud of, I want to be who I want to be and create a life I don’t always need a vacation from. I’m not on the road to martyrdom, I literally just haven’t quite worked out how to do it all and still be me. But I’m getting there. And understanding more and more that a happy me is a better me. Be good to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>