<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Motivation on Tinu Alikor</title>
        <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/motivation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Motivation on Tinu Alikor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Get Lippy 2019</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy-pout_huac9749c397c0ad2fd8521412fe21b4f3_250809_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I’m not great at following trends! I’d like to think I’m individual and try not to get swept away with fads and to be honest I’m about as ‘on trend’ as John McCririck or a stale Jaffa cake. Now I’m 35 I care less what people think, I wear what I like , rarely wear make up and generally enjoying the not giving a damn phase. Spending time with my family, sharing, loving, connecting rather than succumbing to the narcism that is gripping the world. I do however love to get dressed up when I have the opportunity and in remembrance of my party days, dancing on bars, crowd surfing (I never managed to pull that off successfully) falling into taxis, falling out of ubers and generally making magical hungover memories I’d like to master something I’ve never got the hang of. Lippy!! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy_huf55190b03eb26501b84459e754078021_220935_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never had the confidence or inclination to wear it, but recently on my journey to improving my confidence and getting involved with self care, I have admired so many who wear lippy with pride! It’s amazing how it can change your entire look and elevate you from casual to ‘oh hello’ in a few pouts! But it does take some confidence to wear it and that’s what I’m working on! Whilst I’m working on my groove, in tandem I need to find decent lippy to try and would love to see you with your favourite lippy on to give me some inspiration! So join me please and  #getlippy2019. Just post a picture of yourself with the hashtags #getlippy2019 and tell me what lippy you’ve got!! I can’t wait to see them all, share with others, the more the merrier! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#getlippy2019&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/two-happy-kids_hu8bd73f293d04bbc53f400c406222be67_1908490_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?! I remember before my daughter was born jokingly but seriously asking people with multiple kids for tips on how to cope with two kids….no one responded. At first I thought, that’s just rude really…a girl just needs some advice, and now I realise that everyone is full on blagging their way through parenthood and no one can offer any tips because some of their survival techniques are unconventional or tailor made to suit them, or they’re simply just surviving!! Whatever your ‘methods’ I salute and chest bump you with passion.  It ain’t easy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well…. I am three months into having two children, just when I thought I had got the shower routine mastered, got my hair out of doo doo plaits and ditched the stained hareem pants, I go and have another child! This new addition was never going to propel me into more self loving and uninterrupted ‘me time’. I now have even less time, am even more exhausted… if that’s even possible and actually considered sitting in my double pram whilst the toddler was at nursery, pulling the hood down and having a kip next to the baby the other day… I was that tired. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I have no real tips as such there are a few things that I wish I had known and that have helped me ‘survive’ so far. So I’m sharing in the hope that even one parent out there receives some light and love from this post, even if it is just a warm virtual bear hug reminding you, you’re not alone! We’re all just fumbling around in the dark hoping not to cause any irreparable damage! And we are essentially doing great, we just need reminding of that occasionally! Please share things that work for you too! Every little helps!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, my top ten suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a baby carrier - I never used one with my first child. I never really needed to! I had the luxury of not having to regularly multi task whilst holding my son, so although I had one only used it a handful of occasions. When you have more than one child, a baby carrier is like air! Fundamental!!! You’ll need your hands free to do stuff, tend to your other child, household stuff, whatever, but in those early stages casually sitting breastfeeding or cuddling your newborn for hours isn’t always possible. Look for your nearest sling library and try before you buy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a decent bag. Notice I didn’t say baby bag. If you find a fit for purpose baby bag that works for you then run with it, but you really need a bag that’s big enough for what you need, accessible, and can be attached or hung on your pushchair with ease. If you buy a large bag you can purchase inserts for each child to differentiate between their things, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always carry a water bottle and food (not just for the kids!) - rehydrate and feed yourself too!! Whether you’re breastfeeding or not, a fuelled mummy is a happier mummy. Water is essential especially when breastfeeding. I remember getting headaches in the first few weeks of my daughters birth when I was dehydrated. Easy resolution! Drink!! And I don’t mean cocktails! As for eating, I had a habit of just eating in between meals, eating my sons left over food and sometimes being too tired to have my own meal once the kids are sleeping. This isn’t sustainable and you need to make sure you’re looking after yourself. So batch cook if it’s easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid to ask for help. My husband and I have always done everything ourselves due to geography, which has put a strain on us both as we seldom get time out. But now we have 2 children we actively welcome opportunities to get help and in the first 2 months of my daughters life I received help with my toddler to ensure he was stimulated daily, happy and engaged. Asking for help from your loved ones is not a sign of weakness or inability to cope. It really does take a village to raise a child. Put your village on speed dial and get them involved!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do your best to schedule your kids naps as close together as possible. Nap time is sacred. My son no longer naps. I know, I cried about it too, but if he did I would be taking this on board! Try and be consistent with bedtime too. Children love routine and once they know what to expect you’ll have an easier time getting them to comply. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find distraction techniques for the older child. Have quick go-to toys and games that your child loves to keep him/her occupied if you need to attend to the younger one. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get out of the house! Yes I know it sounds like a logistical nightmare and it can be the first couple of times when you work out what works for you, and literally ‘how’ to get you all clothed and fed to leave the house! But… once you get past the chaos, it will feel like you’ve reached nirvana! The fresh air and change of scenery will do wonders for your mental health and the children will feel better too! 
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sleep when they sleep. If you manage to get both kids sleeping simultaneously….grab your duvet and get involved! The washing, cooking, laundry, phonecall, can wait!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Date night. In-between feeds, nappy changes, projectile vomit, nursery runs and reruns of paw patrol remember how it all began and make some time for the love that started it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make time for yourself at least once a week. Even if it’s just half an hour of uninterruption. Do something you enjoy! Read a book, paint your nails, have a hot bath, go to the cinema, go for a swim. Whatever floats your boat, make time for it. You will always have lots to do, the list is endless, but if you make time for the things that are important to you and make them a priority rather than a ‘nice to have’ the rest of your time will be filled with the daily responsibilities and you’ll feel better for the little moments you made time for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloglovin.com/blog/19788609/?claim=e5x9w3qxhr6&#34;&gt;Follow my blog with Bloglovin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Ten ways to improve confidence</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloglovin.com/blog/19788609/?claim=e5x9w3qxhr6&#34;&gt;Follow my blog with Bloglovin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-believe-in-yourself&#34;&gt;1. Believe in yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be your own cheerleader. Focus on the things you’re great at. Trust your own abilities. Remember the things you have achieved so far and use those memories as a foundation for the things you’d like to achieve in the future. Don’t be afraid to be heard. Your opinion is valuable and counts &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-silence-your-inner-critic&#34;&gt;2. Silence your inner critic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self deprecation needs to stop. When someone says you look great, say thank you. When someone congratulates you on a good job, again say thank you. Sometimes to silence the inner critic you need positive voices around you shouting louder! If you have no friends to reinforce Your good qualities and give you positive constructive feedback, then listen to energising talks, podcasts, videos, audio books, fill your spirit with so much positivity that the niggling inner critic will soon be drowned out… and reconsider your friendship circle! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-follow-through-with-what-you-say-you-will-do&#34;&gt;3. Follow through with what you say you will do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop procrastinating. Under promise and over deliver at first if you have to. But whatever you do, follow through. Differentiate between reasons and excuses. The more you get stuff done the more credible you will feel. It’s really as simple as that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-educate-yourself-stay-current&#34;&gt;4. Educate yourself - stay current.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge really is power and the more information you have the less you’ll feel like an imposter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-visualise-your-goals&#34;&gt;5. Visualise your goals &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create mind maps and mood boards. Someone once said to me ‘if you can see it you can have it’. Visualising your goals will make them more tangible, and on your road to a more confident you, make your vision of yourself a reality, but paint the picture first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-dress-to-impress-yourself&#34;&gt;6. Dress to impress yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason when you look good you feel good. When you put on your best you feel like you’re on the road to world domination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-monitor-your-progress&#34;&gt;7. Monitor your progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidence grows with progress, it’s really as simple as that. If you monitor your progress you can see just how far you’ve come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/joshuarunning_hu96d1b73486cb87c6c4b4666de6e6e3a0_361557_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-be-shameless-and-stay-in-your-lane&#34;&gt;8. Be shameless and stay in your lane&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think less about what people think. Most people don’t have their ish together and are just faking it until they make it. Don’t worry about what others are doing or not doing! Don’t use other people as your benchmark for success. Just be you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;9-take-risks&#34;&gt;9. Take risks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risk takers are history makers. Heard of the saying he who dares wins? Risks are not for the faint hearted but to really grow in confidence you have to do things that scare you, and in stepping out of your comfort zone, you’re winning already. It takes confidence to take risks and be bold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-do-more-of-what-makes-you-happy-and-you-re-good-at&#34;&gt;10. Do more of what makes you happy and you’re good at&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidence is reinforced by joy. Be happy and confidence will exude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, please feel free to get in touch. I’ll be posting a new blog every Monday morning. You can follow me using the links on my site. Have a great week!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Absolutely Fabulous</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 05:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/babies_hu9254ecaebb10959bdf27619441dc4657_438742_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I saw a post the other day that made me laugh…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“None of this new year new me bollocks, last year I was fabulous and next year I will be fabulous!”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very amusing, and vaguely relevant to me, I’m fabulous some days, possibly two days a week, but honestly, I think it’s BS. Maybe not a new me, but a better version of myself wouldn’t hurt, perhaps like a software update! I don’t want to put myself under any undue pressure….believe me, I’m already precariously balancing several bits of Swedish china at once, but without any pressure how do you move forward? Improvement is growth and staying fabulous takes a bit of work! I just need to find the right amount of pressure that’ll kick me out of bed to get stuff done but won’t leave me feeling like the soggy lettuce I found in my fridge this morning, if I drop the ball sometimes. I haven’t made any new years resolutions because I have genuinely been overwhelmed with ‘stuff’, to do lists, trello boards, survival lists, breastfeeding, laundry, nursery runs, cooking, cleaning, answering my 2 year olds repeated questions on underground trains and if mummy is having another baby? And did I say laundry already?! Laundry is a full time occupation in itself with a newborn and toddler! The washer and dryer are regularly abused by us, my husband is the family expert on this, I have more of a fly by the seat of your pants approach semi conscious and bundling heaves of milk and mud stained items of clothing in for saving… long live the washer and dryer….if anyone’s deliberating, separate washer and dryer gets a thumbs up from me if you have the space it’ll change your life! Middle aged confessions of a mum… No need for resolutions, just live, set goals achievable and stretching, and ambitious if you feel the urge, and be kind to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind there’s so much I want to do, but I really need to ace the basic getting the kids ready in under 2 hours and maintain my demeanour routine before I start trying to conquer the world! Or do I? I mean what am I really waiting for? Waiting for perfection before I take on something I’m passionate about sounds counterintuitive, or like a well versed delay tactic…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So….in pursuit of happiness and progress, not a tick boxing exercise or a fake fad or an overzealous binge diet, I am starting a new project! I am continuing my blog once a week channelling my thoughts and sharing my journey and soon I’ll be recording a podcast. Returning to a former passion I had the pleasure of finding in my teens with BBC Radio 4 when I recorded programmes and audio diaries. I’m looking forward to learning how to record, it feels like a natural progression from blogging, I’m in the process of researching, getting the right equipment and creating my structure and format. I have a few ideas I’m excited about and looking forward to putting it in to action. Watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may know I’ve been living in Switzerland with my husband and now two children. Housewife with the mostess… parenting like a supply teacher who should consider retiring. Finding my way through local culture, far from where I call home and the people I love, starting a new chapter in the land of cheese, orgasmic chocolate and fancy watches. The biggest change for me has been getting used to what being a housewife means. Or perhaps defining what we &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; my role to be and what we &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; my role to be, and getting it to fit with my passions and my desired direction. I’m jack of all trades, master of most. Like most parents I can’t have a day off, I don’t get sick leave. I don’t have it all together, and running seamlessly….but I do have the drive and passion that fuels my exhausted body to teach myself how to make meat pies for my 2 year old at 1am because we can’t get them out here… Yes I did that last night… so basically Beyonce is right &lt;strong&gt;we run the world!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second project this year will be something that’s close to my heart. Married to a techie, I’ve grown to love tech more and realise just how much it influences our daily lives. I’m motivated enough to function on minimal sleep and love technology, but most of all I love people and getting the best out of them. And I’ve had the pleasure of meeting awesome women out here, some who just like me followed their spouse across water, land, or just a car park to pursue a dream. Fully supporting the husbands career and building a home often means that some women are unable to fulfill their own goals and realise their own passions. Coupled with a system here that encourages women to stay at home, getting back to work after having a baby or just being a homemaking spouse can sometimes be a tall order, and even taller for us foreign folk, the expat crew. So I’m setting up a coding school called Tech Mums with childcare here in Zurich, Switzerland!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_395x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 395w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 790w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_1580x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 1580w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_2370x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 2370w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_3160x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Mums will be a place where mums can learn a new skill, invest in their career, network with like minded parents and professionals, socialise, update their skillset&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and get back to work if they choose! I had the pleasure of being a part of a similar initiative in London called Mums in Technology, and found it to be invaluable, supportive and groundbreaking. I am excited to be starting a project that inspires me to get more women in technology here in Switzerland! Lean into the sisterhood and stay fabulous…I want to inspire and be inspired. To create a welcoming, nurturing environment where mums can come and be themselves, gain a friend, gain a hobby, gain a skill and get the tools they need to kick some arse into a career they can thrive in…let’s go!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Be the change you want to see</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 06:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I gave birth to my daughter not so long ago…and my life changed. All of a sudden I feel the need to be the woman my daughter will respect and look up to. A woman of integrity and good standing. A woman she’d be proud to call her mum. I didn’t quite feel the same when I had my son. Yes, I felt the basic maternal pull of wanting to be a good role model and parent, and keep him happy and create a nurturing loving environment for him. But this awareness of my daughter, a woman in the making, in a world where we have fought for equality tirelessly and still argue over the gender pay gap and general sexism, I fear that I have brought her into a world that won’t give her the chance she deserves. But I want to teach her to take what she deserves and throw away the notion that you get what you’re given and to wait politely for your turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to equip her with the tools to make the best of every situation. To thrive even in arid conditions. To be a lover not a hater. I want her to be resilient, strong, feisty, unrepentant in truth, strong willed and vivacious. To be herself, authentic, unapologetic, fierce and loving. To see her unairbrushed, undiluted beauty. I want her to feel entitled to success, to belong if she chooses, to banish any emotions of imposition, to set her own standards, dance to her own beat and to enjoy every moment as if it were her last. I need to lead by example…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2019 is moments away…a new year, full of new opportunities, new hope, new challenges, new adventures. I’m excited, and apprehensive and eager to embark on a new chapter. I’ve been a stay at home mother for almost three years. Enjoying the fruit of nurturing the growth of my children and balancing my need for personal satisfaction with my responsibilities as a mother and wife. I’m enjoying this stage in my life and preparing for my next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going into this year putting the pains and mistakes of 2018 behind me, learning as I go. Allowing doors that need to be closed to stay firmly shut, looking forward to new doors being open. Finding new zeal and passion for progress, and making me a priority. Grateful for loyal friends whose love is without condition. Looking forward to continuing raising my children in love and peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, may you find joy, and may your dreams find you. May you be the change you want to see. May you find peace in your decisions. May you find vision helpers and people who truly have your back. May your husband replace the toilet roll occasionally, and take the rubbish out without complaining. May your boobs recover from breastfeeding and may postpartum hair loss be a myth, may you get some precious sleep without being shocked awake with a chubby finger in your nostril. May your glass of prosecco always runneth over. May you find the strength to make the changes you need and the resilience to plan without fear of failure. And mostly may you remember just how wonderful you are and have the potential to be, and simply be thankful for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t create your life first and then live it. You create it by living it not agonising over it! Whatever your situation be the best version of yourself! May this year be a year of doing, and living. Happy New Year! Be intentional…&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Dreams Don’t Expire</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 07:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/images/feature_hud963163ef20da0887dddfc3ae1a095c2_492555_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;When I was 8 if you had asked me what I want to be when I grow up my answers were as colourful as my prized Care Bear lunch box…pilot, lawyer, doctor, painter, architect, ballerina, astronaut, UN leader, journalist, news reader, butcher, baker, candlestick maker…and I truly believed I could be any one of those on any given day, and perhaps moonlight in one I was less keen on in the evenings! Cute? Ambitious much?! Or even perhaps ridiculous? Like most children I was a dreamer, with boundless priceless possibilities in my mind. Innocent desire that had no limitations. That had no concept of can’t, no glass ceilings, or iron doors, or gender pay gaps or concept of discrimination, or insecurities. Just dreams. Dreams that I loved to picture, that gave me drive, motivated me to do my homework, gave me a goal, a purpose and a passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m in my 30s I’m not sure I have space for my dreams right now. Time to dream, or the energy to pursue them. But I need to make space. Space to imagine the impossible, to conjure up paths full of adventure, of hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I the only one who’s shelved my dreams? The only one who’s decided dreaming is for kids, adults don’t dream, they get real. Life is real, and when the reality of its fabric hits you, the dreamer fairytale is squashed. What a travesty! What’s the point of living if you can’t dream? What happened to that gooey feeling when you think of all the possibilities and hopes? What happened to the energy you felt when someone asked you what you wanted to be when you grew up? Just because you didn’t make it to the Bar or aren’t a famous West End dancer, that doesn’t mean you should stop dreaming. A dream changed is not a dream lost. We can just pivot…can’t we… aim for the moon and hit the stars…aim for something…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do we stop trying to fulfil our dreams? Fear of not living up to those dreams? When did dreams get old? Maybe in adulthood we rename dreams ‘goals’? Maybe it’s easier to comprehend. When did we start trying to apply the SMART criteria to dreams? Specific, measurable, achievable, results-focused, and time- bound! Don’t confine your dreams to principles. Dreams are glorious, and big and seemingly unachievable, and uplifting and scary. We need them! They keep us alive, motivated , focused and inspired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine Charlotte Philby has just announced completion of one of her life’s dreams! A spy novel she’s been working on! What an achievement! What a feeling to have started and finished! To have accomplished and reached the peak of one of your wild imaginations! Awesome and inspiring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going back to the drawing board of dreams and writing up new ones and rehashing old post-its that have been relegated to a notebook I bought in 1991. I’m bringing back dreams! They push me out of my comfort zone. Big dreams are like big knickers, we all need them even if we don’t admit it! I’m not ashamed of my big knickers, I’m not ashamed of my dreams. One day I’ll be sharing completion of my big dreams too and celebrating even the small wins with glee! If your dreams don’t scare you they’re not big enough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share your dreams with those you love. Once you vocalise them they become tangible and possible. Dreams can change and evolve, but don’t crush your dreams or let others. Don’t give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t create your life first and then live it. You create it by living it! Not agonising over it. Try letting go of perfection today and dream! Dream because you deserve to be free to think the impossible. Because dreamers are doers. Because sometimes we’re surrounded by walls and restrictions, and dreams elevate us into a beautiful realm of possibilities. Let go of perfect and dream. I’d love to hear your dreams!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Say Yes</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/images/feature_hu2dbd46e9711a6edef913096b4e75ada8_231367_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it. It wasn’t on my bucket list of countries to visit, I’m not a big chocolate fan and my interest in cheese is variable. But move here we did, to the beauty that is Zurich, following some research and a passion to try something new, live unapologetically and say yes more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband is like a used sales man who could sell a written off fiat punto as a limited edition collectors item. Not that I’m likening Zurich to a clapped out motor… more like high spec Range. So I was sold… changed my work contract to give me supplementary leave, sorted out all my boring admin and packed up our flat and crammed what I could in suitcases, storage and the rest just got trashed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scarily final, we arrived in a country I’d never even visited weeks after having surgery on my leg. I was still on crutches and struggled to push the pram and walk at the same time. But somehow I did. Physio at its best! We stayed in temporary accommodation for months! Small bedsit type apartments that I thought were better suited to a bachelor on a stag than a family of 3 attempting to set up home…note to self, ‘do not leave husband in charge of booking accommodation’. We applied for permanent apartments in the notoriously competitive Swiss housing market and were rejected countless times. Our housing applications read like arse kissing resumes, frustratingly detailed and intrusive, and yet still not good enough….blood anyone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After months of sleeping on broken beds, showering with flip flops on and cooking pasta in someone else’s pot above my sons travel cot, I’d had enough. Having no fixed abode was not only stressful because of the size and lack of amenities, having an active toddler rattling around in a non baby friendly apartment hitting his head on every sharp edge available was eye watering. I couldn’t register for anything as we had no fixed abode, I was in nomadic limbo. I told my husband I was going home until we found somewhere to live that had a bath I could bathe our son in, and four hobs on the stove, and a freezer…yes I am that girl….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Home is wherever you hang your hat baby’….’as long as we’re together we’ll be happy’…”save your lyrics for R Kelly, call me when we’ve got somewhere to live babe….and I love you too”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I took my son back to London, gratefully returned to our bath and four hobs, and kept on the search for somewhere permanent in Switzerland. I did viewings via Facetime whilst my husband sauntered around the empty apartments showing me the layout, pretentiously wearing a suit to portray the ‘right image’… cue eye roll. Months later we were successful and finally got a break! We signed the contract and were given the keys to our first home in Switzerland! It didn’t tick all of my boxes but compromise is a large pill that must be swallowed fast when your options are limited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a place to call home. Relieved and settled, I can now start to make connections with people and I have found my son a nursery and local activities. It’s taken us a year of blood sweat and tears, but we did it. There were times I wanted to give up. I questioned our assessment of the pros and cons and just wanted to be able to find my hair straighteners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;&#34;
    srcset=&#34;&#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switzerland is a beautiful country, designed for efficiency, and ideal for young families. It’s charm lies in exploring its breathtaking postcard landscapes and relaxed bubble of safety. The Swiss are reserved, non-confrontational and polite, and yet display an air of frost that ensures that after pleasant introductions you keep your distance. If you’re young free and single I think there are more exciting places to savour, and if you hate recycling I’d give it a wide berth! I have never spent so much time contemplating what to do with rubbish! And my cardboard folding skills are still not up to scratch. Yes they expect you to fold cardboard and tie it neatly in piles for collection on specific days….are you still awake!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expat community is large and welcoming, and embraces new comers with enthusiasm, helpful suggestions and friendly recommendations. Switzerland lives on Facebook groups and old barely functional websites. So if you’re craving taramasalata at 2am or need an acupuncturist with a clinic overlooking the lake, someone somewhere will kindly point you in the right direction! My husband enjoys his job and my son loves it here, now I just need to find my place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving here has meant I’ve not been able to work, I’ve put my career on hold to raise our family and get us settled. I’ve been fiercely independent my whole life, the concept of being a housewife despite having a role made me question my worth, and left me feeling vulnerable and itching to do something. Is that what I really want to do? Is it a means to an end? Can I raise a family and still have a thriving career? How do I balance work and childcare? Can i return to my job? The hours were long, travel commitments can be unfavourable and will I be able to afford to work and pay for childcare?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motherhood often forces you to reassess your choices, your career path and your dreams. Flexible working is no longer a buzz term, it’s something I really need to find, and make it work for me. It’s ok to want to fulfill your dreams and it’s ok to not know where to even begin. But it’s not ok to be riddled with regret and ‘what ifs’. I encourage you to join me in daring to dream, and live your life to it’s fullest potential. Live the best life for you…you are unique and beautiful for your situation. I’m looking for my passion, taking opportunities that arise and simply saying yes! Yes is where the adventure begins!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>