<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Travel on Tinu Alikor</title>
        <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/travel/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Travel on Tinu Alikor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Lost in Translation</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Travel</category>
            
                <category>Family life</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Risks</category>
            
                <category>Adventure</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Living in a country where English is the secondary or even third language has its ups and downs.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Living in a country where English is the secondary or even third language has its ups and downs. We are physically immersed in a language we have little comprehension of. Thankfully, our intuition is often strong, we’re able to muddle our way through most situations., and thankfully we seem to have the seventh sense, “get your arse out of here”, or “go ask someone you pillock before you end up requesting for bail”. Today has been one of those days that highlights just how lost in translation we are here in Switzerland! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/confused_hu3a0c9e253d989f8cdf0f18383befcab8_1461885_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way to the Accident and Emergency on the only day that suits our setup! No support means illnesses need to be scheduled on appropriate days where both parents are available, so the sick parent can be relieved of duties temporarily to seek repair, heaven forbid we’re both sick at the same time, if man flu is a contender, I lose….cue eye roll…so today is apparently a national holiday here in Switzerland. Perfect for me to get myself seen by a doctor. Enroute we’re waiting at a tram stop and no trams are showing up, but the electronic display is indicating there’ll be one along in 8 minutes….10 minutes later nothing….this is so unswiss, you could almost set your clock using the transport schedule as they’re usually so punctual!! ….but there’s no sign anywhere, I’ve made that mistake before, sitting at an out of service bus stop behind a large bright orange sign in German saying out of service….so I’m not making that mistake again!! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope this time it’s different, something’s going on….but no clue what!! Intuition and a large dose of impatience means we’re never caught out for long in a situation like this, but it’s oh so frustrating when apparently there’s a demonstration which has closed off the city centre, so we need to abort our plan and find another doctor! I bet that’s what all those annoying announcements were blaring out on the way! Typical….no bloody idea! I know a little high German, and that gets me by mostly. And I’ve considered getting private lessons but Swiss German is spoken out here and you can only really learn that on the streets…and it’s nothing like high German&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/horn_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2856276_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often ask me why we moved, are we home sick, what is it like living in a different country, do we consider it home yet? My answers to these questions often vary depending on who’s asking, why, and what time of the day I’m approached, but for the most part we are adventurers. We love exploring, travelling, learning and expanding our horizons and know that the world has so much to offer if we just open our eyes, and step out of our comfort zone. Adventures are stories that we can’t predict, they’re exciting, scary, risky, fun and open doors that we never thought we had access to and in that vein create the art of the possible. Possibilities create hope, they fuel passion and ignite a zeal that no one can quench. We live by the mantra that you only live once, and you should grasp opportunities with both hands and run. Opportunities don’t always approach you, waving and beckoning, opportunities also need to be created. Create opportunities and make things happen, say yes more, and do things that excite you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adventures don’t last forever, things change, life happens, and we ride the waves and keep it moving. We all need to pause sometimes, take stock, change direction, re-evaluate where we are and where we’re trying to get to. We win some, we lose, and that’s ok. it’s ok to pause,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/lost-in-translation/images/street_hu302e1873caa1ae34f8d89cd06b315671_2326387_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set ourselves apart from the crowd by choosing courage over comfort, love over solitude. Our risks don’t always pay off, but that doesn’t matter, we keep trying, keep hustling, keep showing up. We love the thrill of the journey, the memories we create, the lessons learnt, the history created. We wouldn’t trade it for a stable paycheck or loyalty points. Stability suits most but our priority is to live, and sometimes these two components are incompatible. Our foundation is strong so a few branches pruned and splintered along the way is fine. Keep your core strong, lean into possibilities, and block out all the noise. It’s in blocking out the noise of the concrete jungle that you’ll truly begin to understand that we are all one, sometimes no need to even translate, just be. Be you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What adventures do you dream of? Made any plans? I’d love to hear from you. Please comment, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;, like and share!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Flying with babies</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/flying_with_babies/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/flying_with_babies/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Travel</category>
            
                <category>Travel tips</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/flying_with_babies/images/flight_hu2d54c1b84a3a7556dc20ca8ce0fc2933_5590305_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I’m planning my next trip to the UK…this time flying solo with my two munchkins.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I’m planning my next trip to the UK…this time flying solo with my two munchkins. If I said I’m shitting it, that would be the understatement of the year! I am absolutely dreading it, but I’ve got no choice! My husband has started a new job and I’ve got commitments to attend. I’ve not had the best flight experiences when travelling alone with my first child, so who knows what’s going to happen when I rock up to check in with another one in tow! If you see me on CNN… you know the deal…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the apprehension over the flight, and the levels of incompetence I’m about to face, I’m thinking positive vibes only, hoping that I encounter kindness and compassion. I’m excited to be going home for a few days, seeing some friends and family and eating my way through deliveroo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can pack for a flight with my eyes closed I’ve done it often enough. Here are a few of my must haves, that you can consider if you’re planning a flight with children:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You’re likely to be feeling like you’re carrying everything but the kitchen sink! Ask yourself if what you’re packing is a must have or a nice to have. Nice to haves stay at home, you’ll be grateful for having less baggage! Your carry on will be in the overhead locker during the flight. Try to pack essentials in a smaller additional bag that fits in your carry on, that you can easily grab and stow under your seat. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Give your kids their own backpack with their own items. It gives them a sense of ownership, and helps you out a little. Don’t get sucked into these cute, awkwardly shaped suitcases designed to get kids ‘excited’ about travel, but essentially end up being carried by the parent. They’re annoying, cumbersome and don’t hold much. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Change all nappies before you board. If you’re lucky and it’s a short haul flight you may never have to experience trying to change a nappy in those ridiculously sized toilets on board, barely large enough for one human, let alone a parent trying to change a nappy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bring a change of clothes for you and the baby(ies) I’ve forgotten to take a change for myself once and ended up covered in a virgin mary and baby puke. The smell was not becoming I can tell ya!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Snacks…you can never have enough snacks. Preferably ones that can be resealable and aren’t too messy, if you’re Marie Kondo in the making decant your snacks into containers for toddlers. I like to live on the edge, decanting isn’t for me… &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distractions - Stickers and a colouring in book for children aged 1 year and upwards. Variety is the spice of life. Depending on the duration of your flight, bring a few options, and don’t bring them all out at once! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yawning and swallowing activate the muscles that open your eustachian tubes and helps equalize the pressure between your ears and the airplane cabin, to avoid that blocked sensation. Depending on the age of the child - take one of those fruit pouches the child can suck on during take off and landing. Breast fed babies, stick a boob in their mouth during take off and landing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Muslins and wipes. Can any parent live without these with an under 2 year old??! Take a few and at least two packs of wipes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blanket in case it gets abit chilly on the plane. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re keen on screens make sure you’ve downloaded your kids flavour of the month to your device, and don’t forget to charge up the device and pack the charger!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A baby carrier is really useful whilst travelling through the airport, especially at security. Trying to open a pram whilst holding a baby can be challenging, a baby carrier solves this problem. It’s also really useful if you are travelling with more than one child. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take a foldable pram you can either take on the aircraft and stow in the over head lockers, or a one piece foldable pram that can be taken to the door of the aircraft. And make sure you empty your pram basket before you leave home. It’s easy to forget all those miscellaneous items we throw in the bottom of the pram on a daily basis. Finding an argos catalogue. a bucket and spade and wellies at security is not fun!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Separate your liquids in hand luggage. No doubt if you’re travelling with tots you’ll have some form of liquid. To make life a tad easier when going through security have them all in one section of your bag so you can easily pull out for examination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with everything check with your airline carrier to ensure you’re travelling with items that are acceptable in their policy. And never be afraid to ask for help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basque in the joy that you can’t lose your toddler on the flight! Comforted by the inevitable truth that no matter how tough the journey sooner or later the plane will land! Ignore tutting passengers, and try and enjoy your flight. We can do this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your tips for flights, especially with more than one child.  I need it!! Thanks for reading! Please like, share and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>We’re all equal in the sky…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Travel</category>
            
                <category>Discrimination</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Disability</category>
            
                <category>British Airways</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/feature_hu9ac72fe668a507003fd0f28db21e8729_1160980_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>So my most recent flight from Switzerland to London has taken me awhile to recover from.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;So my most recent flight from Switzerland to London has taken me awhile to recover from. I am a seasoned traveller who isn’t easily flustered. I plan my route, prepare my luggage and get going! Saying this being a black female, with mobility issues travelling with a toddler whilst pregnant puts a slightly different spin on the situation and its this I’d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m always trying to do it all, juggling, balancing plates on my head whilst spinning wheels in my palms…I’m the consummate multi tasker. Like most, you just get on without considering the extent of the task you’re embarking on. If it’s got to get done, you just do. Having a toddler who doesn’t always fit nicely into my trello board of actions and more often than not actually seems to purposely sabotage my zen goals, just makes my multi tasking all the more challenging and sometimes fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I forget to add that I have mobility issues too….?! Yep I have scoliosis and had a major op on my leg so walking long distances carrying luggage isn’t possible for me unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve got a few things making life a little more colourful it seems but I still need to get from A to B. I do everything within my power to prepare for the trip, and even requested for mobility assistance when booking my flight. On a previous journey I had been reprimanded…yes reprimanded for not requesting assistance for both myself and my son, as they sent one person to assist me and despite my booking clearly being for myself and my 2 year old son, they apparently assumed he’d manage to get himself to the gate and just meet me there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this time I was ready, I prudently booked assistance for both of us. I arrived at check in with ample time. I reminded them I had requested assistance and was told to wait in the waiting area for assistance to arrive. I waited…..and waited…..and waited…..sorry did I forget to say I have an active two year old?!? And waited….nothing….feeling a little anxious about the flight time, I went back to the desk and asked for an update and reminded them I was still waiting. I was told that the flight had been delayed and they had no idea when the plane would arrive, and that someone would let me know…..a series of ambiguous statements after waiting for almost 2 hours with a toddler….no one informed me of any changes to the flight time and rather some half an hour later, assistance arrived. She took one look at me and abruptly told me she wasn’t there to run after my baby!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now….please enlighten me…. a pregnant passenger with mobility issues travelling with her baby requests for assistance and this is the response?! I told her I had not expected anyone to ‘run after my child’ and simply needed one person to push me in the wheelchair and another to push his pram. Or be transported in one of those buggy carts. I would have happily had my son on my lap but apparently health and safety regulations do not permit this, so what other option do I have?! She said that isn’t going to happen, and I burst into tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was the hormones, maybe it was the frustration. I feel like I am constantly at war with the world. Fighting to prove that I can do it all, and sometimes I just can’t….and when I ask for help, I really need it…..and if it’s offered and then taken away with such humiliation I’m lost. That day I was lost. What do I do? I always work on the premise that you just need to learn to deal with things yourself. Lower your expectations of people and get on with what you need to do…I plan for disappointment daily. I plan for having to do it all…. but when a company pretends to offer a service that means that for once I can plan for someone to help me, and at my most vulnerable I realise that once again I’m on my own, I’m reduced to tears. I cried because had this happened two hours before I would have somehow got myself and my son to the gate. I would have walked at a pace I can manage, taken breaks if I needed to and just got on with it. But with no time to get through security and then walk to the gate I felt helpless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing they had reduced me to tears somehow they managed to get another person to push my son in the pram whilst I sobbed in the wheelchair. But it was too late. Whatever shred of dignity I had when I arrived had been reduced to the size of the wet boarding pass I held in my hand. They left me at the plane entrance, no staff helped me board the flight, a passenger kindly helped me with my hand baggage, whilst the air stewards looked on. It wasn’t heavy, but I am unable to even reach the over head lockers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On arrival at Heathrow it didn’t get much better. Again no assistance disembarking with my hand luggage and toddler. I left the plane and mobility assistance was waiting at the entrance. I told the assistant my son had a buggy that was usually brought to the plane entrance. The buggy arrived and she asked me to carry it to the mobility transportation! Carry it??! How on earth can I carry it?! I am asking for assistance and you expect me to carry a large buggy?!! I told her I can’t do that as it’s too heavy, and if she’d give me a moment I can unfold it and simply push it. To which she rolled her eyes and waited. Again no assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the transportation and I put my luggage and my son on the buggy cart, again no assistance. She began to drive and it soon became apparent that all of the lifts were surprisingly out of service! She stopped the cart and said that we had to walk. I saw several other passengers being driven in buggy carts over take us and I wondered what route they were taking and why their assistant had not demanded they walk? Surely we are all going to the exit? I was exhausted by now and asked her if she could ask one of her colleagues if there was another way she could take to avoid us having to walk. She reluctantly did so, and lo and behold there was another route!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am dumbfounded as to how @Britishairways and both Zurich and Heathrow airport handled my situation. The guidelines are unclear so expectations are hazy. The training given to staff dealing with passengers with mobility requirements needs to be revised. Unfortunately this is not an isolated incident and I and many have experienced poor customer service because of requesting for mobility assistance. The grey area the airports and airlines seem to be ignoring is how to handle passengers with mobility issues and dependants. How to help pregnant women if needed. Why do airlines have conflicting regulations? Which policy takes precedence? The airline or the airport?! If it’s at the discretion of airline staff whether to assist with hand baggage or not, should I simply not travel with hand baggage?! Travelling without hand baggage with a baby is an impossibility by the way…or should I hope that the air steward has woken up on the right side of bed today and isn’t offended by my stained hareem pants?! If I can’t physically put my hand luggage in the overhead locker and the staff are not obliged to assist me, what happens next?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One too many bad experiences on British Airways. The consequence of these ‘errors’, ‘oversights’ even blissful ignorance, is that it robs people of their dignity. It exposes our differences rather than celebrating our similarities. It creates fear and anxiety where just a small hand of help can change so much. Airlines and service providers need to be consistent in their approach to all that seek mobility assistance, and all that are less able or vulnerable for whatever reason. Consistent in their policy making and create confidence in our expectations. I rarely ask for help, but when I do, I really need it. Discrimination isn’t ok, it’s real, demeaning, demoralising, and whilst so many commentators on the subject have no real experience I unfortunately live it every day. When will it get better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People talk about discrimination like it’s just a hot topic, or an awkward can of worms they’d rather not consume. Debate is great, but please stop telling me about your best friends, hairdressers, neighbour who’s from Eritrea, or that cashier at Tesco’s you love with Downs Syndrome. It mocks our daily struggle and reminds me that we have come so far and yet have so much further left to go. Rather listen, be honest and sincere if you lack understanding and desire to break down barriers, and support the fight for injustice. Don’t succumb to the faux pax minefield, just let your integrity speak for itself and lets stand together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mum always said to treat others how you’d like to be treated. As simple as it sounds, we all need to try a little bit harder to engage this way and treat everyone like humans. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>