<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>discrimination on Tinu Alikor</title>
        <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/discrimination/</link>
        <description>Recent content in discrimination on Tinu Alikor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/discrimination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>We All Bleed Red</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/we-all-bleed-red/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/we-all-bleed-red/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>pregnancy</category>
            
                <category>discrimination</category>
            
                <category>racism</category>
            
                <category>diversity</category>
            
                <category>motherhood</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/we-all-bleed-red/images/gabriella_hu639f56b8a1e4418ee42a23d160c04111_2487295_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>They say with every cloud…there’s a silver lining.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;They say with every cloud…there’s a silver lining.  Well my grey cloud was lined with silver and gold and just kept giving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My previous blog post outlined some of the challenges I faced during my third pregnancy.  A combination of undiluted discrimination, and physiological challenges, which mainly manifested in pelvic girdle pain and a frightening unexplained extensive period of bleeding during my second trimester.  Unfortunately the treatment I received from medical professions was eye wateringly unacceptable, painful, distressing and completely unimaginable.  Covid has not only levied more pressure on the NHS and its finite resource pool, but also quietly permitted some professionals to take leave of compassion and play roulette with application of their duty of care.  As a black female I have felt mistreated, unheard and experienced a shocking level of exposed vulnerability with no recourse.  Following a lengthy letter of complaint to the hospital and still no concrete outcome or lessons learned, the one step the medical trust initiated because of their failings was to ensure I was supported by a team of midwives called the Lotus Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lotus team support Oxfordshire women and families with a variety of complex needs and provides access to one-to-one holistic midwifery care across all settings.  They aim to improve outcomes and experiences for women and their babies and are part of the maternity services’ ambition of a known midwife for all aspects of care and provides continuity whilst developing relationships with the women under their caseload.  The Lotus Team is part of a variety of measures to help provide individualised care to Oxford’s most vulnerable women as part of the national strategies to address health inequalities across maternity services and reduce neonatal and maternal mortality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the mistreatment I experienced I was essentially gifted a doula on the NHS.  And what a gift she was…
A quirky, mildly eccentric midwife full of love and compassion.  Her priority was to ensure I felt safe and this mantra was at the forefront of every decision she made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having adult children and a successful background in the corporate world, she decided to retrain and become a midwife 2 years ago.  What an inspirational and bold move.  Re-emphasisinig that its never too late to pursue your dreams and doing so may provide the piece to someone else’s puzzle they may never have been able to complete if you don’t take that step.  We met during the pandemic, so I’ll refer to her as my masked angel at times, as I don’t know what she looks like without a mask!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She asked and never assumed, she waited, she listened, she quietly observed me and got to know me even in the handful of encounters we had before my labour day.  She understood why I had been referred to her team, although we never spoke of the detail, she presented her unwavering support to me at every visit, in every phone call, through ever text message.  She slowly and unwittingly established a trusting and safe rapport with me.  She spoke with gentle confidence and encouraged me to consider my options. For the first time in years, and after 2 previous pregnancies, someone asked me what I wanted.  Someone cared that I had a preference, and they were willing to listen and consider how to make that a reality for me. I was no longer powerless or insignificant, or a mute pawn.  I was a woman with wants and needs and fears, and hopes and someone was finally listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a history of relatively quick labours and felt some anxiety at the thought of misreading the signs of labour and potentially having my baby on the hard shoulder en route to the hospital.  Because of the amazing continuity of care, my midwife knew me well enough to know when my situation had changed.  I was hesitant and unsure about labour signs and whether to call her, but knew my body had changed, and she believed me without hesitation and decisively told me to meet her at the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my birth guide was a request for a water birth if the pool was available.  My masked angel found an available room, got me comfortable and secure and told me that I would deliver my baby myself today.  I don’t think I quite digested her words or really comprehended what she was saying.  But she gave me a safe space to deliver my baby girl and told me to reach down and lift her out of the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the most beautiful and life changing experience.  I didn’t have to push, I felt relaxed and safe and as I breathed deeply, the fetal ejection reflex took over and my daughter arrived.  I could not have asked for a better experience.  Following the hurt and painful memories I held previously, what a beautiful chapter to close my birth stories.  Facilitated by support, care, love and empathy.  Every woman deserves to be heard, supported, to feel safe and for their vulnerability to be protected.  Every woman deserves the reassurance, the comfort and the care that I received, and this should not be dependent on their skin colour.  No woman ever forgets their birth story, some remember with pride and some with pain, fear and anxiety.  Whilst no one can determine how labour will unfold, there are so many ways that we can mitigate the trauma that some experience as a result of their birth stories.  This trauma often cascades affecting the family as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Channel 4 aired a documentary on Monday called “The Black Maternity Scandal” giving an insight into the mortality rates of black women during pregnancy and childbirth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What stood out most poignantly for me was the reference to the Joint Committee on Human Rights report entitled - Black people, racism and human rights. It states in the report;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the stark finding from this data that Black women are five times more likely to die in childbirth than white women the report contains no recommendation specifically aimed at reducing that disparity, although it does commit to further research on its causation. The 2018 report noted the issue but merely concluded action is needed to address these disparities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nadine Dorries, the minister for maternity, also declined to be interviewed for the programme further reinforcing the government’s disregard, lack of commitment and inability to respond to the large racist elephant in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quiet cynic in me resents the need to be advocated for, to be listened to via a lotus midwife.  Is my voice not loud enough, strong enough, relevant enough, important enough?  I shouldn’t need the representation of a white impartial midwife to be heard.  But if that’s what it takes to be heard and to survive then i’ll take that for now.  But this isn’t the answer.  We need real systemic, grass roots change.  Black women deserve to be heard, for the narrative to change, for the statistics to matter. The last consideration any woman wants to face is being confronted with her mortality and the real prospect that what began with such hope could end so painfully simply because of her race.  I’m one of the near misses, the unrecorded data that would undoubtedly send an even more alarming message about the value we place on women of colour, because I know I’m not alone. The streets unfortunately are lined with near misses, littered with stories, with trauma so many would rather forget. Those who can tell their stories despite the pain and scars, are seemingly the lucky ones…. still here, survivors. We stand for those who are too traumatised to speak and those no longer here to fight. We want answers, and we deserve change.  We are life givers, let us live ours, without fear of losing at one of the most precious times of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear from you. Please comment, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;, like and share!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Freedom Day</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>MyFreedomDay</category>
            
                <category>discrimination</category>
            
                <category>pregnancy</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>freedom</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/freedom_hu72824833961529480145661fda384d45_219928_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>If it doesn’t have Lycra in it and requires ironing, it’s dead to me.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;If it doesn’t have Lycra in it and requires ironing, it’s dead to me. I’m somewhere in between a size 12 and in denial. No idea what my style is right now. Comfortable? Functional? Clean? Or maybe just not publicly naked?! I can’t legitimately wear maternity clothing anymore….although that stretchy waistband gives me life most days! So for now I’m going with it! Baggy is totally in. Bed hair chic is back and I’m rocking it like it’s 99. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiger marks are appearing in some obscure places but I’m loving the life tattoos. These battle scars are epic and the war has been won!! Well yes I’ve won, I have two beautiful children and I fought through the sickness, the exhaustion, the aches, the doubts, the tests, the sleepless nights, the bladder with a mind of its own, the garlic aversions, the breathlessness, the mumgry moments on the London underground during rush hour, and of course… the labour. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labour… the event that’s pencilled into your diary as a definite, with no definites, no calendar invite needed, this is your party baby!  There’s no opting out of this one, no deferring, it’s the inevitable…that baby is coming to join the world by any means necessary. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t give labour much thought initially. I attended a prenatal class, watched documentaries, my husband banned me from watching as I cried over every episode and read a couple of articles. But nothing really prepared me for the day it all happened. For medical reasons I was told that I may have to have a caesarean section. No one could really explain why, just that it was ‘best’. I spent months of the pregnancy with a small hope that I may be able to give birth naturally, but content with having a C section if that was best for both me and the baby. I have nothing against c sections, it’s just that I’ve spent the majority of my life in and out of hospital, and been on the operating table more times than I care to remember. I take surgery very seriously, and if there’s a path that safely avoids that route, I’ll take that thank you very much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day I went into the emergency maternity unit as I couldn’t feel the baby moving as I had before. I was checked over and thankfully all was fine. Before I left, the doctor asked me if I had made a decision on whether or not to have a c section. I reiterated that I still didn’t quite understand why I couldn’t give birth naturally and if this was still an option I’d like to take it. The doctor told me that if I gave birth naturally I would end up having an emergency c section and that in those instances the doctors primary objective is to get the baby out quickly. According to her if in this emergency organs are damaged or arteries cut, that’s just collateral damage I’ll have to accept! Through tears of fear in that cold examination room, I signed the consent forms she shoved in front of me and agreed to have the c section. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C section day arrived… I had my bag packed and my husband and I went to the hospital to meet our baby. The consultants did their early morning rounds before the day began. The consultant introduced himself and asked me how I was and what I was there for. I laughed and said ‘I’m here to meet my baby, and you’ve booked me in for a c-section I don’t even want’. It was a teaching hospital, and surrounded by a group of students they all gawked at me. The consultant then sat on my bed and asked me what I wanted… I explained what had happened and how throughout my pregnancy no one had explained anything to me and I felt invisible, I even had to write my birth plan myself as the midwife said I didn’t need one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one knows how labour will go for anyone, and why was I any different? Unless there’s a clear medical reason that someone can actually explain to me I would rather not have surgery. The doctor smiled, and said ‘you don’t have to do anything you don’t want to do’. He told me to go home. I went home and a week later gave birth to my son naturally. Whether it was possible or not, someone believed I had the right to choose. He empowered me that morning and gave me my voice back. He gave me the freedom to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years later, pregnant again, I  faced similar attitudes and an air of disconnection that I couldn’t quite put my finger on. Last pregnancy I pretty much lived in the hospital, going in weekly for check ups towards the end and being treated like a glass shoe. This time I’ve been seen a handful of times for the mandatory scans and checks, nothing more nothing less. As I’ve given birth naturally once before there was no question as to my ability to do so this time, with the obvious disclaimer that anything can happen during labour! This time around no consultant checks, again no birth plan. Bewildered by the eerie sense of isolation I just got on with it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into labour in the middle of the night, awoken by feelings I’d had a dodgy burrito. Went back to sleep more irritated than in pain…clearly I don’t know what contractions feel like, as this apparently was the start of labour for me. I eventually gave into the discomfort and got dressed to go and get checked out at the hospital, during which the pain increased and I realised I was in labour. We got an uber to the hospital and I was literally struggling not to have the baby in the back seat of the car! We arrived at the hospital, it was quiet… just a dozing security guard who although manning the entrance to a maternity unit seemed mythed that a woman had arrived in the middle of the night in labour…cue eye roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband found a wheelchair and a nurse and I was taken in. I felt a certain sense of relief, that I was in safe hands and that they knew what they were doing, and that it would all be ok. As the pain increased and I begged for someone to help me and give me some pain relief I realised that this may not be the case. I was examined and they quickly assessed I was already 8cm dilated. I kept shouting that the baby was coming, at least give me some gas and air…they insisted on moving me to another room on a different floor! I got to the designated room and told to relax it would ok. I begged for gas and air and none came. I remember in that moment being silent and realising I was on my own. It felt like an out of body experience. I started concentrating on my breathing, focussing on slowing down and blocking out the noise of the panicked midwives. They were fumbling around trying to find the baby’s heartbeat. Amidst the confusion they finally gave me gas and air, my daughters head popped out, they all looked visibly shocked and the rest is history. No one was listening to me, I felt invisible and vulnerable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 14 is #MyFreedomDay. Every woman deserves to be heard. To have the freedom to make informed choices about their bodies, to be listened to and understood. To be given the power of autonomy over their fabric, their mind, their uterus. Freedom to decide what’s best for me and my baby. When you take away a woman’s freedom, you strip her of her dignity, you extinguish her power, you make her invisible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women often like to share labour stories. When you’ve had a child it’s almost a right of passage, a conversation that creates bonds. So many people have asked me to share my story, so many have stories that hurt to relive. Labour can be traumatic for some, life changing for all. I don’t know why my cries were ignored, or my wishes mocked, but I hear all too often of the plight of black women in labour and it makes my heart cry. If it had not been for the consultant who sat down and listened to me, my story would have been very different. We may be strong, but we deserve to be heard, everyone deserves this freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>We’re all equal in the sky…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Travel</category>
            
                <category>Discrimination</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Disability</category>
            
                <category>British Airways</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/feature_hu9ac72fe668a507003fd0f28db21e8729_1160980_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>So my most recent flight from Switzerland to London has taken me awhile to recover from.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;So my most recent flight from Switzerland to London has taken me awhile to recover from. I am a seasoned traveller who isn’t easily flustered. I plan my route, prepare my luggage and get going! Saying this being a black female, with mobility issues travelling with a toddler whilst pregnant puts a slightly different spin on the situation and its this I’d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m always trying to do it all, juggling, balancing plates on my head whilst spinning wheels in my palms…I’m the consummate multi tasker. Like most, you just get on without considering the extent of the task you’re embarking on. If it’s got to get done, you just do. Having a toddler who doesn’t always fit nicely into my trello board of actions and more often than not actually seems to purposely sabotage my zen goals, just makes my multi tasking all the more challenging and sometimes fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I forget to add that I have mobility issues too….?! Yep I have scoliosis and had a major op on my leg so walking long distances carrying luggage isn’t possible for me unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve got a few things making life a little more colourful it seems but I still need to get from A to B. I do everything within my power to prepare for the trip, and even requested for mobility assistance when booking my flight. On a previous journey I had been reprimanded…yes reprimanded for not requesting assistance for both myself and my son, as they sent one person to assist me and despite my booking clearly being for myself and my 2 year old son, they apparently assumed he’d manage to get himself to the gate and just meet me there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this time I was ready, I prudently booked assistance for both of us. I arrived at check in with ample time. I reminded them I had requested assistance and was told to wait in the waiting area for assistance to arrive. I waited…..and waited…..and waited…..sorry did I forget to say I have an active two year old?!? And waited….nothing….feeling a little anxious about the flight time, I went back to the desk and asked for an update and reminded them I was still waiting. I was told that the flight had been delayed and they had no idea when the plane would arrive, and that someone would let me know…..a series of ambiguous statements after waiting for almost 2 hours with a toddler….no one informed me of any changes to the flight time and rather some half an hour later, assistance arrived. She took one look at me and abruptly told me she wasn’t there to run after my baby!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now….please enlighten me…. a pregnant passenger with mobility issues travelling with her baby requests for assistance and this is the response?! I told her I had not expected anyone to ‘run after my child’ and simply needed one person to push me in the wheelchair and another to push his pram. Or be transported in one of those buggy carts. I would have happily had my son on my lap but apparently health and safety regulations do not permit this, so what other option do I have?! She said that isn’t going to happen, and I burst into tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was the hormones, maybe it was the frustration. I feel like I am constantly at war with the world. Fighting to prove that I can do it all, and sometimes I just can’t….and when I ask for help, I really need it…..and if it’s offered and then taken away with such humiliation I’m lost. That day I was lost. What do I do? I always work on the premise that you just need to learn to deal with things yourself. Lower your expectations of people and get on with what you need to do…I plan for disappointment daily. I plan for having to do it all…. but when a company pretends to offer a service that means that for once I can plan for someone to help me, and at my most vulnerable I realise that once again I’m on my own, I’m reduced to tears. I cried because had this happened two hours before I would have somehow got myself and my son to the gate. I would have walked at a pace I can manage, taken breaks if I needed to and just got on with it. But with no time to get through security and then walk to the gate I felt helpless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing they had reduced me to tears somehow they managed to get another person to push my son in the pram whilst I sobbed in the wheelchair. But it was too late. Whatever shred of dignity I had when I arrived had been reduced to the size of the wet boarding pass I held in my hand. They left me at the plane entrance, no staff helped me board the flight, a passenger kindly helped me with my hand baggage, whilst the air stewards looked on. It wasn’t heavy, but I am unable to even reach the over head lockers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On arrival at Heathrow it didn’t get much better. Again no assistance disembarking with my hand luggage and toddler. I left the plane and mobility assistance was waiting at the entrance. I told the assistant my son had a buggy that was usually brought to the plane entrance. The buggy arrived and she asked me to carry it to the mobility transportation! Carry it??! How on earth can I carry it?! I am asking for assistance and you expect me to carry a large buggy?!! I told her I can’t do that as it’s too heavy, and if she’d give me a moment I can unfold it and simply push it. To which she rolled her eyes and waited. Again no assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the transportation and I put my luggage and my son on the buggy cart, again no assistance. She began to drive and it soon became apparent that all of the lifts were surprisingly out of service! She stopped the cart and said that we had to walk. I saw several other passengers being driven in buggy carts over take us and I wondered what route they were taking and why their assistant had not demanded they walk? Surely we are all going to the exit? I was exhausted by now and asked her if she could ask one of her colleagues if there was another way she could take to avoid us having to walk. She reluctantly did so, and lo and behold there was another route!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am dumbfounded as to how @Britishairways and both Zurich and Heathrow airport handled my situation. The guidelines are unclear so expectations are hazy. The training given to staff dealing with passengers with mobility requirements needs to be revised. Unfortunately this is not an isolated incident and I and many have experienced poor customer service because of requesting for mobility assistance. The grey area the airports and airlines seem to be ignoring is how to handle passengers with mobility issues and dependants. How to help pregnant women if needed. Why do airlines have conflicting regulations? Which policy takes precedence? The airline or the airport?! If it’s at the discretion of airline staff whether to assist with hand baggage or not, should I simply not travel with hand baggage?! Travelling without hand baggage with a baby is an impossibility by the way…or should I hope that the air steward has woken up on the right side of bed today and isn’t offended by my stained hareem pants?! If I can’t physically put my hand luggage in the overhead locker and the staff are not obliged to assist me, what happens next?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One too many bad experiences on British Airways. The consequence of these ‘errors’, ‘oversights’ even blissful ignorance, is that it robs people of their dignity. It exposes our differences rather than celebrating our similarities. It creates fear and anxiety where just a small hand of help can change so much. Airlines and service providers need to be consistent in their approach to all that seek mobility assistance, and all that are less able or vulnerable for whatever reason. Consistent in their policy making and create confidence in our expectations. I rarely ask for help, but when I do, I really need it. Discrimination isn’t ok, it’s real, demeaning, demoralising, and whilst so many commentators on the subject have no real experience I unfortunately live it every day. When will it get better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People talk about discrimination like it’s just a hot topic, or an awkward can of worms they’d rather not consume. Debate is great, but please stop telling me about your best friends, hairdressers, neighbour who’s from Eritrea, or that cashier at Tesco’s you love with Downs Syndrome. It mocks our daily struggle and reminds me that we have come so far and yet have so much further left to go. Rather listen, be honest and sincere if you lack understanding and desire to break down barriers, and support the fight for injustice. Don’t succumb to the faux pax minefield, just let your integrity speak for itself and lets stand together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mum always said to treat others how you’d like to be treated. As simple as it sounds, we all need to try a little bit harder to engage this way and treat everyone like humans. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>