<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Life Lessons on Tinu Alikor</title>
        <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/life-lessons/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Life Lessons on Tinu Alikor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/life-lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/two-happy-kids_hu8bd73f293d04bbc53f400c406222be67_1908490_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[Now I’ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?! I remember before my daughter was born jokingly but seriously asking people with multiple kids for tips on how to cope with two kids….no one responded. At first I thought, that’s just rude really…a girl just needs some advice, and now I realise that everyone is full on blagging their way through parenthood and no one can offer any tips because some of their survival techniques are unconventional or tailor made to suit them, or they’re simply just surviving!! Whatever your ‘methods’ I salute and chest bump you with passion.  It ain’t easy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well…. I am three months into having two children, just when I thought I had got the shower routine mastered, got my hair out of doo doo plaits and ditched the stained hareem pants, I go and have another child! This new addition was never going to propel me into more self loving and uninterrupted ‘me time’. I now have even less time, am even more exhausted… if that’s even possible and actually considered sitting in my double pram whilst the toddler was at nursery, pulling the hood down and having a kip next to the baby the other day… I was that tired. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I have no real tips as such there are a few things that I wish I had known and that have helped me ‘survive’ so far. So I’m sharing in the hope that even one parent out there receives some light and love from this post, even if it is just a warm virtual bear hug reminding you, you’re not alone! We’re all just fumbling around in the dark hoping not to cause any irreparable damage! And we are essentially doing great, we just need reminding of that occasionally! Please share things that work for you too! Every little helps!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, my top ten suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a baby carrier - I never used one with my first child. I never really needed to! I had the luxury of not having to regularly multi task whilst holding my son, so although I had one only used it a handful of occasions. When you have more than one child, a baby carrier is like air! Fundamental!!! You’ll need your hands free to do stuff, tend to your other child, household stuff, whatever, but in those early stages casually sitting breastfeeding or cuddling your newborn for hours isn’t always possible. Look for your nearest sling library and try before you buy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a decent bag. Notice I didn’t say baby bag. If you find a fit for purpose baby bag that works for you then run with it, but you really need a bag that’s big enough for what you need, accessible, and can be attached or hung on your pushchair with ease. If you buy a large bag you can purchase inserts for each child to differentiate between their things, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always carry a water bottle and food (not just for the kids!) - rehydrate and feed yourself too!! Whether you’re breastfeeding or not, a fuelled mummy is a happier mummy. Water is essential especially when breastfeeding. I remember getting headaches in the first few weeks of my daughters birth when I was dehydrated. Easy resolution! Drink!! And I don’t mean cocktails! As for eating, I had a habit of just eating in between meals, eating my sons left over food and sometimes being too tired to have my own meal once the kids are sleeping. This isn’t sustainable and you need to make sure you’re looking after yourself. So batch cook if it’s easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid to ask for help. My husband and I have always done everything ourselves due to geography, which has put a strain on us both as we seldom get time out. But now we have 2 children we actively welcome opportunities to get help and in the first 2 months of my daughters life I received help with my toddler to ensure he was stimulated daily, happy and engaged. Asking for help from your loved ones is not a sign of weakness or inability to cope. It really does take a village to raise a child. Put your village on speed dial and get them involved!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do your best to schedule your kids naps as close together as possible. Nap time is sacred. My son no longer naps. I know, I cried about it too, but if he did I would be taking this on board! Try and be consistent with bedtime too. Children love routine and once they know what to expect you’ll have an easier time getting them to comply. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find distraction techniques for the older child. Have quick go-to toys and games that your child loves to keep him/her occupied if you need to attend to the younger one. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get out of the house! Yes I know it sounds like a logistical nightmare and it can be the first couple of times when you work out what works for you, and literally ‘how’ to get you all clothed and fed to leave the house! But… once you get past the chaos, it will feel like you’ve reached nirvana! The fresh air and change of scenery will do wonders for your mental health and the children will feel better too! 
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sleep when they sleep. If you manage to get both kids sleeping simultaneously….grab your duvet and get involved! The washing, cooking, laundry, phonecall, can wait!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Date night. In-between feeds, nappy changes, projectile vomit, nursery runs and reruns of paw patrol remember how it all began and make some time for the love that started it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make time for yourself at least once a week. Even if it’s just half an hour of uninterruption. Do something you enjoy! Read a book, paint your nails, have a hot bath, go to the cinema, go for a swim. Whatever floats your boat, make time for it. You will always have lots to do, the list is endless, but if you make time for the things that are important to you and make them a priority rather than a ‘nice to have’ the rest of your time will be filled with the daily responsibilities and you’ll feel better for the little moments you made time for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Absolutely Fabulous</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 05:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Podcasting</category>
            
                <category>Women In Tech</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/babies_hu9254ecaebb10959bdf27619441dc4657_438742_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[I saw a post the other day that made me laugh…]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I saw a post the other day that made me laugh…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“None of this new year new me bollocks, last year I was fabulous and next year I will be fabulous!”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very amusing, and vaguely relevant to me, I’m fabulous some days, possibly two days a week, but honestly, I think it’s BS. Maybe not a new me, but a better version of myself wouldn’t hurt, perhaps like a software update! I don’t want to put myself under any undue pressure….believe me, I’m already precariously balancing several bits of Swedish china at once, but without any pressure how do you move forward? Improvement is growth and staying fabulous takes a bit of work! I just need to find the right amount of pressure that’ll kick me out of bed to get stuff done but won’t leave me feeling like the soggy lettuce I found in my fridge this morning, if I drop the ball sometimes. I haven’t made any new years resolutions because I have genuinely been overwhelmed with ‘stuff’, to do lists, trello boards, survival lists, breastfeeding, laundry, nursery runs, cooking, cleaning, answering my 2 year olds repeated questions on underground trains and if mummy is having another baby? And did I say laundry already?! Laundry is a full time occupation in itself with a newborn and toddler! The washer and dryer are regularly abused by us, my husband is the family expert on this, I have more of a fly by the seat of your pants approach semi conscious and bundling heaves of milk and mud stained items of clothing in for saving… long live the washer and dryer….if anyone’s deliberating, separate washer and dryer gets a thumbs up from me if you have the space it’ll change your life! Middle aged confessions of a mum… No need for resolutions, just live, set goals achievable and stretching, and ambitious if you feel the urge, and be kind to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind there’s so much I want to do, but I really need to ace the basic getting the kids ready in under 2 hours and maintain my demeanour routine before I start trying to conquer the world! Or do I? I mean what am I really waiting for? Waiting for perfection before I take on something I’m passionate about sounds counterintuitive, or like a well versed delay tactic…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So….in pursuit of happiness and progress, not a tick boxing exercise or a fake fad or an overzealous binge diet, I am starting a new project! I am continuing my blog once a week channelling my thoughts and sharing my journey and soon I’ll be recording a podcast. Returning to a former passion I had the pleasure of finding in my teens with BBC Radio 4 when I recorded programmes and audio diaries. I’m looking forward to learning how to record, it feels like a natural progression from blogging, I’m in the process of researching, getting the right equipment and creating my structure and format. I have a few ideas I’m excited about and looking forward to putting it in to action. Watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may know I’ve been living in Switzerland with my husband and now two children. Housewife with the mostess… parenting like a supply teacher who should consider retiring. Finding my way through local culture, far from where I call home and the people I love, starting a new chapter in the land of cheese, orgasmic chocolate and fancy watches. The biggest change for me has been getting used to what being a housewife means. Or perhaps defining what we &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; my role to be and what we &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; my role to be, and getting it to fit with my passions and my desired direction. I’m jack of all trades, master of most. Like most parents I can’t have a day off, I don’t get sick leave. I don’t have it all together, and running seamlessly….but I do have the drive and passion that fuels my exhausted body to teach myself how to make meat pies for my 2 year old at 1am because we can’t get them out here… Yes I did that last night… so basically Beyonce is right &lt;strong&gt;we run the world!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second project this year will be something that’s close to my heart. Married to a techie, I’ve grown to love tech more and realise just how much it influences our daily lives. I’m motivated enough to function on minimal sleep and love technology, but most of all I love people and getting the best out of them. And I’ve had the pleasure of meeting awesome women out here, some who just like me followed their spouse across water, land, or just a car park to pursue a dream. Fully supporting the husbands career and building a home often means that some women are unable to fulfill their own goals and realise their own passions. Coupled with a system here that encourages women to stay at home, getting back to work after having a baby or just being a homemaking spouse can sometimes be a tall order, and even taller for us foreign folk, the expat crew. So I’m setting up a coding school called Tech Mums with childcare here in Zurich, Switzerland!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_395x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 395w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 790w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_1580x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 1580w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_2370x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 2370w,
          /blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/josh_hu24b54a7992b206655459fac9c5647387_2423831_3160x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Mums will be a place where mums can learn a new skill, invest in their career, network with like minded parents and professionals, socialise, update their skillset&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and get back to work if they choose! I had the pleasure of being a part of a similar initiative in London called Mums in Technology, and found it to be invaluable, supportive and groundbreaking. I am excited to be starting a project that inspires me to get more women in technology here in Switzerland! Lean into the sisterhood and stay fabulous…I want to inspire and be inspired. To create a welcoming, nurturing environment where mums can come and be themselves, gain a friend, gain a hobby, gain a skill and get the tools they need to kick some arse into a career they can thrive in…let’s go!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Fail Like a Boss</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Failure</category>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Fear Of Failure</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/images/feature_hu922ba9b63a8233a3c6308bd992b0acb5_4597736_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School.]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School. Apparently he has passed his probationary period! Yay!! ! But a probationary period….so he can pass or fail? Eurgh…please tell me they’re not starting this already! He’s 2!!! He can’t fail!! Surely?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then began questioning myself and why I took issue with the suggestion of a probationary period and the thought that my child may be rejected. ‘Rejection’ is so emotive! Are we so sensitive that the thought of being measured or challenged makes us inherently uncomfortable? Is failing at something a conclusive label? What’s wrong with failing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son may not be best suited to a particular environment or activity depending on his disposition, but fail…? No no no….I’m a great believer in exposing children to as many new experiences as you can and letting them decide what they enjoy, or have an affinity for. I don’t want to be pushy or overbearing, just trying to find a balance between being encouraging and of course being protective and having his best interests at heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many of us pre-empt what we think our children can handle, we allow our own characteristics to define our children’s potential. We often label them, and spend their formative years projecting ourselves on their blank canvases, before they can even pronounce the word ‘fail’. In trying to protect them we confine them to our own limitations. Sometimes we confuse genuine care with control and fear. Finding the right balance is not easy…like most aspects of parenting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not big on wildlife and nature. I’m in awe of the beauty of the world and intrigued by animals…and have had the pleasure of experiencing some truly breathtaking sights all over the world. But whilst I love an adventure, and have been known to get stuck into spontaneous excursions, white water rafting, zip lining and (indoor) skydiving, I’m Nigerian, my mum would slap me if I voluntarily threw myself out of a plane. But I’m more comfortable reclining in an air conditioned vehicle observing the various spectacles than being knee deep in dirt swatting away creatures that quite possibly could send me into a panicked state of hyperventilation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So roughing it in campsites, sharing a bathroom and using toilet facilities that involve holes in the ground are just not my thing. But of course I don’t want to inflict my princess ways on my child. He’ll learn some grit from me, but not the kind that’s suitable for any bush tucker trial. So I’m trying my best to put my own sensibilities aside and allow my son to learn and grow, and experience the world through his own lens. And that’s what parenting is all about. Trying not to screw your child over with the sometimes messed up issues you may have whilst keeping them alive and happy! Tall order!
Have you ever been so afraid at failing at something you decided not to try at all? Is the fear of failure so strong that it surpasses the fear of regret or stagnation? I’m not sure why we’re so fearful of failing, personally I’d rather fail quickly and move on than paralyse myself into not trying at all. I guess I have more of a fear of regret than a fear of failure. Failing is ok, it means you had the guts to try and that in itself deserves a pat on the back. Failure should be followed by a personal debrief, what went wrong? How can you avoid it in the future? It’s ok to fail, but failing to try is a waste of your potential. And you have potential!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m altering my perspective and promoting failure, as it is in the trying that we truly become great. I want my son to grasp opportunities with both hands and I’ll try my best to stand behind him and cushion if his falls. Falling is ok, as long as you get up again. And it doesn’t matter how many times you fail, keep rising, and don’t stop trying.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Love yourself</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Self Love</category>
            
                <category>Self Healing</category>
            
                <category>Bullying</category>
            
                <category>Positivity</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/images/feature_hu8bc1fff2af24458dba8e5250014f41bc_145314_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[This blog is for everyone who contacted me in private or public about one of my previous blogs ‘ Freedom’.]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;This blog is for everyone who contacted me in private or public about one of my previous blogs ‘ Freedom’. I was brought to tears by you reaching out to share your stories with me. I’m touched by the strength in your daily struggles and the memories that you hold on to. I’m inspired by you. Thank you for reaching out, thank you for sharing. Vulnerability is not weakness, it’s powerful. Freedom in your mind and thoughts, freedom in your choices, freedom in your movements, freedom in your memories, that’s what I strive for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever you choose to do, please don’t suffer in silence. So many people are hurting in isolation. Facing mountains they cannot climb alone. Confronting battles they don’t know how to navigate. Someone somewhere can help. Talk, be heard, share… nothing is insurmountable and although it may seem like it sometimes, you are not alone. Sometimes you just need to reach out, cry, scream, whisper…just be heard. You deserve to be heard, valued and appreciated.You’re stronger than you give yourself credit for, but you don’t need to carry the weight alone. A problem shared is truly a problem halved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the unfortunate experience of being bullied for just over a year some time ago. I let someone make me believe I was inferior, worthless and incapable, and once a voice is prominent enough, allowed enough volume, and persistent it becomes the only noise you hear. Abuse can come in so many forms…all are unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emotional abuse is like an undetected gas leak. You often don’t see it coming or realise when it’s escalating. It’s difficult to even quantify its impact but the trail of destruction is undeniable. When I think back to those dark days when I didn’t want to get out of bed or eat…when the smallest feat seemed impossible, when I almost took a woman out for pushing me on the Northern Line, and cried when I dropped a bag of percy pigs, I genuinely thought I was losing the plot. I remember someone telling me how much I had changed and asking me what had happened to the Tinu he used to know? I had no idea? What had happened? Where had she gone?? Had she left the building? Had I really changed so much? I hadn’t noticed….but one day through a blur of mascara I turned off auto pilot. I decided to actually look at myself in the mirror. It felt like I was staring for hours, I just didn’t recognise myself. I was a hollow resemblance of the confident girl who interviewed Tony Blair in her teens, and gave Ann Widdecombe a run for her money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had allowed someone to impose their own self hatred on me. I believed her. I don’t know why my self esteem was so low but it was, and the consequence was years of self doubt, low confidence and an impenetrable imposter syndrome. I’m in recovery now, I removed myself from the situation and have started some serious kumbaya sessions listening to kick arse Ted talks and getting my mojo back. I didn’t see it coming, and I didn’t recognise just how bad it was as I was actively avoiding every reflective surface and hiding in my own shadow. That’s how I believe the bullying went from a few snarly throw away comments to a barrage of painful, insensitive relentless attacks. I stopped looking in the mirror. I was ashamed of what I had become, and in running away from it I was only making matters worse. Bullies thrive on victim isolation…don’t be a victim and please look at the beauty you see in the mirror before you don’t recognise the person staring back at you. Love yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep coming across these new social media phrases, ‘self love’, ‘living my best life’ and ‘self care’ essentially they all mean the same thing…be good to yourself, but what does it mean to you? Everyday I’m choosing to love me. I’m doing something ‘selfish’ that makes me happy and makes me a priority. Today I painted my nails, yesterday I bought a bottle of root beer and didn’t share it! And I loved it….so rock and roll! Whatever your situation is, the daily choices you make paint your life’s canvas. I constantly remind myself of the advice given on aeroplanes…put your own oxygen mask on first. You can’t help anyone if you cut off your own supply. So I encourage you to do abit of self hugging and loving today. Make a point of doing something for yourself everyday, no matter how small or seemingly insignificant, and take time to look at you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling trapped and stagnant is a painful position to find yourself in. Claustrophobic, suffocated, helpless, directionless. But there’s a light at the end of every tunnel. And you can create that light…don’t wait for someone to hand you a torch. A well known proverb describes hope perfectly, “Just when the caterpillar thought the world was ending, it turned into a butterfly.” Hope is an expectation, and my hope for you is that you harness the strength within you to move forward. That you see your glass half full and change your perception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scars are the best tattoos. They represent battles fought and won. They tell a story, your story. Stop hiding your scars and show them with pride. You are winning. Every night my son and I pray and go through positive affirmations. If you ask him, he’ll say he’s a winner…and that he’s always on top. If a two year old can do it, so can you! You are a winner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you can’t fly then run, if you can’t run then walk, if you can’t walk then crawl, but whatever you do you have to keep moving forward.” ― Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Freedom</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Single Moms</category>
            
                <category>Abandonment</category>
            
                <category>Mental Health</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
                <category>freedom</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[Growing up without a father I always wondered what happened between my parents.]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Growing up without a father I always wondered what happened between my parents. In my naivety and innocence I questioned what part I had played in my father leaving before I was 3, and what I could have done to get him to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 16 I went in search for a father who had not responded to any of my phone calls or letters. Who had never contacted me on my birthday or even when he was told I had been undergoing a series of potentially life threatening surgeries. He had stayed distant and unconcerned like someone who had left an old umbrella on the tube. I could envisage myself as one of those girls with ‘daddy issues’ and wanted to try and change ‘My Story’, I didn’t want this abandonment to define me, if that was even possible…so armed with a microphone, digital recorder and BBC Radio 4 producer I went looking for a man who wasn’t lost. His address hadn’t changed in 20 years, but in my eyes he was lost. And he had lost. I found him in Lagos, Nigeria and being the Jeremy Paxman I am asked him everything I’d ever wanted to know in concise detail. But nothing really made sense, could it ever? I’m not sure I prepared myself for less than satisfactory responses. But what could he possibly have said that would make it all ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could write a letter to my younger self, I’d tell her, you did nothing wrong. That adults sometimes make decisions that affect children negatively in response to their own emotional and physical needs. I would tell her that sometimes life happens in such a way that circumstances create a gulf that cannot be breached, and people sometimes can not find the strength, maturity or motivation to bridge that distance. That sometimes relationships don’t work, and children are collateral damage. Created with love or lust, but sometimes a painful afterthought in the transaction that is separation. Sometimes differences can’t be embraced. Sometimes destiny can’t be diverted. Sometimes people just can’t forgive and forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would tell my younger self, that parents are just human, flawed and facing the journey of life with an incomprehensible and selfish desire to be happy, at whatever cost, often with an out of date road map or a faulty sat nav. Parents do their best at the best of times and scrape through with a could do better, or simply just shouldn’t have bothered at their worst. I would tell her, you are enough. You did nothing wrong. The family he chose to raise instead of you did not win. His choice illustrates his short sightedness, his inability to responsibly find a way to love you all. His weakness, not yours, his failures not yours. And for every tear you have shed the pool of hope has grown. It’s made you stronger, more thoughtful, resilient and caring. Your story isn’t a guilty secret, it’s a beacon of hope. You have overcome adversity and shone through the fog, pursuing your dreams with courage. You can do anything you put your mind to. You can be anything you choose. Remember that those that helped create you are simple vessels and sometimes their part is fleeting and temporal. The day I found true forgiveness is the day I really became free. Free of the pain of not knowing, free of not understanding, free of the burden of unanswered questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mum found a way to raise me alone and always praised my father. She created a home that was our normal, and ensured my perception of my father was always good. She told me stories of how they met, what a good man he was and how much he loved me. Maybe that was her way of coping too. The positive reinforcements despite the reality of his absence helped me to find forgiveness. And one day in my mid 20s he turned up sick and unannounced at the Euston concourse and came to find me. Too little too late, but a gesture of love nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a child of my own, everything has changed. My mental and emotional freedom mean so much more, as I’m conscious of how my behaviour and insecurities could impact my child. I understand the flawed behaviour of parents as I see my own daily, but now even more cannot comprehend the choice to abandon a child. Finding that freedom and release of negativity in your memories is a remarkable step to healing, no matter what has caused your pain. It’s all part of your journey and everyone’s path is different. Just be open to freeing your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgiveness is personal and painful, but liberating and essential. It doesn’t mean forgetting, it just means you’ve let go….and that is awe inspiring and powerful, and uplifting, and the best gift you can give yourself. Try it….you’ve got nothing to lose and freedom to gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So whatever your situation, free yourself from the burden of holding on to pain that will only create wounds that can take a lifetime to heal. Let go of that bitterness, resentment, disappointment, regret, anger. Find somewhere to put it to rest. I hope you find peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Say Yes</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Travelling</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Marriage</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/images/feature_hu2dbd46e9711a6edef913096b4e75ada8_231367_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago.]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it. It wasn’t on my bucket list of countries to visit, I’m not a big chocolate fan and my interest in cheese is variable. But move here we did, to the beauty that is Zurich, following some research and a passion to try something new, live unapologetically and say yes more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband is like a used sales man who could sell a written off fiat punto as a limited edition collectors item. Not that I’m likening Zurich to a clapped out motor… more like high spec Range. So I was sold… changed my work contract to give me supplementary leave, sorted out all my boring admin and packed up our flat and crammed what I could in suitcases, storage and the rest just got trashed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scarily final, we arrived in a country I’d never even visited weeks after having surgery on my leg. I was still on crutches and struggled to push the pram and walk at the same time. But somehow I did. Physio at its best! We stayed in temporary accommodation for months! Small bedsit type apartments that I thought were better suited to a bachelor on a stag than a family of 3 attempting to set up home…note to self, ‘do not leave husband in charge of booking accommodation’. We applied for permanent apartments in the notoriously competitive Swiss housing market and were rejected countless times. Our housing applications read like arse kissing resumes, frustratingly detailed and intrusive, and yet still not good enough….blood anyone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After months of sleeping on broken beds, showering with flip flops on and cooking pasta in someone else’s pot above my sons travel cot, I’d had enough. Having no fixed abode was not only stressful because of the size and lack of amenities, having an active toddler rattling around in a non baby friendly apartment hitting his head on every sharp edge available was eye watering. I couldn’t register for anything as we had no fixed abode, I was in nomadic limbo. I told my husband I was going home until we found somewhere to live that had a bath I could bathe our son in, and four hobs on the stove, and a freezer…yes I am that girl….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Home is wherever you hang your hat baby’….’as long as we’re together we’ll be happy’…”save your lyrics for R Kelly, call me when we’ve got somewhere to live babe….and I love you too”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I took my son back to London, gratefully returned to our bath and four hobs, and kept on the search for somewhere permanent in Switzerland. I did viewings via Facetime whilst my husband sauntered around the empty apartments showing me the layout, pretentiously wearing a suit to portray the ‘right image’… cue eye roll. Months later we were successful and finally got a break! We signed the contract and were given the keys to our first home in Switzerland! It didn’t tick all of my boxes but compromise is a large pill that must be swallowed fast when your options are limited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a place to call home. Relieved and settled, I can now start to make connections with people and I have found my son a nursery and local activities. It’s taken us a year of blood sweat and tears, but we did it. There were times I wanted to give up. I questioned our assessment of the pros and cons and just wanted to be able to find my hair straighteners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;&#34;
    srcset=&#34;&#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switzerland is a beautiful country, designed for efficiency, and ideal for young families. It’s charm lies in exploring its breathtaking postcard landscapes and relaxed bubble of safety. The Swiss are reserved, non-confrontational and polite, and yet display an air of frost that ensures that after pleasant introductions you keep your distance. If you’re young free and single I think there are more exciting places to savour, and if you hate recycling I’d give it a wide berth! I have never spent so much time contemplating what to do with rubbish! And my cardboard folding skills are still not up to scratch. Yes they expect you to fold cardboard and tie it neatly in piles for collection on specific days….are you still awake!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expat community is large and welcoming, and embraces new comers with enthusiasm, helpful suggestions and friendly recommendations. Switzerland lives on Facebook groups and old barely functional websites. So if you’re craving taramasalata at 2am or need an acupuncturist with a clinic overlooking the lake, someone somewhere will kindly point you in the right direction! My husband enjoys his job and my son loves it here, now I just need to find my place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving here has meant I’ve not been able to work, I’ve put my career on hold to raise our family and get us settled. I’ve been fiercely independent my whole life, the concept of being a housewife despite having a role made me question my worth, and left me feeling vulnerable and itching to do something. Is that what I really want to do? Is it a means to an end? Can I raise a family and still have a thriving career? How do I balance work and childcare? Can i return to my job? The hours were long, travel commitments can be unfavourable and will I be able to afford to work and pay for childcare?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motherhood often forces you to reassess your choices, your career path and your dreams. Flexible working is no longer a buzz term, it’s something I really need to find, and make it work for me. It’s ok to want to fulfill your dreams and it’s ok to not know where to even begin. But it’s not ok to be riddled with regret and ‘what ifs’. I encourage you to join me in daring to dream, and live your life to it’s fullest potential. Live the best life for you…you are unique and beautiful for your situation. I’m looking for my passion, taking opportunities that arise and simply saying yes! Yes is where the adventure begins!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>New Beginnings</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Blogger</category>
            
                <category>Journey</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[Today, I’m diving head first into my blog.]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m diving head first into my blog. I’m just as clueless about the start as i am about the finish. But here I am hoping to share my journey with you and express myself creatively, prompted by change, displacement, fear, love, growth, freedom, happiness, adventure and an overwhelming feeling that this is what I’m meant to do….this is what I need to do, and for once it’s something just for me….between me and you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So who am I??! Million dollar question! I’m a work in progress, an unfinished genuine article, curry without the mango chutney, tasty but missing that je ne sais quoi. My street cred expired with my last library card, circa 1999, RIP. My son of course will think I’m the coolest thing since Tupac and Biggy, I’m working on sustaining that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am human, direct, thoughtful, sensitive but resilient. unconfident at times but opinionated, seemingly quiet but fiery. I am a contradiction personified, my background is complex but simple, I bleed red just like everyone else, and my eyes give away my thoughts every time…just the way I like it. I won’t be taking up poker anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Educated in a girls school, no interest in boys or girls for that matter until I was at university. Penises are my preference, relationships were a distant goal on my vague checklist of things I’d like to consider doing with my life. Just not that interested I guess or just busy. Tomboy extraordinaire with the scars to prove it turned princess with shin pads. Born and raised in a religious single parent home in London, my boundaries were clear and rarely contested. University catapulted me into a world I never knew existed. It was like releasing an amputated hungry dog amongst chickens. Restrained but ravenous. It gave me a taste of freedom that I had longed for, and I knew that I had to do everything within my power to maintain this light. For freedom is light. And that I did. Moved out of home a few years after returning from university and haven’t looked back since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born with a condition called scoliosis, and living with being different my whole life, I’ve learnt to celebrate my uniqueness, push through my insecurities and challenges and make sure ‘can’t’ is permanently removed from my vocabulary. There are so many things people didn’t expect of me, low expectations just fire me on to prove them all wrong. I can and will do anything I put my mind to. Nothing can stop me but me….and If I stop it’s a choice not a weakness. I’ve lived my life optimistically, hoping for the best, living for the best, seeing the best and having the best. Long may it continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been married for 3 years and have a son, and baby on the way. I currently live in Switzerland following a whirlwind romance (apparently), epic honeymoon and baptism of matrimonial fire. My husband is a diamond, he shines when I shine. He’s the epitome of a geeky Flinstone with a hint of Hackney swag. Think Sheldon with the flavour of Nottinghill Carnival. The perfect balance for me. We’ve been literally inseparable since the day we met. Nauseatingly loved up, opposite but cut from the same cloth. He brings balance to my life and loves me like no other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we Brexited and left Theresa to sort herself out and end this hockey cokey with the EU, whilst we enjoy the heidi hills and embark on an exciting adventure. It’s been a year since we took the plunge and left Saveloy for Swiss chocolate! And what a year it’s been!! A year of finding our rhythm, finding our place, finding us. An exciting and daunting mix of surprise and the unknown, celebration and grief. Perpetually lost in translation but surrounded by the safety of Swiss etiquette and morality. Moving country is not for the faint hearted. in fact moving country with a baby puts hairs on your chest. We love it here and yet occasionally miss the familiar hustle and bustle of home. Strangely it’s the food I really miss…can a girl just get an eggs benedict please….somewhere?!!! Feeling stronger, more capable, and simply grateful for life. Finding happiness on the way to where we want to be, we’re risk takers. Blessed with the passion and zest for life that motivates us to prefer trying than failing to try at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yes i currently live in beautiful Switzerland, billy not a lot of mates in the ex-pat community, all of a sudden I’m a professional turned housewife still looking for my inner Nigella to burst out. Struggling with finding a balance, still scratching my afro when filling out the occupation section of admin forms, but enjoying the beauty of the life I have with my best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the kind of girl who never really fit in, and stopped trying to a long time ago! Growing in confidence, perfecting my ability to give less of a shit what people think. Making my own rules and enjoying breaking them when needed. Setting my own standards. Creating my own manual. No idea what tomorrow holds but looking forward to you joining me, navigating it with integrity and fun. Looking for new interests, reviving old ones, cooking like a boss who really enjoys good food, with no time to make it! Window shopping online for my fashion fix, celebrating my natural curls and nervously looking forward to 3 becoming 4! Lets go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>