<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life Lessons on Tinu Alikor</title>
    <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/tags/life-lessons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life Lessons on Tinu Alikor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 05:53:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tinualikor.co.uk/tags/life-lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolutely Fabulous</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 05:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</guid>
      <description>I saw a post the other day that made me laugh…
“None of this new year new me bollocks, last year I was fabulous and next year I will be fabulous!”
Very amusing, and vaguely relevant to me, I’m fabulous some days, possibly two days a week, but honestly, I think it’s BS. Maybe not a new me, but a better version of myself wouldn’t hurt, perhaps like a software update!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail Like a Boss</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</guid>
      <description>I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School. Apparently he has passed his probationary period! Yay!! ! But a probationary period….so he can pass or fail? Eurgh…please tell me they’re not starting this already! He’s 2!!! He can’t fail!! Surely?
I then began questioning myself and why I took issue with the suggestion of a probationary period and the thought that my child may be rejected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love yourself</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/love-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/love-yourself/</guid>
      <description>This blog is for everyone who contacted me in private or public about one of my previous blogs ‘ Freedom’. I was brought to tears by you reaching out to share your stories with me. I’m touched by the strength in your daily struggles and the memories that you hold on to. I’m inspired by you. Thank you for reaching out, thank you for sharing. Vulnerability is not weakness, it’s powerful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/freedom/</guid>
      <description>Growing up without a father I always wondered what happened between my parents. In my naivety and innocence I questioned what part I had played in my father leaving before I was 3, and what I could have done to get him to stay.
 At 16 I went in search for a father who had not responded to any of my phone calls or letters. Who had never contacted me on my birthday or even when he was told I had been undergoing a series of potentially life threatening surgeries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say Yes</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/say-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/say-yes/</guid>
      <description>We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/new-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Today, I’m diving head first into my blog. I’m just as clueless about the start as i am about the finish. But here I am hoping to share my journey with you and express myself creatively, prompted by change, displacement, fear, love, growth, freedom, happiness, adventure and an overwhelming feeling that this is what I’m meant to do….this is what I need to do, and for once it’s something just for me….</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>