<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Individuality on Tinu Alikor</title>
    <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/tags/individuality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Individuality on Tinu Alikor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 07:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tinualikor.co.uk/tags/individuality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroin, carbs and a stable pay cheque</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</guid>
      <description>“The three biggest addictions are heroin, carbs, and a stable pay cheque” according to Nassim Taleb.
I’m inclined to believe him! I’m presently trying to get a grip of two of these addictions…Thankfully I have never battled with heroin, the closest I’ve got to substance abuse has been a tea addiction! I didn’t even realise I was addicted until I decided to give it up for Lent….and the hulk appeared every morning instead of the amenable me….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Sonshine</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/my-sonshine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.co.uk/blog/my-sonshine/</guid>
      <description>This one. This brilliant, energetic, bold, adventurous, talkative, loving, mischievous boy with endless curiosity is my biggest test. He’s the child you’ll find in the sandpit after a huge downfall of rain playing snow angels in the mud. He’s the one that could find puddles in the desert and could give a puma a run for its money. The one you’ll find moving furniture to scale the table, or pulling the blender out of the cupboard to see how it works, or trying to hang from the window ledge so he can see the bus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>