<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Selflove on Tinu Alikor</title>
        <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/selflove/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Selflove on Tinu Alikor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/selflove/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>It’s a Wrap</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-a-wrap/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-a-wrap/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Pandemic</category>
            
                <category>Selflove</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Parenthood</category>
            
                <category>Financial freedom</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-a-wrap/images/bumpstraw_hu49c03114a9ce8ad2bc0bd62c0ddb3f2a_5620154_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>2020 you’ve been educational! Like that aunty at a party you don’t know if you’re going to get a slap or a hug, I’ve been dealt with both in what feels like equal measure.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-a-wrap/images/bumpstraw_hu49c03114a9ce8ad2bc0bd62c0ddb3f2a_5620154_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/its-a-wrap/images/bumpstraw_hu49c03114a9ce8ad2bc0bd62c0ddb3f2a_5620154_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/its-a-wrap/images/bumpstraw_hu49c03114a9ce8ad2bc0bd62c0ddb3f2a_5620154_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/its-a-wrap/images/bumpstraw_hu49c03114a9ce8ad2bc0bd62c0ddb3f2a_5620154_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/its-a-wrap/images/bumpstraw_hu49c03114a9ce8ad2bc0bd62c0ddb3f2a_5620154_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/its-a-wrap/images/bumpstraw_hu49c03114a9ce8ad2bc0bd62c0ddb3f2a_5620154_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 you’ve been educational! Like that aunty at a party you  don’t know if you’re going to get a slap or a hug, I’ve been dealt with both in what feels like equal measure. The lows and highs have been life altering and with all the extra time we’ve all had to over think life,  the process has been like trying to do a sudoku puzzle upside down.  Now we’ve been thrust into chaos navigating another lockdown with our little people and all of the stresses that come with caring for them whilst trying to maintain our sanity, our health and our income. Controversially we pulled our children out before Boris’ announcement. We’re grateful to have options, that don’t come without pain and sacrifices but it was a no brainier for our family situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Switzerland, to Germany, to Belgium and the Netherlands and back to London, the journey has been a roller coaster.  I got my first speeding fine in Belgium (proud moment), consumed the best pancakes in the Netherlands and got sneezed on by a cheeky alpaca in Germany….clearly living the dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here we are gratefully in 2021 shielding, home schooling, surviving, thriving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what have I learnt in 2020?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slow down! Life doesn’t just happen and pass us by, we ignore it and disregard the beautiful moments and get sucked in by the negativity.  Being forced to slow down has allowed me to open my eyes and acknowledge the simple things, its given me the time to focus on things I had previously neglected and forced me to be more appreciative and content. I try not to focus on losing control of what I thought were just basic rights, but perceive it as temporarily scaling down my freedom to achieve a collectively beneficial outcome. It seems to be working for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationships are for the mature. Pandemics and people that lack basic communication skills will come a cropper.  Pandemics have the power to magnify the things you get to ignore whilst at work.  All of a sudden we’ve been thrust into groundhog day, sometimes with loved ones who were barely tolerable on the weekend let alone all day everyday! It takes a huge dose of maturity and commitment to work through the intensity of such situations….work harder, no one is perfect….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn to enjoy your own company. If you don’t like you…. well no need to even finish that sentence… Isolation is tough but it can be a good opportunity to focus on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop procrastinating…. seriously…. tomorrow is not guaranteed and Boris could announce another seismic shift so go get that facial! Paint that bedroom! Enrol on that course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appreciate your loved ones.  Spend quality time and create memories. Regular video chats until this storm is over!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t sweat the small stuff…it’s so easy to drive yourself nuts when someone leaves teabags on kitchen tables daily or drinks milk from the carton. But it’s so important to put things into perspective and don’t overwhelm yourself with things that just don’t matter and are out of your control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be good to yourself - what does that even mean?!! I’ve been struggling to prioritise myself for awhile now and I’ve got a new perspective on self care….there just doesn’t seem to be enough time in the day to do it all.  I’m already spreading myself thin. Squeezing in the rare and coveted pedicure when I can, or treating myself to a slap up meal when the stars align and I’m baby free. My ability to take time out for myself seems to be directly influenced by my cash flow….the more money I have  the more choices I have and the better my ability to ‘self care’ so 2020 has taught me to ‘go get it’! Get me some financial freedom.  So I’m on a journey to living life on my own terms and that means creating wealth to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 weeks ago I had an ungodly sized tube stuck up my vajayjay and was fighting for my life and the life of my unborn….I was not reading Cosmo and watching Loose Women contrary to external observations!  I won’t go into detail but I lost enough blood to require admission and transfusion. By the way….I know why black women are statistically more likely to die in childbirth or during prenatal and postnatal care….we’re not seen, or heard, and simply don’t matter.  Controversial I know….but its true….and there’s absolutely no consequence to the shocking treatment experienced by so many  of us at the hands of racist medical professionals…. and I can boldly say that with no reservation, because I’ve lived it. Fortunately for me, His grace is sufficient in times of my weakness and He has bestowed on me a mouth bigger than any racist wishes to endure…. but this battle is far from over. I want a system that isn’t determined by my countenance, or by the attitude of the professional. A senior consultant recently advised me to “complain” next time I’m mistreated as though I ordered an inadequately cooked steak in Hawksmoor. White privilege allows people to make statements like this. Despite my battles I’ve won the war, I’m just tired of being thrust into the firing line. Grateful for life and love. There’s a story behind the glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How has your 2020 been?! Wishing you love, light and good health. I’d love to hear from you. Please comment, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;, like and share!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>66 Days To Make Me A Priority</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/66-days-to-make-me-a-priority/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/66-days-to-make-me-a-priority/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Selflove</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Parenthood</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Priorities</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/66-days-to-make-me-a-priority/images/beach_jacks_hu0db4735ca0eefac53af818f4f734843c_2049965_790x0_resize_box_2.png" />
          
         

            <description>Have you ever been so tired you start doing things that you’d be embarrassed if anyone saw?</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been so tired you start doing things that you’d be embarrassed if anyone saw? I must have been sleep walking yesterday morning as I almost put orange juice in my cereal and laundry in the oven! I laughed when I snapped out of it, and knew that was a sign I needed to stop and breathe! Before I ended up doing something less funny, and more irreversibly annoying! Time for a cold cup of tea! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever feel like you’re always catching up? Like nothing’s ever quite finished and you’re literally in a state of permanently to be continued? My days are blurring into one, I rarely know what date it is, let alone what day of the week it is! I’m no longer frantic, or perplexed by the seemingly never ending chores. I’ve just accepted I can’t do it all, all of the time. Some things just won’t get done right now, and that’s fine. As long as everyone’s fed, we’re winning! No one ever died from a bulging laundry basket, though the size of mine could easily cause extreme palpitations! If dinner’s not made from scratch, pizza it is tonight! And if I don’t get up early enough to give Mary Poppins a run for her money and make a pack lunch for my toddler, the world will still continue revolving and luckily for me we don’t live in no mans land and food can be bought on route. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a Mothers work is never done, there’s literally no point beating yourself up about not doing it all … just do enough, there will always be something that needs to be done, a floor that needs mopping, clothes that need ironing, a nose that needs wiping. Parents tend to put their own needs secondary to that of their children, it goes with the territory and most of us gracefully accept this as a term of parenting. But what if we just decided to put our own needs on par with that of our children? Is that crazy? Or perhaps just slightly below, a kind of one for me two for them scenario. There will always be demands on your time, your energy, your head space, your boobs, but if you choose you and make yourself a priority even for just a fraction of the day you’ll see that your daily commitments still fill the rest of the day, but you get a moment amidst the chaos just for you. You’re worth that moment. Find it, treasure and make it a new habit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday I’ve decided to choose a self care item on my long list of things I’d like to. Today it’s hair braiding, tomorrow I’ll paint my nails… Well at least that’s the plan, and I feel like finding a nice cafe and having a slow uninterrupted cappuccino and cake st some point this week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitting a little bit of self care is a challenge most days, my days are non stop and when both kids are sleeping in the evening I’m usually exhausted, staring at an overwhelming pile of laundry that needs sorting and a dishwasher that needs loading. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But without that little bit of self care, I have a day full of taking care of everyone but me. And I’ve decided that I deserve to be taken care of too! And it feels good, and yes I’m worth it! So if you’re anything like me and can’t remember the last time you shaved your legs or enjoyed an indulgent bubble bath with essential oils and a glass of Prosecco it may be time for you to join me! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;66 days of me. So the challenge is to do at least one selfish thing a day for 66 days. According to some research carried out by the University College London it takes 66 days to form a habit and this is a habit I want entrenched in my life! So I’m going to make it my new normal to shine a daily dose of self love in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so important to look after our physical, mental and emotional well being. And too often we forget that it takes some effort to do this. Sometimes you’re too burnt out to care or simply don’t have the energy to give you the attention you need. But if you can just claw back a little time and enough energy for yourself, you won’t regret it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self care can come in so many different forms, interpret as you wish. Just do something for yourself that has a positive impact on your physical, mental or emotional wellbeing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t juggle all of the balls at the expense of being well rounded and happy. Our children need us to look after ourselves so that we can be the best parents we can be. And we deserve to reflect the love we give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your thoughts and how you exercise self love. Please &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow&lt;/a&gt;, tag someone who needs to hear this and get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>