<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Tinu Alikor</title>
        <description>Tinu Alikor - Entrepreneur, Agile Evangelist, Wife and Mother</description>
        <link>http://alikor.co.uk/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://alikor.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:21:12 +0100</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:21:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Crossroads</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So after two weeks of reconsidering my business idea, following several fruitless conversations with receptionists and PAs filtering calls to the people I really want to engage with, I have decided to put Sense Care on hold and pursue another idea to take through the PSA course! This is by no means a change of heart, I really believe in Sense Care and what I want to achieve but think I need the experience of a successful startup in order to give me leverage and a foot in, and need a better strategy for b2b marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after an epic few days of mental wrangling I have decided to change my mission…. my mission now is to help new parents with children under 2 to have confidence in public and freedom in the community because parents should feel confident enough to go out so that they can improve the moods of themselves and their children and enjoy their time together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I spent a week writing my story and doing some market research with parents I believe to be my target customer.  My story essentially is the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had my son almost six months ago, and I remember the fear that overwhelmed me when I thought about leaving the house with him and all the challenges that may arise.  I remember feeling completely out of my depth, not knowing where I could go and even how to get myself together to leave the house! The first time I ventured out alone I met a friend at a cafe and apologetically asked the waitress if I could breastfeed my son.  As time has gone on I quickly got my mojo back and was whipping out my breast on demand to feed my hungry baby! I was navigating my way around shopping centres, getting stuck into buggy wars on buses and meandering through busy supermarkets! And loving every moment! When I look back I laugh at the quivering sleep deprived mess I was! For some it takes a little longer to emerge from the zombie like haze….some are possibly never the same again!! Whatever your story, most can identify or know of someone that has experienced some discomfort or struggle with venturing out with a new baby!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have a baby you shouldn’t stop doing the things you love.  You may have to change your perception but fun and babies don’t have to be mutually exclusive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following several iterations and feedback from fellow entrepreneurs and my ideal customer I plan to create a mobile application that helps parents to find their nearest baby friendly venue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://alikor.co.uk/2016/08/14/Crossroads/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alikor.co.uk/2016/08/14/Crossroads/</guid>
                
                <category>entrepreneur</category>
                
                <category>balance</category>
                
                <category>parenthood</category>
                
                <category>change</category>
                
                <category>direction</category>
                
                <category>ideas</category>
                
                <category>independence</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>My Why</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So why…..why why why? I feel an urge to create a lasting legacy.  I want to help people, empower them and support them in making informed and safe decisions about their lives and care provision for as long as they can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Care is so personal, it exposes vulnerabilities and highlights weaknesses.  We understand this is a challenging time for families and offer a service that is person centred, person led and person focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want all of our users to experience and comfortably navigate our systems intuitively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to create a system that works. That promotes independence.  I had my first peer mentoring session today and have also had my first Miracle Morning! Awesome day but truly exhausting as I have been up since 05:00! Today has been a busy day of networking at an event and short-listing designs for my corporate identity. Exciting!  My peer coaching session was with a friend of mine who is taking part of the course aswell and the founder Blooming Founders.  She gave us a good insight into her business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I am in week 4.  Struggling to identify my customer niche and actually speak to them! Who knew how tough it would be to cold call strangers and convince them to part with 10 minutes of their time….would I do it?? Possibly not….what would make me do it…??? Thats the key to unlocking this.  At present there appears to be absolutely no incentive for these already time pressured individuals to talk to me.  So I need to find an incentive and fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rejection is such a painful emotion.  It’s a real blow to my confidence.  After several unsuccessful attempts at securing some market research, I retreated.  Feeling low, confused as to why no one seems interested.  Imagine, being bewildered that no one wants to talk to me(!!)  Similarly to dating its time for a break, to recoup, realign, readjust and rethink my tactics.  Giving up is not an option.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://alikor.co.uk/2016/08/10/My-Why/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alikor.co.uk/2016/08/10/My-Why/</guid>
                
                <category>entrepreneur</category>
                
                <category>balance</category>
                
                <category>parenthood</category>
                
                <category>sensecare</category>
                
                <category>homecare</category>
                
                <category>independence</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Journey Begins</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the beginning of the my story, the first page of what I hope to be the chapter that births my new beginning.  What has inspired this?? Life, and love….I am the proud new mother of my son Joshua.  All 16 weeks of motherhood have been a fierce combination of emotions, sleep deprivation, intimate beauty, overwhelmed with joy.  A journey that has created an abundance of hope, unrivalled love and a desire to be the best I can…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which leads me to my journey of self discovery and achievement.  I want Joshua to be proud of me, motherhood has revived my fierce independence and desire to give him the best start in life I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am, beginning my adventure into the unknown…. by way of a brief introduction, I married the love of my life, Madu an accomplished and passionate polygot developer just over a year ago.  He has slowly encouraged me to dip my pedicured pinky into the world of technology and although initially reluctant it was almost inevitable.  My background is legal, but my true passion is people.  While pregnant, I started to build on my foundations by learning about agile project management and am now a certified practitioner and Scrum Master.  I am keen to follow the Lean methodology in my business and am currently on maternity leave, embarking on a career change to follow my dreams of being a full time entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the present. I have taken a leap of faith and enrolled on two courses, one with a Startup called Mums in Tech, a wonderful group of like minded women who complete a 6 week course to learn the basics of computer programming.  The second is called the Parentpreneur Startup Accelerator, a course that basically helps parents become entrepreneurs and find balance with family life.  So here I am, following a feed with my son at 0300 writing my first blog post! I am excited about this journey and looking forward to sharing the highs and lows with you.  I am all in….destination unknown, but happy.  I am inspired to change my life and those around me for the better and am willing to get dirty doing it….so here goes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://alikor.co.uk/2016/08/01/the-journey-begins/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alikor.co.uk/2016/08/01/the-journey-begins/</guid>
                
                <category>entrepreneur</category>
                
                <category>balance</category>
                
                <category>parenthood</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>