<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motherhood on Tinu Alikor</title>
    <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/motherhood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motherhood on Tinu Alikor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/motherhood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</guid>
      <description>Now I&amp;rsquo;ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?! I remember before my daughter was born jokingly but seriously asking people with multiple kids for tips on how to cope with two kids….no one responded. At first I thought, that&amp;rsquo;s just rude really…a girl just needs some advice, and now I realise that everyone is full on blagging their way through parenthood and no one can offer any tips because some of their survival techniques are unconventional or tailor made to suit them, or they&amp;rsquo;re simply just surviving!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroin, carbs and a stable pay cheque</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</guid>
      <description>“The three biggest addictions are heroin, carbs, and a stable pay cheque” according to Nassim Taleb.
I’m inclined to believe him! I’m presently trying to get a grip of two of these addictions…Thankfully I have never battled with heroin, the closest I’ve got to substance abuse has been a tea addiction! I didn’t even realise I was addicted until I decided to give it up for Lent….and the hulk appeared every morning instead of the amenable me….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Sonshine</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</guid>
      <description>This one. This brilliant, energetic, bold, adventurous, talkative, loving, mischievous boy with endless curiosity is my biggest test. He’s the child you’ll find in the sandpit after a huge downfall of rain playing snow angels in the mud. He’s the one that could find puddles in the desert and could give a puma a run for its money. The one you’ll find moving furniture to scale the table, or pulling the blender out of the cupboard to see how it works, or trying to hang from the window ledge so he can see the bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be the change you want to see</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 06:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</guid>
      <description>I gave birth to my daughter not so long ago…and my life changed. All of a sudden I feel the need to be the woman my daughter will respect and look up to. A woman of integrity and good standing. A woman she’d be proud to call her mum. I didn’t quite feel the same when I had my son. Yes, I felt the basic maternal pull of wanting to be a good role model and parent, and keep him happy and create a nurturing loving environment for him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail Like a Boss</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</guid>
      <description>I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School. Apparently he has passed his probationary period! Yay!! ! But a probationary period….so he can pass or fail? Eurgh…please tell me they’re not starting this already! He’s 2!!! He can’t fail!! Surely?
I then began questioning myself and why I took issue with the suggestion of a probationary period and the thought that my child may be rejected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We’re all equal in the sky…</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</guid>
      <description>We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planned Boob Strikes Are Ok</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 09:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</guid>
      <description>Emergency ones are not! In other words, choosing not to breastfeed is ok. Being forced to stop is not!
It’s National Breast-Feeding week!! Let’s talk food….or should I say food provision…..or should I say shame ridden, guilt provoking, nurturing, painful, stressful, bonding, life sustaining breastfeeding!
It can be all of these things and more, it is truly a personal experience and can be so different for each individual, provoking so many conflicting and often overwhelming emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>