<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Motherhood on Tinu Alikor</title>
        <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/motherhood/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Motherhood on Tinu Alikor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/motherhood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Village People</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/village-people/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/village-people/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Diversity</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/village-people/images/ball_pit_hu8f8ca5005615b0b302b90b7461ff314b_1535491_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>They say it takes a village to raise a child.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;They say it takes a village to raise a child. What do you do when you have no village? When you live away from your village, when your village is dysfunctional, destructive or just plain disappointing? ‘Get your sh*t together and stay in your lane’. That’s my armour response, the response that comes from pain, having learnt the hard way, not to rely on anyone. But honestly, it does take a village to raise a child, a colourful array of loving individuals who piece together the puzzle of life, embrace and care for the child, educate, discipline, uphold, encourage and nurture. I am truly a sum of my evolving village. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/village-people/images/image_huad114e40a948f067e72582eecf6e4ad8_333765_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/village-people/images/image_huad114e40a948f067e72582eecf6e4ad8_333765_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/village-people/images/image_huad114e40a948f067e72582eecf6e4ad8_333765_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/village-people/images/image_huad114e40a948f067e72582eecf6e4ad8_333765_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/village-people/images/image_huad114e40a948f067e72582eecf6e4ad8_333765_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/village-people/images/image_huad114e40a948f067e72582eecf6e4ad8_333765_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If like me you find yourself village-less I implore you to look beyond the parapet and with discernment and an open mind, create your own village. Find those people that you admire, that bring you sunshine, that add value, an alternative perspective, and a different pace. Find your village and be fluid about it’s inhabitants. The cashier at the bank, the lollipop person on your school run, aunty May, uncle Joe, the attendant at the supermarket, the childminder, the Pastor, the neighbour upstairs, grandma or even your old university friend. Your village surrounds you, it’s up to you to choose, and glean what you need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your village is otherwise engaged, a wise unfettered woman once told me, to outsource the heck outta my life! I’m still working on the finances required for that setup! But it’s definitely a new goal! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parenting is one of the toughest and most rewarding gigs on the planet. Some days I have to pinch myself when I think of my blessings and that I’m responsible for two beautiful humans, other days it scares me to think that every decision I make affects them. Doing my best will always have to be good enough, and recently I’ve taken more time for myself to ensure this mama’s self love game is on point! It just gives me more love to dish out. I recently challenged myself to make self love more of a habit, aiming to do at least one act of self love for 66 days. I got to about day 11, then life happened… and I struggled to do anything as so much has been happening. But I haven’t given up, and the thought of the challenge spurs me on to regain the rhythm I started. Self love is more at the forefront of my mind, and that is definitely a positive outcome of the challenge as I previously wasn’t giving myself the time I deserve. Self love isn’t a buzz term, it’s real and it’s necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somebody asked me how I would describe motherhood… and I simply said it’s literally having your heart existing outside of your body. We all just want to give the best to our children, and do our best, and sometimes are consumed with this desire. I’ve started to do less lately, and I don’t mean ‘kids sort your own dinner out’ kind of less… although those days are on the horizon in about 15 years! I mean do less in the sense that I allow myself to do less without judgement. I do what I can and enjoy the feeling of being within my capacity, not over stretched or over burdened. Doing less for me has meant having to be more organised. My days are less care free and ad hoc and more planned with occasional moments for poetic licence. That’s how I do less! I do less of the worrying, less of the white noise that fills my days, less of the gap fillers…more of the meaningful moments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a few recent parenting moments that have left me unsure of what to do, the most recent situation was at my sons nursery.  I turned up the other day and I was greeted by someone whom I didn’t recognise. They had a new member of staff…again…now continuity of staff was appearing to be a small problem, apparently retention of staff in this industry is challenging. I briefly spoke to the new staff member, who seemed shy but pleasant, and as our conversation concluded I found myself wondering whether I was talking to a male or female. The person identified as a woman but had previously been a man. I was completely taken by surprise. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I met someone from the transgender community I was dancing around my hand bag in Soho. And here I was toe to toe whilst wiping my sons nose. It would’ve been nice to be given a heads up by the nursery… I’m not even sure that’s politically correct or acceptable as I guess it would be deemed to be prejudicial and discriminatory to have to announce the employment of someone purely because of their sexuality or gender. I just wanted to have some warning, give me the opportunity to have a few conversations with my son, a whole lot earlier than I would have envisioned. Am I being difficult in wanting to control what my son is exposed to at such an early age? Should the nursery have an obligation to educate the children and inform the parents on the diversity that surrounds them? I’m completely out of my comfort zone, my son may not even have noticed the bearded individual wearing heels and a wig and sporting an impressive adams apple, but mummy did. The world is changing, and diversity comes in all shapes and sizes. I just think as we need to respect individual life choices, that respect should extend to having open and honest discussions and educating us about differences. Parenting is hard. We just want the best for our children, and are often thrust into situations that we have never navigated before and are ill equipped to respond to. Daily I make decisions for my children, and do my best to put their interests first. Just a mama trying to do her best. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your views. Please like, share and comment.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>66 Days To Make Me A Priority</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/66-days-to-make-me-a-priority/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/66-days-to-make-me-a-priority/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Selflove</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Parenthood</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Priorities</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/66-days-to-make-me-a-priority/images/beach_jacks_hu0db4735ca0eefac53af818f4f734843c_2049965_790x0_resize_box_2.png" />
          
         

            <description>Have you ever been so tired you start doing things that you’d be embarrassed if anyone saw?</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been so tired you start doing things that you’d be embarrassed if anyone saw? I must have been sleep walking yesterday morning as I almost put orange juice in my cereal and laundry in the oven! I laughed when I snapped out of it, and knew that was a sign I needed to stop and breathe! Before I ended up doing something less funny, and more irreversibly annoying! Time for a cold cup of tea! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever feel like you’re always catching up? Like nothing’s ever quite finished and you’re literally in a state of permanently to be continued? My days are blurring into one, I rarely know what date it is, let alone what day of the week it is! I’m no longer frantic, or perplexed by the seemingly never ending chores. I’ve just accepted I can’t do it all, all of the time. Some things just won’t get done right now, and that’s fine. As long as everyone’s fed, we’re winning! No one ever died from a bulging laundry basket, though the size of mine could easily cause extreme palpitations! If dinner’s not made from scratch, pizza it is tonight! And if I don’t get up early enough to give Mary Poppins a run for her money and make a pack lunch for my toddler, the world will still continue revolving and luckily for me we don’t live in no mans land and food can be bought on route. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a Mothers work is never done, there’s literally no point beating yourself up about not doing it all … just do enough, there will always be something that needs to be done, a floor that needs mopping, clothes that need ironing, a nose that needs wiping. Parents tend to put their own needs secondary to that of their children, it goes with the territory and most of us gracefully accept this as a term of parenting. But what if we just decided to put our own needs on par with that of our children? Is that crazy? Or perhaps just slightly below, a kind of one for me two for them scenario. There will always be demands on your time, your energy, your head space, your boobs, but if you choose you and make yourself a priority even for just a fraction of the day you’ll see that your daily commitments still fill the rest of the day, but you get a moment amidst the chaos just for you. You’re worth that moment. Find it, treasure and make it a new habit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday I’ve decided to choose a self care item on my long list of things I’d like to. Today it’s hair braiding, tomorrow I’ll paint my nails… Well at least that’s the plan, and I feel like finding a nice cafe and having a slow uninterrupted cappuccino and cake st some point this week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitting a little bit of self care is a challenge most days, my days are non stop and when both kids are sleeping in the evening I’m usually exhausted, staring at an overwhelming pile of laundry that needs sorting and a dishwasher that needs loading. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But without that little bit of self care, I have a day full of taking care of everyone but me. And I’ve decided that I deserve to be taken care of too! And it feels good, and yes I’m worth it! So if you’re anything like me and can’t remember the last time you shaved your legs or enjoyed an indulgent bubble bath with essential oils and a glass of Prosecco it may be time for you to join me! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;66 days of me. So the challenge is to do at least one selfish thing a day for 66 days. According to some research carried out by the University College London it takes 66 days to form a habit and this is a habit I want entrenched in my life! So I’m going to make it my new normal to shine a daily dose of self love in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so important to look after our physical, mental and emotional well being. And too often we forget that it takes some effort to do this. Sometimes you’re too burnt out to care or simply don’t have the energy to give you the attention you need. But if you can just claw back a little time and enough energy for yourself, you won’t regret it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self care can come in so many different forms, interpret as you wish. Just do something for yourself that has a positive impact on your physical, mental or emotional wellbeing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t juggle all of the balls at the expense of being well rounded and happy. Our children need us to look after ourselves so that we can be the best parents we can be. And we deserve to reflect the love we give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your thoughts and how you exercise self love. Please &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow&lt;/a&gt;, tag someone who needs to hear this and get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Mamas on the edge</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mamas-on-the-edge/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/mamas-on-the-edge/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Mental health</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Happy place</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/mumAndSon_hu358252306266c9178e090aa045e416f3_530939_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Last week was mental health awareness week.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Last week was mental health awareness week. Sadly as a society we seem to have difficulty accepting the diversity of mental illness, and our sensitivities and ignorance have alienated some of the most vulnerable and misunderstood. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a compelling documentary by Louis Theroux called Mothers on the Edge on BBC Two. Depicting an insight into the stories of mothers who found themselves facing mental illness. A fascinating programme which really highlighted the nature of mental illness and it’s indiscriminate, potentially destructive reach. If you haven’t already, it’s worth a gander. It told stories of women who were staying at a residential mental health facility with their babies being treated for various illnesses. Some with a history of mental health concerns and some whose first experience of their illness emerged when their babies were born. It told of women, just like me, living and hoping, working towards a future and through no fault of their own struck with sometimes unexplainable mental illnesses. It humbled me to think that this so easily could have been me. Mental illness doesn’t discriminate, it transcends class, wealth, social position, employment history, and notions of ‘strength’. When people speak of women on the edge I slightly recoil as I feel we’re all living on the edge of something… and sometimes the smallest and seemingly insignificant catalyst can push any of us over the edge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/mamas-on-the-edge/images/bridge_hubf12bc8b79aaa77bbbb2d4149e7f4010_1499565_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motherhood as I’ve documented in my blogs has been an experience I will treasure forever. It’s been beautiful and rewarding, and yet the hardest journey I’ve ever encountered and whilst I’ve never experienced mental illness I could identify with some of the emotions the women claimed to be feeling. Helplessness, anxiety, exhaustion to name a few. I saw myself in some of them and wondered what pushed them to the edge? Most of these feelings I guess are just part and parcel of motherhood… but when these emotions begin to overwhelm you and you literally feel like you’re drowning, it’s time to ask for help. At what point should you ask for help…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now…the time is now, it’s never too early to speak and be heard, to share your thoughts, your fears, the confusion that envelopes you, the debilitating anxiety that grips you. You’re not alone. I’ll be honest and say that the documentary made me tear up. When I thought about these women facing their demons, struggling in their daily lives, suffocated by their thoughts, I felt sad. Sad not only because of the compassion I felt and the poignance of the relationship between a mother and child, and the daily challenges, but because that could so easily have been me, or one of my loved ones… and I’m not sure I’d recognise the signs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in social media perfection, striving to show our best, put our best foot forward and ensure we keep it together at all costs, and when we can’t, insta doesn’t send help… facebook doesn’t give you a warm embrace and twitter certainly doesn’t wipe away your tears. And yet we continue to expect mothers to have it all ticking along, because Grandma had 8 kids and could balance 3 of them on her hip whilst ploughing the field. Grandma was awesome. Props to her! I on the other hand hate gardening and can barely balance one kid on my hip. I have it as all together as I can, regularly questioning my ability to keep all my balls in the air, and even more regularly deciding to put the balls down and just have a nap. I try, like we all do and have moments of vulnerability, despondence and darkness, sometimes no amount of self motivation will do, and we just need some help. So as we come to the end of Mental Health Awareness week, I implore you to consider the mothers who may need a little extra kindness, patience, compassion and a non judgmental ear. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself on the edge I hope you remember there are so many of us right next to you. Don’t look down and lose your balance, step away from the rim and keep your feet firmly on the ground. I hope you find a source of help and support, and get back to your happy place. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please comment, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow&lt;/a&gt;, like and share!, like and share. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Freedom Day</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>MyFreedomDay</category>
            
                <category>discrimination</category>
            
                <category>pregnancy</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>freedom</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/freedom_hu72824833961529480145661fda384d45_219928_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>If it doesn’t have Lycra in it and requires ironing, it’s dead to me.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;If it doesn’t have Lycra in it and requires ironing, it’s dead to me. I’m somewhere in between a size 12 and in denial. No idea what my style is right now. Comfortable? Functional? Clean? Or maybe just not publicly naked?! I can’t legitimately wear maternity clothing anymore….although that stretchy waistband gives me life most days! So for now I’m going with it! Baggy is totally in. Bed hair chic is back and I’m rocking it like it’s 99. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiger marks are appearing in some obscure places but I’m loving the life tattoos. These battle scars are epic and the war has been won!! Well yes I’ve won, I have two beautiful children and I fought through the sickness, the exhaustion, the aches, the doubts, the tests, the sleepless nights, the bladder with a mind of its own, the garlic aversions, the breathlessness, the mumgry moments on the London underground during rush hour, and of course… the labour. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labour… the event that’s pencilled into your diary as a definite, with no definites, no calendar invite needed, this is your party baby!  There’s no opting out of this one, no deferring, it’s the inevitable…that baby is coming to join the world by any means necessary. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t give labour much thought initially. I attended a prenatal class, watched documentaries, my husband banned me from watching as I cried over every episode and read a couple of articles. But nothing really prepared me for the day it all happened. For medical reasons I was told that I may have to have a caesarean section. No one could really explain why, just that it was ‘best’. I spent months of the pregnancy with a small hope that I may be able to give birth naturally, but content with having a C section if that was best for both me and the baby. I have nothing against c sections, it’s just that I’ve spent the majority of my life in and out of hospital, and been on the operating table more times than I care to remember. I take surgery very seriously, and if there’s a path that safely avoids that route, I’ll take that thank you very much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day I went into the emergency maternity unit as I couldn’t feel the baby moving as I had before. I was checked over and thankfully all was fine. Before I left, the doctor asked me if I had made a decision on whether or not to have a c section. I reiterated that I still didn’t quite understand why I couldn’t give birth naturally and if this was still an option I’d like to take it. The doctor told me that if I gave birth naturally I would end up having an emergency c section and that in those instances the doctors primary objective is to get the baby out quickly. According to her if in this emergency organs are damaged or arteries cut, that’s just collateral damage I’ll have to accept! Through tears of fear in that cold examination room, I signed the consent forms she shoved in front of me and agreed to have the c section. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C section day arrived… I had my bag packed and my husband and I went to the hospital to meet our baby. The consultants did their early morning rounds before the day began. The consultant introduced himself and asked me how I was and what I was there for. I laughed and said ‘I’m here to meet my baby, and you’ve booked me in for a c-section I don’t even want’. It was a teaching hospital, and surrounded by a group of students they all gawked at me. The consultant then sat on my bed and asked me what I wanted… I explained what had happened and how throughout my pregnancy no one had explained anything to me and I felt invisible, I even had to write my birth plan myself as the midwife said I didn’t need one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one knows how labour will go for anyone, and why was I any different? Unless there’s a clear medical reason that someone can actually explain to me I would rather not have surgery. The doctor smiled, and said ‘you don’t have to do anything you don’t want to do’. He told me to go home. I went home and a week later gave birth to my son naturally. Whether it was possible or not, someone believed I had the right to choose. He empowered me that morning and gave me my voice back. He gave me the freedom to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years later, pregnant again, I  faced similar attitudes and an air of disconnection that I couldn’t quite put my finger on. Last pregnancy I pretty much lived in the hospital, going in weekly for check ups towards the end and being treated like a glass shoe. This time I’ve been seen a handful of times for the mandatory scans and checks, nothing more nothing less. As I’ve given birth naturally once before there was no question as to my ability to do so this time, with the obvious disclaimer that anything can happen during labour! This time around no consultant checks, again no birth plan. Bewildered by the eerie sense of isolation I just got on with it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into labour in the middle of the night, awoken by feelings I’d had a dodgy burrito. Went back to sleep more irritated than in pain…clearly I don’t know what contractions feel like, as this apparently was the start of labour for me. I eventually gave into the discomfort and got dressed to go and get checked out at the hospital, during which the pain increased and I realised I was in labour. We got an uber to the hospital and I was literally struggling not to have the baby in the back seat of the car! We arrived at the hospital, it was quiet… just a dozing security guard who although manning the entrance to a maternity unit seemed mythed that a woman had arrived in the middle of the night in labour…cue eye roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband found a wheelchair and a nurse and I was taken in. I felt a certain sense of relief, that I was in safe hands and that they knew what they were doing, and that it would all be ok. As the pain increased and I begged for someone to help me and give me some pain relief I realised that this may not be the case. I was examined and they quickly assessed I was already 8cm dilated. I kept shouting that the baby was coming, at least give me some gas and air…they insisted on moving me to another room on a different floor! I got to the designated room and told to relax it would ok. I begged for gas and air and none came. I remember in that moment being silent and realising I was on my own. It felt like an out of body experience. I started concentrating on my breathing, focussing on slowing down and blocking out the noise of the panicked midwives. They were fumbling around trying to find the baby’s heartbeat. Amidst the confusion they finally gave me gas and air, my daughters head popped out, they all looked visibly shocked and the rest is history. No one was listening to me, I felt invisible and vulnerable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 14 is #MyFreedomDay. Every woman deserves to be heard. To have the freedom to make informed choices about their bodies, to be listened to and understood. To be given the power of autonomy over their fabric, their mind, their uterus. Freedom to decide what’s best for me and my baby. When you take away a woman’s freedom, you strip her of her dignity, you extinguish her power, you make her invisible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women often like to share labour stories. When you’ve had a child it’s almost a right of passage, a conversation that creates bonds. So many people have asked me to share my story, so many have stories that hurt to relive. Labour can be traumatic for some, life changing for all. I don’t know why my cries were ignored, or my wishes mocked, but I hear all too often of the plight of black women in labour and it makes my heart cry. If it had not been for the consultant who sat down and listened to me, my story would have been very different. We may be strong, but we deserve to be heard, everyone deserves this freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
                <category>Family</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/two-happy-kids_hu8bd73f293d04bbc53f400c406222be67_1908490_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Now I’ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?! I remember before my daughter was born jokingly but seriously asking people with multiple kids for tips on how to cope with two kids….no one responded. At first I thought, that’s just rude really…a girl just needs some advice, and now I realise that everyone is full on blagging their way through parenthood and no one can offer any tips because some of their survival techniques are unconventional or tailor made to suit them, or they’re simply just surviving!! Whatever your ‘methods’ I salute and chest bump you with passion.  It ain’t easy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well…. I am three months into having two children, just when I thought I had got the shower routine mastered, got my hair out of doo doo plaits and ditched the stained hareem pants, I go and have another child! This new addition was never going to propel me into more self loving and uninterrupted ‘me time’. I now have even less time, am even more exhausted… if that’s even possible and actually considered sitting in my double pram whilst the toddler was at nursery, pulling the hood down and having a kip next to the baby the other day… I was that tired. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I have no real tips as such there are a few things that I wish I had known and that have helped me ‘survive’ so far. So I’m sharing in the hope that even one parent out there receives some light and love from this post, even if it is just a warm virtual bear hug reminding you, you’re not alone! We’re all just fumbling around in the dark hoping not to cause any irreparable damage! And we are essentially doing great, we just need reminding of that occasionally! Please share things that work for you too! Every little helps!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, my top ten suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a baby carrier - I never used one with my first child. I never really needed to! I had the luxury of not having to regularly multi task whilst holding my son, so although I had one only used it a handful of occasions. When you have more than one child, a baby carrier is like air! Fundamental!!! You’ll need your hands free to do stuff, tend to your other child, household stuff, whatever, but in those early stages casually sitting breastfeeding or cuddling your newborn for hours isn’t always possible. Look for your nearest sling library and try before you buy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a decent bag. Notice I didn’t say baby bag. If you find a fit for purpose baby bag that works for you then run with it, but you really need a bag that’s big enough for what you need, accessible, and can be attached or hung on your pushchair with ease. If you buy a large bag you can purchase inserts for each child to differentiate between their things, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always carry a water bottle and food (not just for the kids!) - rehydrate and feed yourself too!! Whether you’re breastfeeding or not, a fuelled mummy is a happier mummy. Water is essential especially when breastfeeding. I remember getting headaches in the first few weeks of my daughters birth when I was dehydrated. Easy resolution! Drink!! And I don’t mean cocktails! As for eating, I had a habit of just eating in between meals, eating my sons left over food and sometimes being too tired to have my own meal once the kids are sleeping. This isn’t sustainable and you need to make sure you’re looking after yourself. So batch cook if it’s easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid to ask for help. My husband and I have always done everything ourselves due to geography, which has put a strain on us both as we seldom get time out. But now we have 2 children we actively welcome opportunities to get help and in the first 2 months of my daughters life I received help with my toddler to ensure he was stimulated daily, happy and engaged. Asking for help from your loved ones is not a sign of weakness or inability to cope. It really does take a village to raise a child. Put your village on speed dial and get them involved!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do your best to schedule your kids naps as close together as possible. Nap time is sacred. My son no longer naps. I know, I cried about it too, but if he did I would be taking this on board! Try and be consistent with bedtime too. Children love routine and once they know what to expect you’ll have an easier time getting them to comply. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find distraction techniques for the older child. Have quick go-to toys and games that your child loves to keep him/her occupied if you need to attend to the younger one. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get out of the house! Yes I know it sounds like a logistical nightmare and it can be the first couple of times when you work out what works for you, and literally ‘how’ to get you all clothed and fed to leave the house! But… once you get past the chaos, it will feel like you’ve reached nirvana! The fresh air and change of scenery will do wonders for your mental health and the children will feel better too! 
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sleep when they sleep. If you manage to get both kids sleeping simultaneously….grab your duvet and get involved! The washing, cooking, laundry, phonecall, can wait!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Date night. In-between feeds, nappy changes, projectile vomit, nursery runs and reruns of paw patrol remember how it all began and make some time for the love that started it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make time for yourself at least once a week. Even if it’s just half an hour of uninterruption. Do something you enjoy! Read a book, paint your nails, have a hot bath, go to the cinema, go for a swim. Whatever floats your boat, make time for it. You will always have lots to do, the list is endless, but if you make time for the things that are important to you and make them a priority rather than a ‘nice to have’ the rest of your time will be filled with the daily responsibilities and you’ll feel better for the little moments you made time for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Heroin, carbs and a stable pay cheque</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Poetry</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Children</category>
            
                <category>Individuality</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>“The three biggest addictions are heroin, carbs, and a stable pay cheque” according to Nassim Taleb.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The three biggest addictions are heroin, carbs, and a stable pay cheque” according to Nassim Taleb.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m inclined to believe him! I’m presently trying to get a grip of two of these addictions…Thankfully I have never battled with heroin, the closest I’ve got to substance abuse has been a tea addiction! I didn’t even realise I was addicted until I decided to give it up for Lent….and the hulk appeared every morning instead of the amenable me….and the headaches….awful, throbbing migraines. But I’m proud to say I went cold turkey and I am 5 years clean and haven’t looked back! I am now content with a satisfying cup of decaf….rock and roll!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_395x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 395w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 790w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_1580x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 1580w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_2370x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 2370w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/food_hu7f402cd7215ecd784fc69a5edaf584b7_249183_3160x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two main forms of carbohydrates are sugars, such as fructose, glucose, and lactose, and starches, which are found in foods such as starchy vegetables,grains, rice, breads, and cereals. The body breaks down (or converts) most carbs into the sugar glucose, which is absorbed into the bloodstream. In my eyes carbs are a necessary part of a balanced diet, but in excess carbs are evil, tasty morsels of doughy sweet pleasure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be a UK size &lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;⁄&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;, without making any effort. I was one of those people, you loved to hate as it took no effort to consume a few Big Macs and a side of nuggets and still look like I was about to run a triathlon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I stupidly made an impulsive online purchase, completely in size denial. A gorgeous size 8 skirt…..what decade was I size 8?! Oh how the mighty fall, that ship has sailed and lost at sea! I’m not sure if it’s age, post baby body or simply that I’ve used up my quota of taking the piss out of human physiology but I now have to actually think about what I eat, and the muscle memory has &lt;strong&gt;left the building.&lt;/strong&gt; So carbs are not a friend, and my love of bread, and pasta, and pizza and rice, and fries and yams and all of the beautiful carbs of the world are becoming my nemesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst breastfeeding I think I eat my body weight in carbs daily. It’s a seriously uncontrollable craving and a bowl of lettuce and quinoa just won’t cut it. So I have no plans to give up carbs, but definitely need to reconsider how much I consume and find myself some satisfying alternatives. I’ll be blogging about these alternatives as and when I find them. If you know of any please share! I’m not going to promise to cut out carbs but I will be more carb conscious and to that effect I’ll aim to reduce my intake significantly! She says as she runs to grab her imported custard creams!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbs and my attachment to a stable pay cheque…both arguably equally as destructive to my waistline. I’ve spent the majority of my adult life addicted to the high of getting my pay at the end of the month it has paralysed me into falling for the mythical safety net. It’s reassured me into almost sleep-walking into retirement in a job I’d rather not be doing, tolerating treatment I don’t deserve, second guessing my worth and relegating my dreams to mere fantasy. We all need an income, and we can’t all be entrepreneurs. There’s no shame in the stability and comfort of a regular pay cheque. But if your dreams are keeping you awake at night and your hands are itching to create your destiny you may be on the road to beating the pay cheque addiction. I’m confident I’ll always be able to find a job that will pay my bills and enable me to survive….but I won’t always have the passion and energy to take risks that could result in me creating my own destiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scarily, the first month of the year is already almost over… That’s one twelfth of the year essentially done and dusted. I’ve only just finished writing my goals for the year, so I’ve missed 27 opportunities to work on achieving them. Yes it is that granula to me! Luckily I have plenty of days to make up for it, to stay focused and make my dreams a reality and I’m ready to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year has already brought our family challenges that appear insurmountable and draining the energy we started with, but as our glass is always half full and even half full we’re willing to give a sip or two to those in a drought, we are persevering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addiction is real, cold turkey isn’t for everyone. I’m a rip the plaster off kind of girl with a high pain threshold and minimal patience. Know yourself. Do what’s best for you. Make yourself a priority. But don’t let addiction of any sort rule your life. Take back the control, and make life enhancing choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, please feel free to get in touch. Before the arrival of my daughter I posted every Monday morning…once I come out of this sleep deprived funk, I’ll be posting regularly again(almost there!)! Please follow me on Medium, instagram, facebook and twitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to join Tech Mums, please join the facebook group&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>My Sonshine</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Poetry</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Children</category>
            
                <category>Individuality</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>This one. This brilliant, energetic, bold, adventurous, talkative, loving, mischievous boy with endless curiosity is my biggest test.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;This one. This brilliant, energetic, bold, adventurous, talkative, loving, mischievous boy with endless curiosity is my biggest test. He’s the child you’ll find in the sandpit after a huge downfall of rain playing snow angels in the mud. He’s the one that could find puddles in the desert and could give a puma a run for its money. The one you’ll find moving furniture to scale the table, or pulling the blender out of the cupboard to see how it works, or trying to hang from the window ledge so he can see the bus. He’s the one that can climb a mountain and still not tire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s the one you have to watch, I have ears and eyes everywhere. My patience is being challenged daily, but I know he’s just being a child, inquisitive, curious, testing the colours of life, testing boundaries, testing the physical integrity of every fixture in the apartment and excited by everything he encounters. It’s exhausting but beautiful to see and I am finding ways to nurture this passionate and inquisitive mind and channel his energy into producing something great, and just let him be. For truly great he will be. Wise, compassionate, loving, strong, sincere, motivated and kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s the one that will eat broccoli just so that his sister doesn’t cry. That asks me multiple times during the day if I’m ok. Who says I love you at every opportunity, and tells me I’m beautiful. And whose kisses and hugs are unrivalled warm embraces that feel like hot chocolate on a cold day. I wouldn’t have him any other way. My sonshine.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Be the change you want to see</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 06:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>New Year</category>
            
                <category>Feminism</category>
            
                <category>New Year Resolution</category>
            
                <category>Motivation</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I gave birth to my daughter not so long ago…and my life changed.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I gave birth to my daughter not so long ago…and my life changed. All of a sudden I feel the need to be the woman my daughter will respect and look up to. A woman of integrity and good standing. A woman she’d be proud to call her mum. I didn’t quite feel the same when I had my son. Yes, I felt the basic maternal pull of wanting to be a good role model and parent, and keep him happy and create a nurturing loving environment for him. But this awareness of my daughter, a woman in the making, in a world where we have fought for equality tirelessly and still argue over the gender pay gap and general sexism, I fear that I have brought her into a world that won’t give her the chance she deserves. But I want to teach her to take what she deserves and throw away the notion that you get what you’re given and to wait politely for your turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to equip her with the tools to make the best of every situation. To thrive even in arid conditions. To be a lover not a hater. I want her to be resilient, strong, feisty, unrepentant in truth, strong willed and vivacious. To be herself, authentic, unapologetic, fierce and loving. To see her unairbrushed, undiluted beauty. I want her to feel entitled to success, to belong if she chooses, to banish any emotions of imposition, to set her own standards, dance to her own beat and to enjoy every moment as if it were her last. I need to lead by example…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2019 is moments away…a new year, full of new opportunities, new hope, new challenges, new adventures. I’m excited, and apprehensive and eager to embark on a new chapter. I’ve been a stay at home mother for almost three years. Enjoying the fruit of nurturing the growth of my children and balancing my need for personal satisfaction with my responsibilities as a mother and wife. I’m enjoying this stage in my life and preparing for my next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going into this year putting the pains and mistakes of 2018 behind me, learning as I go. Allowing doors that need to be closed to stay firmly shut, looking forward to new doors being open. Finding new zeal and passion for progress, and making me a priority. Grateful for loyal friends whose love is without condition. Looking forward to continuing raising my children in love and peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, may you find joy, and may your dreams find you. May you be the change you want to see. May you find peace in your decisions. May you find vision helpers and people who truly have your back. May your husband replace the toilet roll occasionally, and take the rubbish out without complaining. May your boobs recover from breastfeeding and may postpartum hair loss be a myth, may you get some precious sleep without being shocked awake with a chubby finger in your nostril. May your glass of prosecco always runneth over. May you find the strength to make the changes you need and the resilience to plan without fear of failure. And mostly may you remember just how wonderful you are and have the potential to be, and simply be thankful for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t create your life first and then live it. You create it by living it not agonising over it! Whatever your situation be the best version of yourself! May this year be a year of doing, and living. Happy New Year! Be intentional…&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Fail Like a Boss</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Failure</category>
            
                <category>Life Lessons</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Fear Of Failure</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/images/feature_hu922ba9b63a8233a3c6308bd992b0acb5_4597736_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School. Apparently he has passed his probationary period! Yay!! ! But a probationary period….so he can pass or fail? Eurgh…please tell me they’re not starting this already! He’s 2!!! He can’t fail!! Surely?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then began questioning myself and why I took issue with the suggestion of a probationary period and the thought that my child may be rejected. ‘Rejection’ is so emotive! Are we so sensitive that the thought of being measured or challenged makes us inherently uncomfortable? Is failing at something a conclusive label? What’s wrong with failing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son may not be best suited to a particular environment or activity depending on his disposition, but fail…? No no no….I’m a great believer in exposing children to as many new experiences as you can and letting them decide what they enjoy, or have an affinity for. I don’t want to be pushy or overbearing, just trying to find a balance between being encouraging and of course being protective and having his best interests at heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many of us pre-empt what we think our children can handle, we allow our own characteristics to define our children’s potential. We often label them, and spend their formative years projecting ourselves on their blank canvases, before they can even pronounce the word ‘fail’. In trying to protect them we confine them to our own limitations. Sometimes we confuse genuine care with control and fear. Finding the right balance is not easy…like most aspects of parenting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not big on wildlife and nature. I’m in awe of the beauty of the world and intrigued by animals…and have had the pleasure of experiencing some truly breathtaking sights all over the world. But whilst I love an adventure, and have been known to get stuck into spontaneous excursions, white water rafting, zip lining and (indoor) skydiving, I’m Nigerian, my mum would slap me if I voluntarily threw myself out of a plane. But I’m more comfortable reclining in an air conditioned vehicle observing the various spectacles than being knee deep in dirt swatting away creatures that quite possibly could send me into a panicked state of hyperventilation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So roughing it in campsites, sharing a bathroom and using toilet facilities that involve holes in the ground are just not my thing. But of course I don’t want to inflict my princess ways on my child. He’ll learn some grit from me, but not the kind that’s suitable for any bush tucker trial. So I’m trying my best to put my own sensibilities aside and allow my son to learn and grow, and experience the world through his own lens. And that’s what parenting is all about. Trying not to screw your child over with the sometimes messed up issues you may have whilst keeping them alive and happy! Tall order!
Have you ever been so afraid at failing at something you decided not to try at all? Is the fear of failure so strong that it surpasses the fear of regret or stagnation? I’m not sure why we’re so fearful of failing, personally I’d rather fail quickly and move on than paralyse myself into not trying at all. I guess I have more of a fear of regret than a fear of failure. Failing is ok, it means you had the guts to try and that in itself deserves a pat on the back. Failure should be followed by a personal debrief, what went wrong? How can you avoid it in the future? It’s ok to fail, but failing to try is a waste of your potential. And you have potential!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m altering my perspective and promoting failure, as it is in the trying that we truly become great. I want my son to grasp opportunities with both hands and I’ll try my best to stand behind him and cushion if his falls. Falling is ok, as long as you get up again. And it doesn’t matter how many times you fail, keep rising, and don’t stop trying.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>We’re all equal in the sky…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Travel</category>
            
                <category>Discrimination</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Disability</category>
            
                <category>British Airways</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/feature_hu9ac72fe668a507003fd0f28db21e8729_1160980_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>So my most recent flight from Switzerland to London has taken me awhile to recover from.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;So my most recent flight from Switzerland to London has taken me awhile to recover from. I am a seasoned traveller who isn’t easily flustered. I plan my route, prepare my luggage and get going! Saying this being a black female, with mobility issues travelling with a toddler whilst pregnant puts a slightly different spin on the situation and its this I’d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m always trying to do it all, juggling, balancing plates on my head whilst spinning wheels in my palms…I’m the consummate multi tasker. Like most, you just get on without considering the extent of the task you’re embarking on. If it’s got to get done, you just do. Having a toddler who doesn’t always fit nicely into my trello board of actions and more often than not actually seems to purposely sabotage my zen goals, just makes my multi tasking all the more challenging and sometimes fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I forget to add that I have mobility issues too….?! Yep I have scoliosis and had a major op on my leg so walking long distances carrying luggage isn’t possible for me unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve got a few things making life a little more colourful it seems but I still need to get from A to B. I do everything within my power to prepare for the trip, and even requested for mobility assistance when booking my flight. On a previous journey I had been reprimanded…yes reprimanded for not requesting assistance for both myself and my son, as they sent one person to assist me and despite my booking clearly being for myself and my 2 year old son, they apparently assumed he’d manage to get himself to the gate and just meet me there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this time I was ready, I prudently booked assistance for both of us. I arrived at check in with ample time. I reminded them I had requested assistance and was told to wait in the waiting area for assistance to arrive. I waited…..and waited…..and waited…..sorry did I forget to say I have an active two year old?!? And waited….nothing….feeling a little anxious about the flight time, I went back to the desk and asked for an update and reminded them I was still waiting. I was told that the flight had been delayed and they had no idea when the plane would arrive, and that someone would let me know…..a series of ambiguous statements after waiting for almost 2 hours with a toddler….no one informed me of any changes to the flight time and rather some half an hour later, assistance arrived. She took one look at me and abruptly told me she wasn’t there to run after my baby!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now….please enlighten me…. a pregnant passenger with mobility issues travelling with her baby requests for assistance and this is the response?! I told her I had not expected anyone to ‘run after my child’ and simply needed one person to push me in the wheelchair and another to push his pram. Or be transported in one of those buggy carts. I would have happily had my son on my lap but apparently health and safety regulations do not permit this, so what other option do I have?! She said that isn’t going to happen, and I burst into tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was the hormones, maybe it was the frustration. I feel like I am constantly at war with the world. Fighting to prove that I can do it all, and sometimes I just can’t….and when I ask for help, I really need it…..and if it’s offered and then taken away with such humiliation I’m lost. That day I was lost. What do I do? I always work on the premise that you just need to learn to deal with things yourself. Lower your expectations of people and get on with what you need to do…I plan for disappointment daily. I plan for having to do it all…. but when a company pretends to offer a service that means that for once I can plan for someone to help me, and at my most vulnerable I realise that once again I’m on my own, I’m reduced to tears. I cried because had this happened two hours before I would have somehow got myself and my son to the gate. I would have walked at a pace I can manage, taken breaks if I needed to and just got on with it. But with no time to get through security and then walk to the gate I felt helpless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing they had reduced me to tears somehow they managed to get another person to push my son in the pram whilst I sobbed in the wheelchair. But it was too late. Whatever shred of dignity I had when I arrived had been reduced to the size of the wet boarding pass I held in my hand. They left me at the plane entrance, no staff helped me board the flight, a passenger kindly helped me with my hand baggage, whilst the air stewards looked on. It wasn’t heavy, but I am unable to even reach the over head lockers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On arrival at Heathrow it didn’t get much better. Again no assistance disembarking with my hand luggage and toddler. I left the plane and mobility assistance was waiting at the entrance. I told the assistant my son had a buggy that was usually brought to the plane entrance. The buggy arrived and she asked me to carry it to the mobility transportation! Carry it??! How on earth can I carry it?! I am asking for assistance and you expect me to carry a large buggy?!! I told her I can’t do that as it’s too heavy, and if she’d give me a moment I can unfold it and simply push it. To which she rolled her eyes and waited. Again no assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the transportation and I put my luggage and my son on the buggy cart, again no assistance. She began to drive and it soon became apparent that all of the lifts were surprisingly out of service! She stopped the cart and said that we had to walk. I saw several other passengers being driven in buggy carts over take us and I wondered what route they were taking and why their assistant had not demanded they walk? Surely we are all going to the exit? I was exhausted by now and asked her if she could ask one of her colleagues if there was another way she could take to avoid us having to walk. She reluctantly did so, and lo and behold there was another route!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/Joshua_sky_plane_hud9f6590b2fb0a76fd320f248e8abdfd4_996747_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am dumbfounded as to how @Britishairways and both Zurich and Heathrow airport handled my situation. The guidelines are unclear so expectations are hazy. The training given to staff dealing with passengers with mobility requirements needs to be revised. Unfortunately this is not an isolated incident and I and many have experienced poor customer service because of requesting for mobility assistance. The grey area the airports and airlines seem to be ignoring is how to handle passengers with mobility issues and dependants. How to help pregnant women if needed. Why do airlines have conflicting regulations? Which policy takes precedence? The airline or the airport?! If it’s at the discretion of airline staff whether to assist with hand baggage or not, should I simply not travel with hand baggage?! Travelling without hand baggage with a baby is an impossibility by the way…or should I hope that the air steward has woken up on the right side of bed today and isn’t offended by my stained hareem pants?! If I can’t physically put my hand luggage in the overhead locker and the staff are not obliged to assist me, what happens next?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One too many bad experiences on British Airways. The consequence of these ‘errors’, ‘oversights’ even blissful ignorance, is that it robs people of their dignity. It exposes our differences rather than celebrating our similarities. It creates fear and anxiety where just a small hand of help can change so much. Airlines and service providers need to be consistent in their approach to all that seek mobility assistance, and all that are less able or vulnerable for whatever reason. Consistent in their policy making and create confidence in our expectations. I rarely ask for help, but when I do, I really need it. Discrimination isn’t ok, it’s real, demeaning, demoralising, and whilst so many commentators on the subject have no real experience I unfortunately live it every day. When will it get better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People talk about discrimination like it’s just a hot topic, or an awkward can of worms they’d rather not consume. Debate is great, but please stop telling me about your best friends, hairdressers, neighbour who’s from Eritrea, or that cashier at Tesco’s you love with Downs Syndrome. It mocks our daily struggle and reminds me that we have come so far and yet have so much further left to go. Rather listen, be honest and sincere if you lack understanding and desire to break down barriers, and support the fight for injustice. Don’t succumb to the faux pax minefield, just let your integrity speak for itself and lets stand together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mum always said to treat others how you’d like to be treated. As simple as it sounds, we all need to try a little bit harder to engage this way and treat everyone like humans. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Planned Boob Strikes Are Ok</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 09:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Breastfeeding</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Baby</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/images/feature_hu9975dff1fa10e7614cba043485ce311b_267554_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Emergency ones are not! In other words, choosing not to breastfeed is ok.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Emergency ones are not! In other words, choosing not to breastfeed is ok. Being forced to stop is not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s National Breast-Feeding week!! Let’s talk food….or should I say food provision…..or should I say shame ridden, guilt provoking, nurturing, painful, stressful, bonding, life sustaining breastfeeding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be all of these things and more, it is truly a personal experience and can be so different for each individual, provoking so many conflicting and often overwhelming emotions. It’s one of the ways we can feed our babies and its benefits are promoted and preached far and wide. At a life changing, stale milk perfumed time, faced with an overwhelming amount of information, advice, advertisements, exhausted by all the physiological changes, sleep deprived and possibly still recovering from and reliving birth trauma, welcoming a new baby can seem like a crazy rollercoaster!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s the problem? Why does the subject of breastfeeding evoke so much tension, frustration, anger, disappointment, passion, loneliness, abandonment, insecurity and guilt? Why are so many women quick to defend themselves and not simply unapologetically declare their choice?! Who are they fighting against? Why are so many made to feel selfish and inadequate, why do we still not understand the true mechanics behind breast feeding? And why are we so obsessed with ‘normal’ we ignore the possibility that we each have a new normal and babies don’t just automatically fit predefined routines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a documentary on Dispatches about Breastfeeding presented by Kate Quilton. It was very informative about the benefits of breastfeeding, giving a balanced and non emotive view of the nutrients provided by both breastfeeding and formula feeding and essentially highlighting some of the reasons for the UKs decline in breastfeeding. It is now among one of the 10 countries in the world with the lowest breastfeeding rates, according to UNICEF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are libraries of information out there preaching about the various benefits and many women proudly breastfeed their babies for as long as they can. And yet &lt;strong&gt;so many feel let down by a system that promotes breastfeeding but doesn’t provide sufficient support to enable women to be successful at it.&lt;/strong&gt; Aside from medical reasons that prevent a woman from being able to breastfeed and those that choose formula as a preference, a woman who chooses to breastfeed needs support. Support from professionals, support from loved ones and support from the community.
Professionals who declare that breast is best should make it their duty to equip women with the tools, support and education women need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loved ones need to provide moral support, love, patience and non judgmental encouragement.
The community as a whole needs to change its perception on breastfeeding and stop insisting mothers should breastfeed in toilets and other unsavoury corners! Would you eat your sushi in the toilet?!
When I had my son, I had read a little about breastfeeding in one of the hundreds of prenatal leaflets given to me during pregnancy. I had seen women breastfeed but hadn’t given the reality a second thought. I attended an NCT class which bought me the best mummy friends I could ask for and during which I gained about 95% of my life’s baby knowledge crammed into a few days of eye watering, informative details. We were even introduced to a lactation specialist and given a breastfeeding hotline to call if we had any questions! Brilliant! I swiftly removed Nandos from my speed dial list and replaced it with my new breast friend! Aptly I called her the Milk Nurse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son was a natural, no latching issues thankfully, no tongue tie to contend with and literally shuffled around until he found my breast as soon as he came out of the womb! Hurray, that was quick! And scarily easy….no no no…..how wrong I was…..
I spent days and nights in pain as he fed. Reciting the words of my Milk Nurse in my head — &lt;strong&gt;‘if it hurts you’re doing something wrong’&lt;/strong&gt; I changed position, changed breast, got him to re-latch and no joy. It still hurt like someone was piercing my nipple with a hot iron. I persevered and finally got an appointment to see a midwife who showed me that he was incorrectly latched on to my breast. Oh….ok….silly me(!) Not enough areola in his gob! But by now my nipples were already raw with pain, and newborns have a relentless feeding pattern, giving your body no time to heal! So &lt;strong&gt;I slapped on the nipple cream like my life depended on it&lt;/strong&gt; and just hoped it would be ok. It got easier, and my high pain threshold combined with blind determination got me through….just. But memories of those isolating moments bring tears to my eyes and I can completely empathise with any woman who says &lt;strong&gt;‘enough is enough’&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those small hours of the morning when you’re trying to feed a hungry baby, exhausted and in pain with no one to help, advise or encourage you a decision has to be made. And &lt;strong&gt;choosing your sanity isn’t selfish&lt;/strong&gt; or weak, or pathetic, or whimsical, it’s essential to being a healthy, good mother. There isn’t enough support to ensure that women are not faced with the pressure of choosing to ‘give up’. I suspect more women would feel less bitter about the whole breastfeeding conversation if their decision was truly a choice, rather than feeling defeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those who breastfeed with ease, or who were able to establish a pattern and push through the initial discomfort, the hurdles don’t stop there. Many women are faced with a society that all too often frowns upon breastfeeding in public, judging them for publicly displaying their assets, as if their primary goal is to become the latest flasher on Clapham Common or compete with Kim Kardashian. Many of those who continue on the breast feeding path, are put off by public judgment, passive aggressive demands to ‘cover up’, disapproving eyes, insensitive requests to nurse in the toilet or sit where you can’t be seen, and quit before they are ready to. All because Mr Jones’ suppressed sexual frustrations and prudish background are confusing him with the nurture of a mother. Nothing wrong with abit of pent up frustration Mr Jones and no one scorns a private prude, but keep that archaic nonsense to yourself, and let a mama feed her baby in peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately there is no question that &lt;strong&gt;fed is best!&lt;/strong&gt; I don’t think anyone could really argue with that. The issue in my mind is that we as women want to give our children the best start in life and if health professionals say that this happens to be breast milk, most do everything within their power to make this happen. The problem is, it’s seldom that straightforward. Health concerns, low milk supply, early return to work and a barrage of other obstacles including lack of support and low confidence often mean breastfeeding just doesn’t happen for a lot of women. It’s this I wanted to really discuss, why are we so emotionally affected by someone telling us that breast is best and if for whatever reason we are unable or choose not to follow this route, we feel guilty, hostile towards those that even suggest that we are inadequate parents and vulnerable about our ability to provide for our child? Why do we care that breast is best? It’s a fact, but formula still provides a baby with nutrients that it needs for healthy development, so let’s change the narrative, stop shaming women who can’t or won’t and start supporting all mothers to grow healthy, happy babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women give themselves such a hard time about everything, and dissect every aspect of parenthood comparing notes with other parents, following advice from forums, friends and foes. Any increase in breast feeding has to be &lt;strong&gt;community inspired, community driven and community led.&lt;/strong&gt; It needs to remove the negative badge it’s adorned for too long and remodel itself in the current environment it’s supposed to serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We all need to support each other more, lean into the sisterhood, however you feed your beautiful being we’re all on the same side of knackered.&lt;/strong&gt; Shed the guilt. Empower yourself with the facts about breastfeeding. Scream for help until you’re heard without delay. Be confident in whatever feeding choice you make. And do what gives you peace and keeps you and your baby well and nourished. Fed is truly best, and all women need support no matter how they choose to feed their baby. What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Make Me a Priority</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Life</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>Priorities</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Parenting Advice</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/images/feature_hu275acd3f4b5175c7aad91a0d8cf92ccb_183840_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>I’m wearing sandals with ashy feet, an unironed t-shirt with a food stain or four, stretchy hareem pants and a multi coloured headscarf wrapped around sprouting doo doo plaits….</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I’m wearing sandals with ashy feet, an unironed t-shirt with a food stain or four, stretchy hareem pants and a multi coloured headscarf wrapped around sprouting doo doo plaits….and yes I left my house looking like this. Without even a second thought. Without even considering that I may be SEEN by someone who’s not partially sighted AND colourblind. And yes I still continued, offending my former self and every self confessed diva who looks upon me either with sympathy, disgust or that knowing smile from a fellow mum who’s also lost her mojo!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I literally don’t even know when this happened?! When did I stop caring what I look like, and put my sons needs before my hygiene and self appearance!?? What has happened to me?? I don’t even bother to look at myself in the mirror some days! Clothed and brushed teeth is the bar that I’ve maintained for awhile. And I’m not feeling it!!!! I caught myself in the mirror the other day, on a nursery day when I had a few hours for myself. The recent heatwave prompted me to look for a skirt that I could still shoe horn my pregnant frame in to….until I saw my legs and was high kicked in the face by chewbacca’s not so distant relative. My 20 year old self would have slapped me and told me to get reacquainted with hair removal fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m trying to find my way back to me, at the very least a groomed version! Perhaps not to the twice weekly manicures but to something that resembles the girl who would proudly sip cocktails on a roof terrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motherhood is beautiful and all consuming, and quite possibly my hardest chapter so far, but I wouldn’t change it for anything. I want to live a life I’m proud of, I want to be who I want to be and create a life I don’t always need a vacation from. I’m not on the road to martyrdom, I literally just haven’t quite worked out how to do it all and still be me. But I’m getting there. And understanding more and more that a happy me is a better me. Be good to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>