<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Tinu Alikor</title>
    <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Tinu Alikor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mumgry</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG</url>
          
            <title>Mumgry</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Have you heard of the term Hangry? It’s a clever portmanteau of hungry and angry, and an adjective that describes being irritable due to hunger, a term to describe that feeling you get when you’re hungry, and about to knock someone the hell out if you don’t get some food fast!
Well I’ve felt like that often, so I’m known for carrying around snacks and planning my life around where the nearest eatery is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Valentines Day</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Happy Valentines Day</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Yesterday I found out the hard way that the Swiss don’t do Valentines Day. I walked around a local shopping centre with the kids (first time in months) hoping to purchase a card, and not a fluffy teddy or heart shaped balloon in sight. Strange? Refreshing? I’m not entirely sure how I feel about that. I don’t care enough about Valentines Day to really have an opinion. Maybe that in itself speaks volumes….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Lippy 2019</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/images/tinu-alikor-lippy-pout_huac9749c397c0ad2fd8521412fe21b4f3_250809_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Get Lippy 2019</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/get-lippy-2019/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not great at following trends! I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I&amp;rsquo;m individual and try not to get swept away with fads and to be honest I&amp;rsquo;m about as &amp;lsquo;on trend&amp;rsquo; as John McCririck or a stale Jaffa cake. Now I&amp;rsquo;m 35 I care less what people think, I wear what I like , rarely wear make up and generally enjoying the not giving a damn phase. Spending time with my family, sharing, loving, connecting rather than succumbing to the narcism that is gripping the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/two-happy-kids_hu8bd73f293d04bbc53f400c406222be67_1908490_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Now I&amp;rsquo;ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?! I remember before my daughter was born jokingly but seriously asking people with multiple kids for tips on how to cope with two kids….no one responded. At first I thought, that&amp;rsquo;s just rude really…a girl just needs some advice, and now I realise that everyone is full on blagging their way through parenthood and no one can offer any tips because some of their survival techniques are unconventional or tailor made to suit them, or they&amp;rsquo;re simply just surviving!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten ways to improve confidence</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/images/tinuwaterfall_hu695ff7802b6ba961a8ee1db686c129f9_625029_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Ten ways to improve confidence</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/ten-ways-to-improve-confidence/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Follow my blog with Bloglovin
1. Believe in yourself You need to be your own cheerleader. Focus on the things you&amp;rsquo;re great at. Trust your own abilities. Remember the things you have achieved so far and use those memories as a foundation for the things you&amp;rsquo;d like to achieve in the future. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to be heard. Your opinion is valuable and counts 2. Silence your inner critic Self deprecation needs to stop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroin, carbs and a stable pay cheque</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/images/tinu-face_hu058d36ce7413b766d4db553bcb7c1fc5_186724_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Heroin, carbs and a stable pay cheque</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/heroin-carbs-and-a-stable-pay-cheque/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>“The three biggest addictions are heroin, carbs, and a stable pay cheque” according to Nassim Taleb.
I’m inclined to believe him! I’m presently trying to get a grip of two of these addictions…Thankfully I have never battled with heroin, the closest I’ve got to substance abuse has been a tea addiction! I didn’t even realise I was addicted until I decided to give it up for Lent….and the hulk appeared every morning instead of the amenable me….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Sonshine</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/images/sunshine_hu771a7050c8f7b1b9bbb501e2e72be7d1_2307142_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>My Sonshine</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/my-sonshine/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>This one. This brilliant, energetic, bold, adventurous, talkative, loving, mischievous boy with endless curiosity is my biggest test. He’s the child you’ll find in the sandpit after a huge downfall of rain playing snow angels in the mud. He’s the one that could find puddles in the desert and could give a puma a run for its money. The one you’ll find moving furniture to scale the table, or pulling the blender out of the cupboard to see how it works, or trying to hang from the window ledge so he can see the bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolutely Fabulous</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 05:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/images/babies_hu9254ecaebb10959bdf27619441dc4657_438742_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG</url>
          
            <title>Absolutely Fabulous</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/absolutely-fabulous/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>I saw a post the other day that made me laugh…
“None of this new year new me bollocks, last year I was fabulous and next year I will be fabulous!”
Very amusing, and vaguely relevant to me, I’m fabulous some days, possibly two days a week, but honestly, I think it’s BS. Maybe not a new me, but a better version of myself wouldn’t hurt, perhaps like a software update!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be the change you want to see</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 06:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/images/olivia_dress_huabea8a00064a6ed828fbd5dd5f6c4da6_893215_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Be the change you want to see</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/be-the-change-you-want-to-see/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>I gave birth to my daughter not so long ago…and my life changed. All of a sudden I feel the need to be the woman my daughter will respect and look up to. A woman of integrity and good standing. A woman she’d be proud to call her mum. I didn’t quite feel the same when I had my son. Yes, I felt the basic maternal pull of wanting to be a good role model and parent, and keep him happy and create a nurturing loving environment for him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adulting</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 16:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Adulting</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Last year I became a member of a club that no one wants to talk about. A club in which membership is one of the most painful experiences most will face in their lifetime and all are pretty much powerless to avoid. We found out we were expecting a baby in December 2017, excited and full of hope and expectation we celebrated.
 As tradition encourages we were hoping to share our good news after the first scan at 12 weeks….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Do…</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/images/feature_hu37a066ceaef65215736dc63427c4303c_1755211_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>I Do…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>I thought I’d introduce my other half properly as I’m sure he’ll be featuring in some of my blogs and it’s only polite to give you a brief low down on the man that is the pepper in my stew, custard on my crumble, my Mr Big.
So I started this post initially wanting to introduce our benetton backgrounds but then it struck me that I’m not adequately equipped to really do it justice as we were both born and bred in London and pie and mash are in our veins with a hint of egusi and flying fish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too much choice?</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/too-much-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 07:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/too-much-choice/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/too-much-choice/images/feature_huf3d7d8729afc8d08aa5a2d237dcd9a56_2987805_790x0_resize_box_2.png</url>
          
            <title>Too much choice?</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/too-much-choice/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Are we the generation that just have too many options??
One where we dismiss potential partners with a quick flick, could easily go on a date a day if our schedules permitted and take pride in our mantra of choosing not to ‘settle’. Now what exactly is settling??
To settle actually means to resolve or reach an agreement about (an argument or problem). But in this modern age when we refer to settling in a relationship context we deem it to be negative and unsatisfactory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreams Don’t Expire</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 07:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/images/feature_hud963163ef20da0887dddfc3ae1a095c2_492555_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Dreams Don’t Expire</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/dreams-dont-expire/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>When I was 8 if you had asked me what I want to be when I grow up my answers were as colourful as my prized Care Bear lunch box…pilot, lawyer, doctor, painter, architect, ballerina, astronaut, UN leader, journalist, news reader, butcher, baker, candlestick maker…and I truly believed I could be any one of those on any given day, and perhaps moonlight in one I was less keen on in the evenings!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail Like a Boss</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/images/feature_hu922ba9b63a8233a3c6308bd992b0acb5_4597736_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Fail Like a Boss</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/fail-like-a-boss/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>I was sent an email last week congratulating me on my sons acceptance into Forest School. Apparently he has passed his probationary period! Yay!! ! But a probationary period….so he can pass or fail? Eurgh…please tell me they’re not starting this already! He’s 2!!! He can’t fail!! Surely?
I then began questioning myself and why I took issue with the suggestion of a probationary period and the thought that my child may be rejected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love yourself</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/images/feature_hu8bc1fff2af24458dba8e5250014f41bc_145314_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Love yourself</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/love-yourself/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>This blog is for everyone who contacted me in private or public about one of my previous blogs ‘ Freedom’. I was brought to tears by you reaching out to share your stories with me. I’m touched by the strength in your daily struggles and the memories that you hold on to. I’m inspired by you. Thank you for reaching out, thank you for sharing. Vulnerability is not weakness, it’s powerful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We’re all equal in the sky…</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/images/feature_hu9ac72fe668a507003fd0f28db21e8729_1160980_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG</url>
          
            <title>We’re all equal in the sky…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/were-all-equal-in-the-sky/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>So my most recent flight from Switzerland to London has taken me awhile to recover from. I am a seasoned traveller who isn’t easily flustered. I plan my route, prepare my luggage and get going! Saying this being a black female, with mobility issues travelling with a toddler whilst pregnant puts a slightly different spin on the situation and its this I’d like to share.
I’m always trying to do it all, juggling, balancing plates on my head whilst spinning wheels in my palms…I’m the consummate multi tasker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Freedom</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Growing up without a father I always wondered what happened between my parents. In my naivety and innocence I questioned what part I had played in my father leaving before I was 3, and what I could have done to get him to stay.
 At 16 I went in search for a father who had not responded to any of my phone calls or letters. Who had never contacted me on my birthday or even when he was told I had been undergoing a series of potentially life threatening surgeries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say Yes</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/images/feature_hu2dbd46e9711a6edef913096b4e75ada8_231367_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Say Yes</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>New Beginnings</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Today, I’m diving head first into my blog. I’m just as clueless about the start as i am about the finish. But here I am hoping to share my journey with you and express myself creatively, prompted by change, displacement, fear, love, growth, freedom, happiness, adventure and an overwhelming feeling that this is what I’m meant to do….this is what I need to do, and for once it’s something just for me….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planned Boob Strikes Are Ok</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 09:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/images/feature_hu9975dff1fa10e7614cba043485ce311b_267554_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Planned Boob Strikes Are Ok</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/planned-boob-strikes-are-ok/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>Emergency ones are not! In other words, choosing not to breastfeed is ok. Being forced to stop is not!
It’s National Breast-Feeding week!! Let’s talk food….or should I say food provision…..or should I say shame ridden, guilt provoking, nurturing, painful, stressful, bonding, life sustaining breastfeeding!
It can be all of these things and more, it is truly a personal experience and can be so different for each individual, provoking so many conflicting and often overwhelming emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Me a Priority</title>
      <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</guid>
        
        
        <image>

        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/images/feature_hu275acd3f4b5175c7aad91a0d8cf92ccb_183840_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
          
            <title>Make Me a Priority</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/make-me-a-priority/</link>
        </image>
          
      <description>I’m wearing sandals with ashy feet, an unironed t-shirt with a food stain or four, stretchy hareem pants and a multi coloured headscarf wrapped around sprouting doo doo plaits….and yes I left my house looking like this. Without even a second thought. Without even considering that I may be SEEN by someone who’s not partially sighted AND colourblind. And yes I still continued, offending my former self and every self confessed diva who looks upon me either with sympathy, disgust or that knowing smile from a fellow mum who’s also lost her mojo!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>