<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
    <title>Family on Tinu Alikor</title>
    <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/family/</link>
        <language>en-EN</language>
        <description>Description of your feed</description>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/family/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

        
        
            <item>
            <title>Happy Valentines Day</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
            <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="900" height="600"
                  url="https://www.yoursite.com/img/" />
            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>Yesterday I found out the hard way that the Swiss don’t do Valentines Day.  I walked around a local shopping centre with the kids (first time in months) hoping to purchase a card, and not a fluffy teddy or heart shaped balloon in sight.  Strange? Refreshing? I’m not entirely sure how I feel about that. I don’t care enough about Valentines Day to really have an opinion.  Maybe that in itself speaks volumes…. Despite my nonchalance, I trudged through the annoyingly brightly lit shopping mall like someone who hasn’t seen daylight for some substantial time.  A journey that should’ve taken me a maximum of 15 minutes ended up being an afternoon of stopping, eating, playing with random chairs, jumping off said random chairs, eating some more, nappy changes, breastfeeding and a small but unwelcome tantrum about Brexit… actually it was about nothing obviously.</p>

<p>I eventually found a semi appropriate card.  Something about love on the front, in English, no text inside. Bish bash bosh!  Thanks, that’ll do!  To be honest, I wasn’t going to buy a card this year, I’ve been feeling like I’ve been dragged through a hedge backwards for some time and the exhaustion and relentless schedule is starting to take it’s toll.  Do you ever feel like you’re sleep walking?  Fire fighting, satisfying a conveyor belt of demands and it just doesn’t stop.  I’ve been shouty, impatient mum for a few days now.  Zero patience with a toddler is like putting washing up liquid in a car engine.  So my frame of mind at present has no room for love hearts and cuddly toys.  A priceless present for me would be an uninterrupted bath with my favourite scented candles…. somehow I’ll make this happen!</p>

<p>Love is love even when he doesn’t take the bins out, when he sleeps through your sleepless nights with the baby and is still apparently knackered.  Love is pushing through the grey matter that fogs your mind and relationship  when the mental load is taking its toll and for once you just wish you didn’t feel like you do it all in military style, forward thinking, back thinking, planning, executing, packing, cooking, cleaning, feeding. Love is sharing the load, being equally knackered, dribbling with exhaustion together in harmony. We love every day, silently over the weetabix,  patiently during laundry days, loudly in the supermarket.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>Whatever your situation, love begins with you. Love you, appreciate you.  Buy yourself flowers, get a new frock, get some whipped cream and marshmallows on that hot chocolate, crack open a bottle of red, enjoy a yummy plate, binge on a box set, have a bubble bath, book a mani pedi, go for a nice walk, do whatever makes your heart sing and your mind at peace.  You are loved, you are cherished, you are worthy of love. Whatever you do today, show some love, appreciate the one you take for granted daily, and most importantly, do something you love and love yourself.</p>

<p>Please add a comment below, like, share and follow me on instagram, twitter and facebook.</p>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Mum of two survival tips</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
            <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="900" height="600"
                  url="https://www.yoursite.com/img/" />
            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<p>Now I&rsquo;ve got your attention… did you think I actually had tips…does anyone?! I remember before my daughter was born jokingly but seriously asking people with multiple kids for tips on how to cope with two kids….no one responded. At first I thought, that&rsquo;s just rude really…a girl just needs some advice, and now I realise that everyone is full on blagging their way through parenthood and no one can offer any tips because some of their survival techniques are unconventional or tailor made to suit them, or they&rsquo;re simply just surviving!! Whatever your &lsquo;methods&rsquo; I salute and chest bump you with passion.  It ain&rsquo;t easy!</p>

<p>Well…. I am three months into having two children, just when I thought I had got the shower routine mastered, got my hair out of doo doo plaits and ditched the stained hareem pants, I go and have another child! This new addition was never going to propel me into more self loving and uninterrupted &lsquo;me time&rsquo;. I now have even less time, am even more exhausted… if that&rsquo;s even possible and actually considered sitting in my double pram whilst the toddler was at nursery, pulling the hood down and having a kip next to the baby the other day… I was that tired. </p>

<p>Whilst I have no real tips as such there are a few things that I wish I had known and that have helped me &lsquo;survive&rsquo; so far. So I&rsquo;m sharing in the hope that even one parent out there receives some light and love from this post, even if it is just a warm virtual bear hug reminding you, you&rsquo;re not alone! We&rsquo;re all just fumbling around in the dark hoping not to cause any irreparable damage! And we are essentially doing great, we just need reminding of that occasionally! Please share things that work for you too! Every little helps!!</p>

<p>So here it is, my top ten suggestions:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Get a baby carrier - I never used one with my first child. I never really needed to! I had the luxury of not having to regularly multi task whilst holding my son, so although I had one only used it a handful of occasions. When you have more than one child, a baby carrier is like air! Fundamental!!! You&rsquo;ll need your hands free to do stuff, tend to your other child, household stuff, whatever, but in those early stages casually sitting breastfeeding or cuddling your newborn for hours isn&rsquo;t always possible. Look for your nearest sling library and try before you buy!</p></li>

<li><p>Get a decent bag. Notice I didn&rsquo;t say baby bag. If you find a fit for purpose baby bag that works for you then run with it, but you really need a bag that&rsquo;s big enough for what you need, accessible, and can be attached or hung on your pushchair with ease. If you buy a large bag you can purchase inserts for each child to differentiate between their things, </p></li>

<li><p>Always carry a water bottle and food (not just for the kids!) - rehydrate and feed yourself too!! Whether you&rsquo;re breastfeeding or not, a fuelled mummy is a happier mummy. Water is essential especially when breastfeeding. I remember getting headaches in the first few weeks of my daughters birth when I was dehydrated. Easy resolution! Drink!! And I don&rsquo;t mean cocktails! As for eating, I had a habit of just eating in between meals, eating my sons left over food and sometimes being too tired to have my own meal once the kids are sleeping. This isn&rsquo;t sustainable and you need to make sure you&rsquo;re looking after yourself. So batch cook if it&rsquo;s easier.</p></li>

<li><p>Don&rsquo;t be afraid to ask for help. My husband and I have always done everything ourselves due to geography, which has put a strain on us both as we seldom get time out. But now we have 2 children we actively welcome opportunities to get help and in the first 2 months of my daughters life I received help with my toddler to ensure he was stimulated daily, happy and engaged. Asking for help from your loved ones is not a sign of weakness or inability to cope. It really does take a village to raise a child. Put your village on speed dial and get them involved!</p></li>

<li><p>Do your best to schedule your kids naps as close together as possible. Nap time is sacred. My son no longer naps. I know, I cried about it too, but if he did I would be taking this on board! Try and be consistent with bedtime too. Children love routine and once they know what to expect you&rsquo;ll have an easier time getting them to comply. </p></li>

<li><p>Find distraction techniques for the older child. Have quick go-to toys and games that your child loves to keep him/her occupied if you need to attend to the younger one. </p></li>

<li><p>Get out of the house! Yes I know it sounds like a logistical nightmare and it can be the first couple of times when you work out what works for you, and literally &lsquo;how&rsquo; to get you all clothed and fed to leave the house! But… once you get past the chaos, it will feel like you&rsquo;ve reached nirvana! The fresh air and change of scenery will do wonders for your mental health and the children will feel better too! 
<figure>
    <img src="/blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/mum-of-two-survival-tips/images/family-travel-taxi_hu59715df773a330f67e52d31a80546973_599068_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure></p></li>

<li><p>Sleep when they sleep. If you manage to get both kids sleeping simultaneously….grab your duvet and get involved! The washing, cooking, laundry, phonecall, can wait!</p></li>

<li><p>Date night. In-between feeds, nappy changes, projectile vomit, nursery runs and reruns of paw patrol remember how it all began and make some time for the love that started it all.</p></li>

<li><p>Make time for yourself at least once a week. Even if it&rsquo;s just half an hour of uninterruption. Do something you enjoy! Read a book, paint your nails, have a hot bath, go to the cinema, go for a swim. Whatever floats your boat, make time for it. You will always have lots to do, the list is endless, but if you make time for the things that are important to you and make them a priority rather than a &lsquo;nice to have&rsquo; the rest of your time will be filled with the daily responsibilities and you&rsquo;ll feel better for the little moments you made time for.</p></li>
</ol>

<p><a href="https://www.bloglovin.com/blog/19788609/?claim=e5x9w3qxhr6">Follow my blog with Bloglovin</a></p>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>I Do…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
            <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="900" height="600"
                  url="https://www.yoursite.com/img/" />
            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<p>I thought I’d introduce my other half properly as I’m sure he’ll be featuring in some of my blogs and it’s only polite to give you a brief low down on the man that is the pepper in my stew, custard on my crumble, my Mr Big.</p>

<p>So I started this post initially wanting to introduce our benetton backgrounds but then it struck me that I’m not adequately equipped to really do it justice as we were both born and bred in London and pie and mash are in our veins with a hint of egusi and flying fish. But diverse we are, my parents are Nigerian and husband’s background stems from Barbados, Nigeria and the UK. Despite this eclectic mix which we hold with pride, we’re both fundamentally Londoners, the melting pot that is the big smoke. And currently global citizens of the world.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>It just happens that my husband Madu spent the first three years of his life in a small village in Nigeria with his parents. The rest of his formative years were in London, but somehow he’s managed to embody the essence of a southern Nigerian man with little effort! Definitely more nature than nurture! An interesting mix of genetic tendencies and perhaps a desire to belong. It’s funny it’s difficult to define a Londoners cultural identity, it can be a blur of complimentary or sometimes opposing ideals, but whatever the composition we love it.</p>

<p>We met online and have been literally inseparable since our first date in Mango Room. From surprise evenings out in West End to an impromptu week long road trip adventure on one of my work stints in Jamaica. Six months after meeting he quit his job and flew out to propose…we haven’t looked back since.</p>

<p>Yesterday my blender gave up the ghost and I almost cried, it’s been good to me and lasted more years than I care to admit, but owning a blender is synonymous with being a Nigerian. And now I’m in a culinary abyss without it. My other concern is that if I don’t replace it sharpish, so close to Christmas I’ll end up with a new blender from Madu as a present…romance isn’t dead, he’s just pragmatic and Igbo(!) At least that’s what he tells me!</p>

<p>He’s a loving, gentle, technology obsessed man who prides himself on being current, always aims for the best and can negotiate a pay rise with slick aptitude and unrivalled confidence. He taught me to love me more, believes in me when I don’t believe in myself. And encourages me to pursue my dreams. That’s a pretty basic but beautiful asset to have, someone who’s always in your corner.</p>

<p>On the flip side, his confidence borders arrogance at times, he sometimes has a problem with authority, is very opinionated and isn’t scared of being fired for what he believes in. His level of maturity needs to step up a few notches as risks don’t just affect him anymore, and we’re no longer in batchelor territory. Every decision impacts his family. Unemployment is not a word I enjoy discussing over my spag bog, but it’s a conversation I’ve had with him one too many times. But because he is who he is, he knows he can get another well paid job relatively easily….but is that the point? Marriage puts you in situations that you just can’t run away from. It forces you to face another persons bad habits and shortcomings head on. There is nowhere to hide. And once you have children the dynamic further alters as you do all that you can to put them first and maintain a stable loving environment. Being told by your husband that he’s job hunting in your 34th week of pregnancy isn’t fun. But apparently it’s all going to be ok.</p>

<p>Marriage is a complex fusion of hearts and minds. Where Mars and Venus align and two attempt to become one. Where perfectionist Polly is confronted with dirty Daves dirty laundry scattered in obscure parts of the home, often next to the laundry basket….strangely it never quite makes it in. Where unintentional blindness is actually a serious condition. Where multi-tasking is apparently a female attribute and replacing the bog roll is a job that requires deep commitment. A friend of mine once said to me that people often forget that marriage is a journey not a destination. And that’s spot on. It’s a work in progress, a marathon, not a sprint. I’m lucky to have married my best friend, as inscribed on his wedding band, my ride or die.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>If people were honest about how tough marriage can be, many would probably avoid it or feel less defeated if it eludes them. Marriage is beautiful and life changing and all consuming, and frustrating and exposing. It’s choosing someone to be vulnerable with, to laugh with and ride the waves of life with. It truly is in sickness and in health, through the good times and the bad. It takes resilience, patience, forgiveness and a sense of humour you didn’t know you had.</p>

<p>I don’t remember the last time I went to the toilet alone. And that’s not just my two year old who barges in on me. Lock the door I hear you say! Yes I would if we didn’t have those annoying child safety door stoppers to stop my son from losing precious digits in the hinges! But seriously…can a girl just go in peace?!</p>

<p>If I had any dignity when we got hitched, and I’d like to think I did! It soon evaporated during child birth. A wonderful, eye watering, life altering experience that stripped me back to my core. Madu was an awesome birth partner, attentive and supportive, although confronting me with photographic and video evidence of the birth of our son without my knowledge almost got him fired, apprentice style! We’ve just been blessed with the arrival of our beautiful daughter, here’s my husband having an obviously much needed rest after I’ve given birth(!)</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>I had a rule when dating years ago, as soon as I liked someone enough to grace them with a second or third date I would ensure I orchestrated a dress down meet up where I wore minimal make up, casual clothes and my hair was in it’s original afro form. I’d do this occasionally if we continued to date and I hadn’t frightened them with my Erykah Badu vibes! I wish more women did this, and they would perhaps be more likely to attract partners that are less superficial! Waking up to put on a full face before your partner wakes up is crazy behaviour. I’d love to hear from women who actually keep this up!</p>

<p>This evening my husband wouldn’t let me finish a sentence and just kept interrupting me. I found it rude and annoying, so as he did it repeatedly I just stopped talking, as clearly he’d prefer to hear the sound of his own voice, so why spoil it for him(!) Then he says I’m harping on about him interrupting me, and just get on with what I have to say….my response to that contains many expletives none of which are suitable for print….marriage gives you a level of patience you didn’t know was possible. And teaches you to forgive even when the other person doesn’t deserve it. It pushes you to prioritise your union and count to a million before you bail. It prevents you from throwing heavy objects at your husband when he jokes about saving money by manually expressing milk rather than buying one of those “over rated pumps”. Marriage is for the mature, the selfless and the committed. Loving someone without condition, loving someone who ate the last import only hobnob and cunningly and perhaps cruelly left the packaging in the cupboard, so you had no idea they were even finished….yes people do that!</p>

<p>Marriage is full of light and wonder, comfort and hope. It has renewed my faith in humanity and given me joy beyond measure and two beautiful children. I’m still understanding what being a wife means, this year I asked for a wife for Christmas…everyone needs a good one! We’re enjoying the learning and the journey. so that’s us the Alikor’s, hopelessly devoted and grateful to have each other.</p>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Freedom</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
            <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="900" height="600"
                  url="https://www.yoursite.com/img/" />
            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<p>Growing up without a father I always wondered what happened between my parents. In my naivety and innocence I questioned what part I had played in my father leaving before I was 3, and what I could have done to get him to stay.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom/images/feature_hu3c1d8d539fb678a0fa65a44ce0648c8c_222210_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>At 16 I went in search for a father who had not responded to any of my phone calls or letters. Who had never contacted me on my birthday or even when he was told I had been undergoing a series of potentially life threatening surgeries. He had stayed distant and unconcerned like someone who had left an old umbrella on the tube. I could envisage myself as one of those girls with ‘daddy issues’ and wanted to try and change ‘My Story’, I didn’t want this abandonment to define me, if that was even possible…so armed with a microphone, digital recorder and BBC Radio 4 producer I went looking for a man who wasn’t lost. His address hadn’t changed in 20 years, but in my eyes he was lost. And he had lost. I found him in Lagos, Nigeria and being the Jeremy Paxman I am asked him everything I’d ever wanted to know in concise detail. But nothing really made sense, could it ever? I’m not sure I prepared myself for less than satisfactory responses. But what could he possibly have said that would make it all ok.</p>

<p>If I could write a letter to my younger self, I’d tell her, you did nothing wrong. That adults sometimes make decisions that affect children negatively in response to their own emotional and physical needs. I would tell her that sometimes life happens in such a way that circumstances create a gulf that cannot be breached, and people sometimes can not find the strength, maturity or motivation to bridge that distance. That sometimes relationships don’t work, and children are collateral damage. Created with love or lust, but sometimes a painful afterthought in the transaction that is separation. Sometimes differences can’t be embraced. Sometimes destiny can’t be diverted. Sometimes people just can’t forgive and forget.</p>

<p>I would tell my younger self, that parents are just human, flawed and facing the journey of life with an incomprehensible and selfish desire to be happy, at whatever cost, often with an out of date road map or a faulty sat nav. Parents do their best at the best of times and scrape through with a could do better, or simply just shouldn’t have bothered at their worst. I would tell her, you are enough. You did nothing wrong. The family he chose to raise instead of you did not win. His choice illustrates his short sightedness, his inability to responsibly find a way to love you all. His weakness, not yours, his failures not yours. And for every tear you have shed the pool of hope has grown. It’s made you stronger, more thoughtful, resilient and caring. Your story isn’t a guilty secret, it’s a beacon of hope. You have overcome adversity and shone through the fog, pursuing your dreams with courage. You can do anything you put your mind to. You can be anything you choose. Remember that those that helped create you are simple vessels and sometimes their part is fleeting and temporal. The day I found true forgiveness is the day I really became free. Free of the pain of not knowing, free of not understanding, free of the burden of unanswered questions.</p>

<p>My mum found a way to raise me alone and always praised my father. She created a home that was our normal, and ensured my perception of my father was always good. She told me stories of how they met, what a good man he was and how much he loved me. Maybe that was her way of coping too. The positive reinforcements despite the reality of his absence helped me to find forgiveness. And one day in my mid 20s he turned up sick and unannounced at the Euston concourse and came to find me. Too little too late, but a gesture of love nonetheless.</p>

<p>Now that I have a child of my own, everything has changed. My mental and emotional freedom mean so much more, as I’m conscious of how my behaviour and insecurities could impact my child. I understand the flawed behaviour of parents as I see my own daily, but now even more cannot comprehend the choice to abandon a child. Finding that freedom and release of negativity in your memories is a remarkable step to healing, no matter what has caused your pain. It’s all part of your journey and everyone’s path is different. Just be open to freeing your mind.</p>

<p>Forgiveness is personal and painful, but liberating and essential. It doesn’t mean forgetting, it just means you’ve let go….and that is awe inspiring and powerful, and uplifting, and the best gift you can give yourself. Try it….you’ve got nothing to lose and freedom to gain.</p>

<p>So whatever your situation, free yourself from the burden of holding on to pain that will only create wounds that can take a lifetime to heal. Let go of that bitterness, resentment, disappointment, regret, anger. Find somewhere to put it to rest. I hope you find peace.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom/images/swing_hue9c4453f921e719d47dd0c089d10d44c_288457_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Say Yes</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
            <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="900" height="600"
                  url="https://www.yoursite.com/img/" />
            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<p>We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it. It wasn’t on my bucket list of countries to visit, I’m not a big chocolate fan and my interest in cheese is variable. But move here we did, to the beauty that is Zurich, following some research and a passion to try something new, live unapologetically and say yes more!</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>My husband is like a used sales man who could sell a written off fiat punto as a limited edition collectors item. Not that I’m likening Zurich to a clapped out motor… more like high spec Range. So I was sold… changed my work contract to give me supplementary leave, sorted out all my boring admin and packed up our flat and crammed what I could in suitcases, storage and the rest just got trashed.</p>

<p>Scarily final, we arrived in a country I’d never even visited weeks after having surgery on my leg. I was still on crutches and struggled to push the pram and walk at the same time. But somehow I did. Physio at its best! We stayed in temporary accommodation for months! Small bedsit type apartments that I thought were better suited to a bachelor on a stag than a family of 3 attempting to set up home…note to self, ‘do not leave husband in charge of booking accommodation’. We applied for permanent apartments in the notoriously competitive Swiss housing market and were rejected countless times. Our housing applications read like arse kissing resumes, frustratingly detailed and intrusive, and yet still not good enough….blood anyone?</p>

<p>After months of sleeping on broken beds, showering with flip flops on and cooking pasta in someone else’s pot above my sons travel cot, I’d had enough. Having no fixed abode was not only stressful because of the size and lack of amenities, having an active toddler rattling around in a non baby friendly apartment hitting his head on every sharp edge available was eye watering. I couldn’t register for anything as we had no fixed abode, I was in nomadic limbo. I told my husband I was going home until we found somewhere to live that had a bath I could bathe our son in, and four hobs on the stove, and a freezer…yes I am that girl….</p>

<p>‘Home is wherever you hang your hat baby’….’as long as we’re together we’ll be happy’…”save your lyrics for R Kelly, call me when we’ve got somewhere to live babe….and I love you too”.</p>

<p>So I took my son back to London, gratefully returned to our bath and four hobs, and kept on the search for somewhere permanent in Switzerland. I did viewings via Facetime whilst my husband sauntered around the empty apartments showing me the layout, pretentiously wearing a suit to portray the ‘right image’… cue eye roll. Months later we were successful and finally got a break! We signed the contract and were given the keys to our first home in Switzerland! It didn’t tick all of my boxes but compromise is a large pill that must be swallowed fast when your options are limited!</p>

<p>Now we have a place to call home. Relieved and settled, I can now start to make connections with people and I have found my son a nursery and local activities. It’s taken us a year of blood sweat and tears, but we did it. There were times I wanted to give up. I questioned our assessment of the pros and cons and just wanted to be able to find my hair straighteners.</p>

<figure>
    <img src=""
    srcset=""
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>Switzerland is a beautiful country, designed for efficiency, and ideal for young families. It’s charm lies in exploring its breathtaking postcard landscapes and relaxed bubble of safety. The Swiss are reserved, non-confrontational and polite, and yet display an air of frost that ensures that after pleasant introductions you keep your distance. If you’re young free and single I think there are more exciting places to savour, and if you hate recycling I’d give it a wide berth! I have never spent so much time contemplating what to do with rubbish! And my cardboard folding skills are still not up to scratch. Yes they expect you to fold cardboard and tie it neatly in piles for collection on specific days….are you still awake!?</p>

<p>The expat community is large and welcoming, and embraces new comers with enthusiasm, helpful suggestions and friendly recommendations. Switzerland lives on Facebook groups and old barely functional websites. So if you’re craving taramasalata at 2am or need an acupuncturist with a clinic overlooking the lake, someone somewhere will kindly point you in the right direction! My husband enjoys his job and my son loves it here, now I just need to find my place.</p>

<p>Moving here has meant I’ve not been able to work, I’ve put my career on hold to raise our family and get us settled. I’ve been fiercely independent my whole life, the concept of being a housewife despite having a role made me question my worth, and left me feeling vulnerable and itching to do something. Is that what I really want to do? Is it a means to an end? Can I raise a family and still have a thriving career? How do I balance work and childcare? Can i return to my job? The hours were long, travel commitments can be unfavourable and will I be able to afford to work and pay for childcare?</p>

<p>Motherhood often forces you to reassess your choices, your career path and your dreams. Flexible working is no longer a buzz term, it’s something I really need to find, and make it work for me. It’s ok to want to fulfill your dreams and it’s ok to not know where to even begin. But it’s not ok to be riddled with regret and ‘what ifs’. I encourage you to join me in daring to dream, and live your life to it’s fullest potential. Live the best life for you…you are unique and beautiful for your situation. I’m looking for my passion, taking opportunities that arise and simply saying yes! Yes is where the adventure begins!</p>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>New Beginnings</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
            <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="900" height="600"
                  url="https://www.yoursite.com/img/" />
            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>Today, I’m diving head first into my blog. I’m just as clueless about the start as i am about the finish. But here I am hoping to share my journey with you and express myself creatively, prompted by change, displacement, fear, love, growth, freedom, happiness, adventure and an overwhelming feeling that this is what I’m meant to do….this is what I need to do, and for once it’s something just for me….between me and you.</p>

<p>So who am I??! Million dollar question! I’m a work in progress, an unfinished genuine article, curry without the mango chutney, tasty but missing that je ne sais quoi. My street cred expired with my last library card, circa 1999, RIP. My son of course will think I’m the coolest thing since Tupac and Biggy, I’m working on sustaining that.</p>

<p>I am human, direct, thoughtful, sensitive but resilient. unconfident at times but opinionated, seemingly quiet but fiery. I am a contradiction personified, my background is complex but simple, I bleed red just like everyone else, and my eyes give away my thoughts every time…just the way I like it. I won’t be taking up poker anytime soon.</p>

<p>Educated in a girls school, no interest in boys or girls for that matter until I was at university. Penises are my preference, relationships were a distant goal on my vague checklist of things I’d like to consider doing with my life. Just not that interested I guess or just busy. Tomboy extraordinaire with the scars to prove it turned princess with shin pads. Born and raised in a religious single parent home in London, my boundaries were clear and rarely contested. University catapulted me into a world I never knew existed. It was like releasing an amputated hungry dog amongst chickens. Restrained but ravenous. It gave me a taste of freedom that I had longed for, and I knew that I had to do everything within my power to maintain this light. For freedom is light. And that I did. Moved out of home a few years after returning from university and haven’t looked back since.</p>

<p>Born with a condition called scoliosis, and living with being different my whole life, I’ve learnt to celebrate my uniqueness, push through my insecurities and challenges and make sure ‘can’t’ is permanently removed from my vocabulary. There are so many things people didn’t expect of me, low expectations just fire me on to prove them all wrong. I can and will do anything I put my mind to. Nothing can stop me but me….and If I stop it’s a choice not a weakness. I’ve lived my life optimistically, hoping for the best, living for the best, seeing the best and having the best. Long may it continue.</p>

<p>I’ve been married for 3 years and have a son, and baby on the way. I currently live in Switzerland following a whirlwind romance (apparently), epic honeymoon and baptism of matrimonial fire. My husband is a diamond, he shines when I shine. He’s the epitome of a geeky Flinstone with a hint of Hackney swag. Think Sheldon with the flavour of Nottinghill Carnival. The perfect balance for me. We’ve been literally inseparable since the day we met. Nauseatingly loved up, opposite but cut from the same cloth. He brings balance to my life and loves me like no other.</p>

<p>So we Brexited and left Theresa to sort herself out and end this hockey cokey with the EU, whilst we enjoy the heidi hills and embark on an exciting adventure. It’s been a year since we took the plunge and left Saveloy for Swiss chocolate! And what a year it’s been!! A year of finding our rhythm, finding our place, finding us. An exciting and daunting mix of surprise and the unknown, celebration and grief. Perpetually lost in translation but surrounded by the safety of Swiss etiquette and morality. Moving country is not for the faint hearted. in fact moving country with a baby puts hairs on your chest. We love it here and yet occasionally miss the familiar hustle and bustle of home. Strangely it’s the food I really miss…can a girl just get an eggs benedict please….somewhere?!!! Feeling stronger, more capable, and simply grateful for life. Finding happiness on the way to where we want to be, we’re risk takers. Blessed with the passion and zest for life that motivates us to prefer trying than failing to try at all.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>So yes i currently live in beautiful Switzerland, billy not a lot of mates in the ex-pat community, all of a sudden I’m a professional turned housewife still looking for my inner Nigella to burst out. Struggling with finding a balance, still scratching my afro when filling out the occupation section of admin forms, but enjoying the beauty of the life I have with my best friend.</p>

<p>I’m the kind of girl who never really fit in, and stopped trying to a long time ago! Growing in confidence, perfecting my ability to give less of a shit what people think. Making my own rules and enjoying breaking them when needed. Setting my own standards. Creating my own manual. No idea what tomorrow holds but looking forward to you joining me, navigating it with integrity and fun. Looking for new interests, reviving old ones, cooking like a boss who really enjoys good food, with no time to make it! Window shopping online for my fashion fix, celebrating my natural curls and nervously looking forward to 3 becoming 4! Lets go!</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>