<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on Tinu Alikor</title>
    <link>http://tinualikor.com/tags/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on Tinu Alikor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:42:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tinualikor.com/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I Do…</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</guid>
      <description>I thought I’d introduce my other half properly as I’m sure he’ll be featuring in some of my blogs and it’s only polite to give you a brief low down on the man that is the pepper in my stew, custard on my crumble, my Mr Big.
So I started this post initially wanting to introduce our benetton backgrounds but then it struck me that I’m not adequately equipped to really do it justice as we were both born and bred in London and pie and mash are in our veins with a hint of egusi and flying fish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom/</guid>
      <description>Growing up without a father I always wondered what happened between my parents. In my naivety and innocence I questioned what part I had played in my father leaving before I was 3, and what I could have done to get him to stay.
 At 16 I went in search for a father who had not responded to any of my phone calls or letters. Who had never contacted me on my birthday or even when he was told I had been undergoing a series of potentially life threatening surgeries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say Yes</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</guid>
      <description>We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Today, I’m diving head first into my blog. I’m just as clueless about the start as i am about the finish. But here I am hoping to share my journey with you and express myself creatively, prompted by change, displacement, fear, love, growth, freedom, happiness, adventure and an overwhelming feeling that this is what I’m meant to do….this is what I need to do, and for once it’s something just for me….</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>