<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Marriage on Tinu Alikor</title>
        <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/marriage/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Marriage on Tinu Alikor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/marriage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Mumgry</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG</url>
                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790" 
                  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<p>Have you heard of the term <strong>Hangry</strong>? It’s a clever portmanteau of hungry and angry, and an adjective that describes being irritable due to hunger, a term to describe that feeling you get when you’re hungry, and about to knock someone the hell out if you don’t get some food fast!</p>

<p>Well I’ve felt like that often, so I’m known for carrying around snacks and planning my life around where the nearest eatery is. I can pretty much describe anywhere I’ve been in the world in relation to good food. Sorry not sorry. I hate being hungry and am blessed to live comfortably enough to never have to experience this feeling unless I’m caught out somewhere remote or just lose track of time and there isn’t a drive through in sight. I’m a self confessed hangry person. Like I need food and am just distracted by it’s absence to the point of vexness, so I just don’t go there and prepare like a girl scout as it’s not a pretty site!</p>

<p>I’d like to think I’m pretty level headed and don’t have any known conditions that affect my ability to respond proportionately to situations. I’m rational, logical, don’t suffer fools much but I’m generally patient…ish. … or at least that’s what I thought! Until I got married and had babies!</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_395x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 395w,
          /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_790x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 790w,
          /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_1580x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 1580w,
          /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_2370x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 2370w,
          /blog/mumgry/images/mumgry_huf144fd544aeb2493469f768cd3b0f2a3_215021_3160x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>Have you heard of the saying, ‘hell hath no fury like a woman scorned’? I’m not so sure it’s comparable to an angry mum! Now I’m coining a new word. <strong>Mumgry!</strong> I can’t be the only one to have felt this silent rage creeping up when your partner is snoring whilst your exhausted body struggles to stay awake and feed the baby? Or when he forgets to load the dishwasher after you cooked dinner, did the laundry, hoovered and painted the Sistine chapel, and says he’ll do it in the morning. It’s that uncontrollable urge to throw a heavy implement at someone you love because for that split second you are seething and just wish they understood the pressure you feel, the exhaustion you’re experiencing and the complete and utter overwhelm that is engulfing you. It’s a time when you feel like your brain has gone to mush, when you can’t remember if you put diesel or petrol in the car. When you breastfeed on demand in a taxi and rush out of the taxi with your boob out until you get home, and no one tells you!</p>

<p>I don’t know the statistics but I’m pretty confident that one of the biggest factors resulting in relationship breakdown is the arrival of children. It changes the dynamics of your partnership. It really separates the men from the boys, and the women from the girls. It exposes your ride or die for the sweet talk he’s been spinning for years. He’s not ride or die, he’s let me sleep or I’ll die! The realisation that this sexy man whom you gave up your uterus for, is now the object of your dissatisfaction and in fact the focus of your vehemence is a little unnerving and can swerve out of nowhere. Even the most laid back of couples can have their mumgry moments. It’s usually a completely understandable response to something that just pushes you over the edge, but because of the new baby and the sleep deprivation people think you’re losing it or are in some hormonal abyss. Hormones may have a huge part to play in it, but it’s also just a whole lot of change and a whole lot of exhaustion, mixed in with expectations, trying to maintain a somewhat functioning household and the fact that sometimes people are just sleep walking into family life and not pulling their weight.</p>

<p>Women tend to be the primary care givers, regardless of the life they had before children, and even those who made more money than their partners unfortunately can’t hand over child bearing duties, and alot of the time the gender stereotypes and society’s perception of the ‘norm’ results in women staying at home, men getting insignificant time off for paternity leave and women left holding the baby.</p>

<p>Somehow we’ve allowed society to tell us that we’re better at nurturing and that essentially gets men off the hook. Maternal instinct doesn’t come naturally for everyone. Most of us have to work at being mums. We learn on the job and it’s tough even for Mary Poppins understudies. But we do our best, and always show up, which is half the battle.</p>

<p>But how do we keep mumgry under control? Just like my detailed planning required to avoid hangry moments, I too need to work on the cues for mumgry ones. And share the trigger points with my partner so he knows what the deal is. So whether it’s chores, finances, sex, socialising, or you’ve simply got beef over hogging the remote control, it’s all fixable, if you both want it to be fixed. Children are an amazing gift that come with unfettered joy and challenges, remind yourself of the love it took to have them and put maintaining that love high on your to do list, above the laundry!</p>

<p>Changing your focus is definitely key. Being comfortable is great, but don’t be complacent. Don’t take your partner for granted, don’t assume anything. Make time for each other. Everyone wants to be heard, understood and loved. Communicate! Write a list of weekly chores and divvy them up. Put it somewhere you can both see. If you both write it the onus on whose responsibility it is to ensure they’re completed changes. It’s our responsibility. If we fail, we fail together, and we can ease the mental load on women just a little bit.</p>

<p>As I write this post, breastfeeding, coughing and full of cold and trying to eat my breakfast. I say that the cough I have is causing me some pain in my stomach. My husbands response is, ‘great babes, those are the muscles where you’re supposed to have abs, you’re building your pack back!’ I can just feel another mumgry moment coming on, so I’m about to play some classical tunes and finish this up! Wishing you light and love and laughter and no police cautions.</p>

<p>I’d love to hear your mumgry moments and if you’ve got any coping mechanisms please share! Thanks for reading! Please like, share and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/">follow me</a>.</p>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Happy Valentines Day</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790" 
                  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-kiss_hub0b9f5cd3ed5bba82b882751731ea36a_6015915_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>Yesterday I found out the hard way that the Swiss don’t do Valentines Day.  I walked around a local shopping centre with the kids (first time in months) hoping to purchase a card, and not a fluffy teddy or heart shaped balloon in sight.  Strange? Refreshing? I’m not entirely sure how I feel about that. I don’t care enough about Valentines Day to really have an opinion.  Maybe that in itself speaks volumes…. Despite my nonchalance, I trudged through the annoyingly brightly lit shopping mall like someone who hasn’t seen daylight for some substantial time.  A journey that should’ve taken me a maximum of 15 minutes ended up being an afternoon of stopping, eating, playing with random chairs, jumping off said random chairs, eating some more, nappy changes, breastfeeding and a small but unwelcome tantrum about Brexit… actually it was about nothing obviously.</p>

<p>I eventually found a semi appropriate card.  Something about love on the front, in English, no text inside. Bish bash bosh!  Thanks, that’ll do!  To be honest, I wasn’t going to buy a card this year, I’ve been feeling like I’ve been dragged through a hedge backwards for some time and the exhaustion and relentless schedule is starting to take it’s toll.  Do you ever feel like you’re sleep walking?  Fire fighting, satisfying a conveyor belt of demands and it just doesn’t stop.  I’ve been shouty, impatient mum for a few days now.  Zero patience with a toddler is like putting washing up liquid in a car engine.  So my frame of mind at present has no room for love hearts and cuddly toys.  A priceless present for me would be an uninterrupted bath with my favourite scented candles…. somehow I’ll make this happen!</p>

<p>Love is love even when he doesn’t take the bins out, when he sleeps through your sleepless nights with the baby and is still apparently knackered.  Love is pushing through the grey matter that fogs your mind and relationship  when the mental load is taking its toll and for once you just wish you didn’t feel like you do it all in military style, forward thinking, back thinking, planning, executing, packing, cooking, cleaning, feeding. Love is sharing the load, being equally knackered, dribbling with exhaustion together in harmony. We love every day, silently over the weetabix,  patiently during laundry days, loudly in the supermarket.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/happy-valentines-day/images/madu-and-tinu-sand_hu71f62084b96601f9eb65f9ddd1abb679_2339850_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>Whatever your situation, love begins with you. Love you, appreciate you.  Buy yourself flowers, get a new frock, get some whipped cream and marshmallows on that hot chocolate, crack open a bottle of red, enjoy a yummy plate, binge on a box set, have a bubble bath, book a mani pedi, go for a nice walk, do whatever makes your heart sing and your mind at peace.  You are loved, you are cherished, you are worthy of love. Whatever you do today, show some love, appreciate the one you take for granted daily, and most importantly, do something you love and love yourself.</p>

<p>Please add a comment below, like, share and follow me on instagram, twitter and facebook.</p>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>I Do…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/images/feature_hu37a066ceaef65215736dc63427c4303c_1755211_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790" 
                  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/i-do/images/feature_hu37a066ceaef65215736dc63427c4303c_1755211_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<p>I thought I’d introduce my other half properly as I’m sure he’ll be featuring in some of my blogs and it’s only polite to give you a brief low down on the man that is the pepper in my stew, custard on my crumble, my Mr Big.</p>

<p>So I started this post initially wanting to introduce our benetton backgrounds but then it struck me that I’m not adequately equipped to really do it justice as we were both born and bred in London and pie and mash are in our veins with a hint of egusi and flying fish. But diverse we are, my parents are Nigerian and husband’s background stems from Barbados, Nigeria and the UK. Despite this eclectic mix which we hold with pride, we’re both fundamentally Londoners, the melting pot that is the big smoke. And currently global citizens of the world.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madtin_hub4757b58b40e6de2afe54dc6cd161c10_465845_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>It just happens that my husband Madu spent the first three years of his life in a small village in Nigeria with his parents. The rest of his formative years were in London, but somehow he’s managed to embody the essence of a southern Nigerian man with little effort! Definitely more nature than nurture! An interesting mix of genetic tendencies and perhaps a desire to belong. It’s funny it’s difficult to define a Londoners cultural identity, it can be a blur of complimentary or sometimes opposing ideals, but whatever the composition we love it.</p>

<p>We met online and have been literally inseparable since our first date in Mango Room. From surprise evenings out in West End to an impromptu week long road trip adventure on one of my work stints in Jamaica. Six months after meeting he quit his job and flew out to propose…we haven’t looked back since.</p>

<p>Yesterday my blender gave up the ghost and I almost cried, it’s been good to me and lasted more years than I care to admit, but owning a blender is synonymous with being a Nigerian. And now I’m in a culinary abyss without it. My other concern is that if I don’t replace it sharpish, so close to Christmas I’ll end up with a new blender from Madu as a present…romance isn’t dead, he’s just pragmatic and Igbo(!) At least that’s what he tells me!</p>

<p>He’s a loving, gentle, technology obsessed man who prides himself on being current, always aims for the best and can negotiate a pay rise with slick aptitude and unrivalled confidence. He taught me to love me more, believes in me when I don’t believe in myself. And encourages me to pursue my dreams. That’s a pretty basic but beautiful asset to have, someone who’s always in your corner.</p>

<p>On the flip side, his confidence borders arrogance at times, he sometimes has a problem with authority, is very opinionated and isn’t scared of being fired for what he believes in. His level of maturity needs to step up a few notches as risks don’t just affect him anymore, and we’re no longer in batchelor territory. Every decision impacts his family. Unemployment is not a word I enjoy discussing over my spag bog, but it’s a conversation I’ve had with him one too many times. But because he is who he is, he knows he can get another well paid job relatively easily….but is that the point? Marriage puts you in situations that you just can’t run away from. It forces you to face another persons bad habits and shortcomings head on. There is nowhere to hide. And once you have children the dynamic further alters as you do all that you can to put them first and maintain a stable loving environment. Being told by your husband that he’s job hunting in your 34th week of pregnancy isn’t fun. But apparently it’s all going to be ok.</p>

<p>Marriage is a complex fusion of hearts and minds. Where Mars and Venus align and two attempt to become one. Where perfectionist Polly is confronted with dirty Daves dirty laundry scattered in obscure parts of the home, often next to the laundry basket….strangely it never quite makes it in. Where unintentional blindness is actually a serious condition. Where multi-tasking is apparently a female attribute and replacing the bog roll is a job that requires deep commitment. A friend of mine once said to me that people often forget that marriage is a journey not a destination. And that’s spot on. It’s a work in progress, a marathon, not a sprint. I’m lucky to have married my best friend, as inscribed on his wedding band, my ride or die.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/i-do/images/madu_hud9a1313d0a45dacbd1405dcc51ce2df7_99259_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>If people were honest about how tough marriage can be, many would probably avoid it or feel less defeated if it eludes them. Marriage is beautiful and life changing and all consuming, and frustrating and exposing. It’s choosing someone to be vulnerable with, to laugh with and ride the waves of life with. It truly is in sickness and in health, through the good times and the bad. It takes resilience, patience, forgiveness and a sense of humour you didn’t know you had.</p>

<p>I don’t remember the last time I went to the toilet alone. And that’s not just my two year old who barges in on me. Lock the door I hear you say! Yes I would if we didn’t have those annoying child safety door stoppers to stop my son from losing precious digits in the hinges! But seriously…can a girl just go in peace?!</p>

<p>If I had any dignity when we got hitched, and I’d like to think I did! It soon evaporated during child birth. A wonderful, eye watering, life altering experience that stripped me back to my core. Madu was an awesome birth partner, attentive and supportive, although confronting me with photographic and video evidence of the birth of our son without my knowledge almost got him fired, apprentice style! We’ve just been blessed with the arrival of our beautiful daughter, here’s my husband having an obviously much needed rest after I’ve given birth(!)</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/i-do/images/sleep_hu2121435d20c8329bd7e27bc603810341_2024313_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>I had a rule when dating years ago, as soon as I liked someone enough to grace them with a second or third date I would ensure I orchestrated a dress down meet up where I wore minimal make up, casual clothes and my hair was in it’s original afro form. I’d do this occasionally if we continued to date and I hadn’t frightened them with my Erykah Badu vibes! I wish more women did this, and they would perhaps be more likely to attract partners that are less superficial! Waking up to put on a full face before your partner wakes up is crazy behaviour. I’d love to hear from women who actually keep this up!</p>

<p>This evening my husband wouldn’t let me finish a sentence and just kept interrupting me. I found it rude and annoying, so as he did it repeatedly I just stopped talking, as clearly he’d prefer to hear the sound of his own voice, so why spoil it for him(!) Then he says I’m harping on about him interrupting me, and just get on with what I have to say….my response to that contains many expletives none of which are suitable for print….marriage gives you a level of patience you didn’t know was possible. And teaches you to forgive even when the other person doesn’t deserve it. It pushes you to prioritise your union and count to a million before you bail. It prevents you from throwing heavy objects at your husband when he jokes about saving money by manually expressing milk rather than buying one of those “over rated pumps”. Marriage is for the mature, the selfless and the committed. Loving someone without condition, loving someone who ate the last import only hobnob and cunningly and perhaps cruelly left the packaging in the cupboard, so you had no idea they were even finished….yes people do that!</p>

<p>Marriage is full of light and wonder, comfort and hope. It has renewed my faith in humanity and given me joy beyond measure and two beautiful children. I’m still understanding what being a wife means, this year I asked for a wife for Christmas…everyone needs a good one! We’re enjoying the learning and the journey. so that’s us the Alikor’s, hopelessly devoted and grateful to have each other.</p>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Say Yes</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
                    
        
        
            <url>https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/images/feature_hu2dbd46e9711a6edef913096b4e75ada8_231367_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg</url>
                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790" 
                  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/say-yes/images/feature_hu2dbd46e9711a6edef913096b4e75ada8_231367_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<p>We moved to Switzerland just over a year ago. It’s been a roller coaster of adjustments, tested the strength of our marriage and my love for fried chicken, or should I say the absence of good chicken. We had discussed moving abroad a little, considered where we’d like to try and my husband joyfully reminisced about a previous experience he had in Switzerland a few years back. I had never been, or heard much about it. It wasn’t on my bucket list of countries to visit, I’m not a big chocolate fan and my interest in cheese is variable. But move here we did, to the beauty that is Zurich, following some research and a passion to try something new, live unapologetically and say yes more!</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/say-yes/images/box_hu98156cfbf905a930fc9c1e2a5fb26330_124054_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>My husband is like a used sales man who could sell a written off fiat punto as a limited edition collectors item. Not that I’m likening Zurich to a clapped out motor… more like high spec Range. So I was sold… changed my work contract to give me supplementary leave, sorted out all my boring admin and packed up our flat and crammed what I could in suitcases, storage and the rest just got trashed.</p>

<p>Scarily final, we arrived in a country I’d never even visited weeks after having surgery on my leg. I was still on crutches and struggled to push the pram and walk at the same time. But somehow I did. Physio at its best! We stayed in temporary accommodation for months! Small bedsit type apartments that I thought were better suited to a bachelor on a stag than a family of 3 attempting to set up home…note to self, ‘do not leave husband in charge of booking accommodation’. We applied for permanent apartments in the notoriously competitive Swiss housing market and were rejected countless times. Our housing applications read like arse kissing resumes, frustratingly detailed and intrusive, and yet still not good enough….blood anyone?</p>

<p>After months of sleeping on broken beds, showering with flip flops on and cooking pasta in someone else’s pot above my sons travel cot, I’d had enough. Having no fixed abode was not only stressful because of the size and lack of amenities, having an active toddler rattling around in a non baby friendly apartment hitting his head on every sharp edge available was eye watering. I couldn’t register for anything as we had no fixed abode, I was in nomadic limbo. I told my husband I was going home until we found somewhere to live that had a bath I could bathe our son in, and four hobs on the stove, and a freezer…yes I am that girl….</p>

<p>‘Home is wherever you hang your hat baby’….’as long as we’re together we’ll be happy’…”save your lyrics for R Kelly, call me when we’ve got somewhere to live babe….and I love you too”.</p>

<p>So I took my son back to London, gratefully returned to our bath and four hobs, and kept on the search for somewhere permanent in Switzerland. I did viewings via Facetime whilst my husband sauntered around the empty apartments showing me the layout, pretentiously wearing a suit to portray the ‘right image’… cue eye roll. Months later we were successful and finally got a break! We signed the contract and were given the keys to our first home in Switzerland! It didn’t tick all of my boxes but compromise is a large pill that must be swallowed fast when your options are limited!</p>

<p>Now we have a place to call home. Relieved and settled, I can now start to make connections with people and I have found my son a nursery and local activities. It’s taken us a year of blood sweat and tears, but we did it. There were times I wanted to give up. I questioned our assessment of the pros and cons and just wanted to be able to find my hair straighteners.</p>

<figure>
    <img src=""
    srcset=""
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>Switzerland is a beautiful country, designed for efficiency, and ideal for young families. It’s charm lies in exploring its breathtaking postcard landscapes and relaxed bubble of safety. The Swiss are reserved, non-confrontational and polite, and yet display an air of frost that ensures that after pleasant introductions you keep your distance. If you’re young free and single I think there are more exciting places to savour, and if you hate recycling I’d give it a wide berth! I have never spent so much time contemplating what to do with rubbish! And my cardboard folding skills are still not up to scratch. Yes they expect you to fold cardboard and tie it neatly in piles for collection on specific days….are you still awake!?</p>

<p>The expat community is large and welcoming, and embraces new comers with enthusiasm, helpful suggestions and friendly recommendations. Switzerland lives on Facebook groups and old barely functional websites. So if you’re craving taramasalata at 2am or need an acupuncturist with a clinic overlooking the lake, someone somewhere will kindly point you in the right direction! My husband enjoys his job and my son loves it here, now I just need to find my place.</p>

<p>Moving here has meant I’ve not been able to work, I’ve put my career on hold to raise our family and get us settled. I’ve been fiercely independent my whole life, the concept of being a housewife despite having a role made me question my worth, and left me feeling vulnerable and itching to do something. Is that what I really want to do? Is it a means to an end? Can I raise a family and still have a thriving career? How do I balance work and childcare? Can i return to my job? The hours were long, travel commitments can be unfavourable and will I be able to afford to work and pay for childcare?</p>

<p>Motherhood often forces you to reassess your choices, your career path and your dreams. Flexible working is no longer a buzz term, it’s something I really need to find, and make it work for me. It’s ok to want to fulfill your dreams and it’s ok to not know where to even begin. But it’s not ok to be riddled with regret and ‘what ifs’. I encourage you to join me in daring to dream, and live your life to it’s fullest potential. Live the best life for you…you are unique and beautiful for your situation. I’m looking for my passion, taking opportunities that arise and simply saying yes! Yes is where the adventure begins!</p>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>