<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
    <title>Journey on Tinu Alikor</title>
    <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/journey/</link>
        <language>en-EN</language>
        <description>Description of your feed</description>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/journey/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

        
        
            <item>
            <title>It&#39;s ok not to be ok…</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
            <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="900" height="600"
                  url="https://www.yoursite.com/img/" />
            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<p><strong>Hey how are you?</strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m good, how are you?</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s so easy to give these knee jerk responses to a casual question we hear daily. And I&rsquo;m by no means suggesting an episode of verbal diarrhoea with boundless content every time someone asks how you are at the supermarket checkout! That would be weird! But when you&rsquo;re in a safe place…and if you don&rsquo;t have a safe place, get one! A safe place, where you can be yourself, a person whom you trust. A real answer is just what the doctor ordered. Honesty breeds healing and progress and gives light to those dark areas in our lives.</p>

<p><strong>Hey how are you?</strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m exhausted, hungry, fed up, disappointed, lonely, depressed and anxious. I got a parking ticket yesterday, I&rsquo;ve got this lingering toothache. I haven&rsquo;t had a shower in two days. The laundry hasn&rsquo;t been done, I&rsquo;ve run out of detergent and milk but forgot to get some in the last shopping trip, so no tea for me today, I can&rsquo;t be dealing with black tea. My job is thankless and monotonous, and my boss hates me. The kids have given me a cold, so now my nose is streaming and as if I&rsquo;m not already sleep deprived enough I&rsquo;m coughing like a chain smoker on helium at night, wheezing and breathless. I&rsquo;m overdrawn on my overdraft, dealing with family conflict, and I think my wife is having an affair. with her personal trainer. We&rsquo;ve been secretly doing IVF and the pressure of the failed cycles is mounting, I&rsquo;m not sure our relationship can endure this battering. We have one last attempt left.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m having a bad hair week, this afro is about to get another big chop if it ain&rsquo;t careful, and I&rsquo;ve gained about 50 pounds in the last month. I need to book a GP appt for myself, I&rsquo;ve had this persistent problem and I need a solution not a placebo… but I&rsquo;m hoping it will just go away if I leave it long enough&hellip;</p>

<p>I woke up this morning and it took me longer than normal to convince myself to face the world. Everyday it seems to be getting more difficult. I&rsquo;ve called in sick a few times at work, but I can&rsquo;t pull a sicky on life. But my response as always if you care to ask is… I&rsquo;m fine.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure if you can relate to any of this, but whatever your challenges and hurdles, whatever is keeping you up at night. It&rsquo;s ok not to be ok. </p>

<p>I see you holding everyone up, holding it all together. Trying to be solid like an ox. Putting on a brave face. Being the foundation that everyone needs, being the rock that you need. Putting everyone before yourself. I see you. I feel you. Carrying the weight around your neck. I see you in the small hours nursing, dreaming of sleep, writing your to do list in the dark, by the light of your phone, responding to messages you&rsquo;d forgotten you even had from last week. I see you awkwardly compressed between a rock and a hard place on your daily 2 hour commute. I see you, working in a job that daily robs you of your joy, quietly stuck in commuter pain, sandwiched between optimism and hopelessness surrounded by people who need to become familiar with deodorant. Overheating, overworked, underpaid and underappreciated. Wondering when the cycle will end. Hoping for deliverance, escape, or the luck of the Irish when that euro millions advert comes on. I see you doing the daily school run, sprinting from the car to the school gates, reciting the list of chores in your head as you head back to the car, praying for a day off. </p>

<p>You pick yourself up when things get tough. People sometimes ask you how you are but rarely listen for the truth. You make excuses for your nearest and dearest, no one seems to care enough, and you&rsquo;re alone, firefighting and trying to keep your head above water.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/its-ok-not-to-be-ok/images/joshua_lake_2_hue5598115f639a42d2e8bfb5284158e7b_2756580_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>If we were honest about how we are feeling if not for public scrutiny, at least for ourselves then maybe we&rsquo;d find the strength to face them and stop saying we&rsquo;re ok, for fear of burdening others, being shunned by others, being misunderstood, or simply ignored. Or maybe sometimes it&rsquo;s easier to just pretend it&rsquo;s not happening and maybe it will all just go away…</p>

<p>Rarely… things rarely just disappear. Sometimes verbalising your truth brings it into reality, shit gets real when you start talking about it. Talking is good. Talking is freedom and relief. Talk to the right people, find solutions and support. But whatever you&rsquo;re going through, however tough or impossible it may seem, there will be an end. I hope you surround yourself with light and love. That you find beauty in ashes. Believe it or not, your worst day to someone else is a dream come true. This week has been exhausting for me on so many levels. I&rsquo;ve had to push through so much pain to get stuff done. I felt drawn to write this post for you to know you&rsquo;re not alone. Don&rsquo;t give up, and speak up. It&rsquo;s ok not to be ok.</p>

<p>Find someone to talk to, who’ll listen, someone you trust who cares, call the Samaritans or just message me, privately&hellip;you’re not alone, be heard.  Thanks for reading! Please like, share and follow me on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/"><i class="fab fa-instagram"></i> Instagram</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.bloglovin.com/blog/19788613/?claim=erkatvubmsc">Follow my blog with Bloglovin</a></p>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>New Beginnings</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 06:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>https://tinualikor.com/blog/new-beginnings/</guid>
            <dc:creator></dc:creator>
            <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="900" height="600"
                  url="https://www.yoursite.com/img/" />
            <description>&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/road_hill_hud4ccc1cfa4451ecf4d15584e0f0ad3ba_556427_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>Today, I’m diving head first into my blog. I’m just as clueless about the start as i am about the finish. But here I am hoping to share my journey with you and express myself creatively, prompted by change, displacement, fear, love, growth, freedom, happiness, adventure and an overwhelming feeling that this is what I’m meant to do….this is what I need to do, and for once it’s something just for me….between me and you.</p>

<p>So who am I??! Million dollar question! I’m a work in progress, an unfinished genuine article, curry without the mango chutney, tasty but missing that je ne sais quoi. My street cred expired with my last library card, circa 1999, RIP. My son of course will think I’m the coolest thing since Tupac and Biggy, I’m working on sustaining that.</p>

<p>I am human, direct, thoughtful, sensitive but resilient. unconfident at times but opinionated, seemingly quiet but fiery. I am a contradiction personified, my background is complex but simple, I bleed red just like everyone else, and my eyes give away my thoughts every time…just the way I like it. I won’t be taking up poker anytime soon.</p>

<p>Educated in a girls school, no interest in boys or girls for that matter until I was at university. Penises are my preference, relationships were a distant goal on my vague checklist of things I’d like to consider doing with my life. Just not that interested I guess or just busy. Tomboy extraordinaire with the scars to prove it turned princess with shin pads. Born and raised in a religious single parent home in London, my boundaries were clear and rarely contested. University catapulted me into a world I never knew existed. It was like releasing an amputated hungry dog amongst chickens. Restrained but ravenous. It gave me a taste of freedom that I had longed for, and I knew that I had to do everything within my power to maintain this light. For freedom is light. And that I did. Moved out of home a few years after returning from university and haven’t looked back since.</p>

<p>Born with a condition called scoliosis, and living with being different my whole life, I’ve learnt to celebrate my uniqueness, push through my insecurities and challenges and make sure ‘can’t’ is permanently removed from my vocabulary. There are so many things people didn’t expect of me, low expectations just fire me on to prove them all wrong. I can and will do anything I put my mind to. Nothing can stop me but me….and If I stop it’s a choice not a weakness. I’ve lived my life optimistically, hoping for the best, living for the best, seeing the best and having the best. Long may it continue.</p>

<p>I’ve been married for 3 years and have a son, and baby on the way. I currently live in Switzerland following a whirlwind romance (apparently), epic honeymoon and baptism of matrimonial fire. My husband is a diamond, he shines when I shine. He’s the epitome of a geeky Flinstone with a hint of Hackney swag. Think Sheldon with the flavour of Nottinghill Carnival. The perfect balance for me. We’ve been literally inseparable since the day we met. Nauseatingly loved up, opposite but cut from the same cloth. He brings balance to my life and loves me like no other.</p>

<p>So we Brexited and left Theresa to sort herself out and end this hockey cokey with the EU, whilst we enjoy the heidi hills and embark on an exciting adventure. It’s been a year since we took the plunge and left Saveloy for Swiss chocolate! And what a year it’s been!! A year of finding our rhythm, finding our place, finding us. An exciting and daunting mix of surprise and the unknown, celebration and grief. Perpetually lost in translation but surrounded by the safety of Swiss etiquette and morality. Moving country is not for the faint hearted. in fact moving country with a baby puts hairs on your chest. We love it here and yet occasionally miss the familiar hustle and bustle of home. Strangely it’s the food I really miss…can a girl just get an eggs benedict please….somewhere?!!! Feeling stronger, more capable, and simply grateful for life. Finding happiness on the way to where we want to be, we’re risk takers. Blessed with the passion and zest for life that motivates us to prefer trying than failing to try at all.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/flight_hua5d537956541a3cfd86e8212ba5b58fb_130208_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>

<p>So yes i currently live in beautiful Switzerland, billy not a lot of mates in the ex-pat community, all of a sudden I’m a professional turned housewife still looking for my inner Nigella to burst out. Struggling with finding a balance, still scratching my afro when filling out the occupation section of admin forms, but enjoying the beauty of the life I have with my best friend.</p>

<p>I’m the kind of girl who never really fit in, and stopped trying to a long time ago! Growing in confidence, perfecting my ability to give less of a shit what people think. Making my own rules and enjoying breaking them when needed. Setting my own standards. Creating my own manual. No idea what tomorrow holds but looking forward to you joining me, navigating it with integrity and fun. Looking for new interests, reviving old ones, cooking like a boss who really enjoys good food, with no time to make it! Window shopping online for my fashion fix, celebrating my natural curls and nervously looking forward to 3 becoming 4! Lets go!</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg"
    srcset="
    
    /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/new-beginnings/images/feature_hudd0083435af24690f53923ecf868f4ec_208191_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    "
    sizes="
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw"/> 
</figure>
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>