<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Pregnancy on Tinu Alikor</title>
        <link>https://tinualikor.com/tags/pregnancy/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pregnancy on Tinu Alikor</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <copyright>2019 - Tinu Alikor - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link href="https://tinualikor.com/tags/pregnancy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>We All Bleed Red</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/we-all-bleed-red/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/we-all-bleed-red/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>pregnancy</category>
            
                <category>discrimination</category>
            
                <category>racism</category>
            
                <category>diversity</category>
            
                <category>motherhood</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/we-all-bleed-red/images/gabriella_hu639f56b8a1e4418ee42a23d160c04111_2487295_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>They say with every cloud…there’s a silver lining.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;They say with every cloud…there’s a silver lining.  Well my grey cloud was lined with silver and gold and just kept giving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My previous blog post outlined some of the challenges I faced during my third pregnancy.  A combination of undiluted discrimination, and physiological challenges, which mainly manifested in pelvic girdle pain and a frightening unexplained extensive period of bleeding during my second trimester.  Unfortunately the treatment I received from medical professions was eye wateringly unacceptable, painful, distressing and completely unimaginable.  Covid has not only levied more pressure on the NHS and its finite resource pool, but also quietly permitted some professionals to take leave of compassion and play roulette with application of their duty of care.  As a black female I have felt mistreated, unheard and experienced a shocking level of exposed vulnerability with no recourse.  Following a lengthy letter of complaint to the hospital and still no concrete outcome or lessons learned, the one step the medical trust initiated because of their failings was to ensure I was supported by a team of midwives called the Lotus Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lotus team support Oxfordshire women and families with a variety of complex needs and provides access to one-to-one holistic midwifery care across all settings.  They aim to improve outcomes and experiences for women and their babies and are part of the maternity services’ ambition of a known midwife for all aspects of care and provides continuity whilst developing relationships with the women under their caseload.  The Lotus Team is part of a variety of measures to help provide individualised care to Oxford’s most vulnerable women as part of the national strategies to address health inequalities across maternity services and reduce neonatal and maternal mortality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the mistreatment I experienced I was essentially gifted a doula on the NHS.  And what a gift she was…
A quirky, mildly eccentric midwife full of love and compassion.  Her priority was to ensure I felt safe and this mantra was at the forefront of every decision she made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having adult children and a successful background in the corporate world, she decided to retrain and become a midwife 2 years ago.  What an inspirational and bold move.  Re-emphasisinig that its never too late to pursue your dreams and doing so may provide the piece to someone else’s puzzle they may never have been able to complete if you don’t take that step.  We met during the pandemic, so I’ll refer to her as my masked angel at times, as I don’t know what she looks like without a mask!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She asked and never assumed, she waited, she listened, she quietly observed me and got to know me even in the handful of encounters we had before my labour day.  She understood why I had been referred to her team, although we never spoke of the detail, she presented her unwavering support to me at every visit, in every phone call, through ever text message.  She slowly and unwittingly established a trusting and safe rapport with me.  She spoke with gentle confidence and encouraged me to consider my options. For the first time in years, and after 2 previous pregnancies, someone asked me what I wanted.  Someone cared that I had a preference, and they were willing to listen and consider how to make that a reality for me. I was no longer powerless or insignificant, or a mute pawn.  I was a woman with wants and needs and fears, and hopes and someone was finally listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a history of relatively quick labours and felt some anxiety at the thought of misreading the signs of labour and potentially having my baby on the hard shoulder en route to the hospital.  Because of the amazing continuity of care, my midwife knew me well enough to know when my situation had changed.  I was hesitant and unsure about labour signs and whether to call her, but knew my body had changed, and she believed me without hesitation and decisively told me to meet her at the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my birth guide was a request for a water birth if the pool was available.  My masked angel found an available room, got me comfortable and secure and told me that I would deliver my baby myself today.  I don’t think I quite digested her words or really comprehended what she was saying.  But she gave me a safe space to deliver my baby girl and told me to reach down and lift her out of the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the most beautiful and life changing experience.  I didn’t have to push, I felt relaxed and safe and as I breathed deeply, the fetal ejection reflex took over and my daughter arrived.  I could not have asked for a better experience.  Following the hurt and painful memories I held previously, what a beautiful chapter to close my birth stories.  Facilitated by support, care, love and empathy.  Every woman deserves to be heard, supported, to feel safe and for their vulnerability to be protected.  Every woman deserves the reassurance, the comfort and the care that I received, and this should not be dependent on their skin colour.  No woman ever forgets their birth story, some remember with pride and some with pain, fear and anxiety.  Whilst no one can determine how labour will unfold, there are so many ways that we can mitigate the trauma that some experience as a result of their birth stories.  This trauma often cascades affecting the family as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Channel 4 aired a documentary on Monday called “The Black Maternity Scandal” giving an insight into the mortality rates of black women during pregnancy and childbirth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What stood out most poignantly for me was the reference to the Joint Committee on Human Rights report entitled - Black people, racism and human rights. It states in the report;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the stark finding from this data that Black women are five times more likely to die in childbirth than white women the report contains no recommendation specifically aimed at reducing that disparity, although it does commit to further research on its causation. The 2018 report noted the issue but merely concluded action is needed to address these disparities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nadine Dorries, the minister for maternity, also declined to be interviewed for the programme further reinforcing the government’s disregard, lack of commitment and inability to respond to the large racist elephant in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quiet cynic in me resents the need to be advocated for, to be listened to via y lotus midwife.  Is my voice not loud enough, strong enough, relevant enough, important enough?  I shouldn’t need the representation of a white impartial midwife to be heard.  But if that’s what it takes to be heard and to survive then i’ll take that for now.  But this isn’t the answer.  We need real systemic, grass roots change.  Black women deserve to be heard, for the narrative to change, for the statistics to matter. The last consideration any woman wants to face is being confronted with her mortality and the real prospect that what began with such hope could end so painfully simply because of her race.  I’m one of the near misses, the unrecorded data that would undoubtedly send an even more alarming message about the value we place on women of colour, because I know I’m not alone. The streets unfortunately are lined with near misses, littered with stories, with trauma so many would rather forget. Those who can tell their stories despite the pain and scars, are seemingly the lucky ones…. still here, survivors. We stand for those who are too traumatised to speak and those no longer here to fight. We want answers, and we deserve change.  We are life givers, let us live ours, without fear of losing at one of the most precious times of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear from you. Please comment, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tinualikor/&#34;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;, like and share!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Freedom Day</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>MyFreedomDay</category>
            
                <category>discrimination</category>
            
                <category>pregnancy</category>
            
                <category>Motherhood</category>
            
                <category>freedom</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/freedom_hu72824833961529480145661fda384d45_219928_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>If it doesn’t have Lycra in it and requires ironing, it’s dead to me.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;If it doesn’t have Lycra in it and requires ironing, it’s dead to me. I’m somewhere in between a size 12 and in denial. No idea what my style is right now. Comfortable? Functional? Clean? Or maybe just not publicly naked?! I can’t legitimately wear maternity clothing anymore….although that stretchy waistband gives me life most days! So for now I’m going with it! Baggy is totally in. Bed hair chic is back and I’m rocking it like it’s 99. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiger marks are appearing in some obscure places but I’m loving the life tattoos. These battle scars are epic and the war has been won!! Well yes I’ve won, I have two beautiful children and I fought through the sickness, the exhaustion, the aches, the doubts, the tests, the sleepless nights, the bladder with a mind of its own, the garlic aversions, the breathlessness, the mumgry moments on the London underground during rush hour, and of course… the labour. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labour… the event that’s pencilled into your diary as a definite, with no definites, no calendar invite needed, this is your party baby!  There’s no opting out of this one, no deferring, it’s the inevitable…that baby is coming to join the world by any means necessary. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t give labour much thought initially. I attended a prenatal class, watched documentaries, my husband banned me from watching as I cried over every episode and read a couple of articles. But nothing really prepared me for the day it all happened. For medical reasons I was told that I may have to have a caesarean section. No one could really explain why, just that it was ‘best’. I spent months of the pregnancy with a small hope that I may be able to give birth naturally, but content with having a C section if that was best for both me and the baby. I have nothing against c sections, it’s just that I’ve spent the majority of my life in and out of hospital, and been on the operating table more times than I care to remember. I take surgery very seriously, and if there’s a path that safely avoids that route, I’ll take that thank you very much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/scan_hub9e2f645a4d5a0e128b169092b18cd75_321566_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day I went into the emergency maternity unit as I couldn’t feel the baby moving as I had before. I was checked over and thankfully all was fine. Before I left, the doctor asked me if I had made a decision on whether or not to have a c section. I reiterated that I still didn’t quite understand why I couldn’t give birth naturally and if this was still an option I’d like to take it. The doctor told me that if I gave birth naturally I would end up having an emergency c section and that in those instances the doctors primary objective is to get the baby out quickly. According to her if in this emergency organs are damaged or arteries cut, that’s just collateral damage I’ll have to accept! Through tears of fear in that cold examination room, I signed the consent forms she shoved in front of me and agreed to have the c section. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C section day arrived… I had my bag packed and my husband and I went to the hospital to meet our baby. The consultants did their early morning rounds before the day began. The consultant introduced himself and asked me how I was and what I was there for. I laughed and said ‘I’m here to meet my baby, and you’ve booked me in for a c-section I don’t even want’. It was a teaching hospital, and surrounded by a group of students they all gawked at me. The consultant then sat on my bed and asked me what I wanted… I explained what had happened and how throughout my pregnancy no one had explained anything to me and I felt invisible, I even had to write my birth plan myself as the midwife said I didn’t need one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one knows how labour will go for anyone, and why was I any different? Unless there’s a clear medical reason that someone can actually explain to me I would rather not have surgery. The doctor smiled, and said ‘you don’t have to do anything you don’t want to do’. He told me to go home. I went home and a week later gave birth to my son naturally. Whether it was possible or not, someone believed I had the right to choose. He empowered me that morning and gave me my voice back. He gave me the freedom to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years later, pregnant again, I  faced similar attitudes and an air of disconnection that I couldn’t quite put my finger on. Last pregnancy I pretty much lived in the hospital, going in weekly for check ups towards the end and being treated like a glass shoe. This time I’ve been seen a handful of times for the mandatory scans and checks, nothing more nothing less. As I’ve given birth naturally once before there was no question as to my ability to do so this time, with the obvious disclaimer that anything can happen during labour! This time around no consultant checks, again no birth plan. Bewildered by the eerie sense of isolation I just got on with it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into labour in the middle of the night, awoken by feelings I’d had a dodgy burrito. Went back to sleep more irritated than in pain…clearly I don’t know what contractions feel like, as this apparently was the start of labour for me. I eventually gave into the discomfort and got dressed to go and get checked out at the hospital, during which the pain increased and I realised I was in labour. We got an uber to the hospital and I was literally struggling not to have the baby in the back seat of the car! We arrived at the hospital, it was quiet… just a dozing security guard who although manning the entrance to a maternity unit seemed mythed that a woman had arrived in the middle of the night in labour…cue eye roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband found a wheelchair and a nurse and I was taken in. I felt a certain sense of relief, that I was in safe hands and that they knew what they were doing, and that it would all be ok. As the pain increased and I begged for someone to help me and give me some pain relief I realised that this may not be the case. I was examined and they quickly assessed I was already 8cm dilated. I kept shouting that the baby was coming, at least give me some gas and air…they insisted on moving me to another room on a different floor! I got to the designated room and told to relax it would ok. I begged for gas and air and none came. I remember in that moment being silent and realising I was on my own. It felt like an out of body experience. I started concentrating on my breathing, focussing on slowing down and blocking out the noise of the panicked midwives. They were fumbling around trying to find the baby’s heartbeat. Amidst the confusion they finally gave me gas and air, my daughters head popped out, they all looked visibly shocked and the rest is history. No one was listening to me, I felt invisible and vulnerable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/freedom_day/images/bump_hu8d7e9d3d01ec13e6a0883354b760ad9a_1535257_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 14 is #MyFreedomDay. Every woman deserves to be heard. To have the freedom to make informed choices about their bodies, to be listened to and understood. To be given the power of autonomy over their fabric, their mind, their uterus. Freedom to decide what’s best for me and my baby. When you take away a woman’s freedom, you strip her of her dignity, you extinguish her power, you make her invisible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women often like to share labour stories. When you’ve had a child it’s almost a right of passage, a conversation that creates bonds. So many people have asked me to share my story, so many have stories that hurt to relive. Labour can be traumatic for some, life changing for all. I don’t know why my cries were ignored, or my wishes mocked, but I hear all too often of the plight of black women in labour and it makes my heart cry. If it had not been for the consultant who sat down and listened to me, my story would have been very different. We may be strong, but we deserve to be heard, everyone deserves this freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
        
            <item>
            <title>Adulting</title>
            <link>https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 16:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/</guid>
            
            <dc:creator>Tinu Alikor</dc:creator>
            
                <category>Miscarriage</category>
            
                <category>Parenting</category>
            
                <category>Children</category>
            
                <category>Pregnancy</category>
            
                <category>Fertility</category>
            
            
        
        
              <media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="790"  url="https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" />
          
         

            <description>Last year I became a member of a club that no one wants to talk about.</description>
            <content:encoded>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Last year I became a member of a club that no one wants to talk about. A club in which membership is one of the most painful experiences most will face in their lifetime and all are pretty much powerless to avoid. We found out we were expecting a baby in December 2017, excited and full of hope and expectation we celebrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/adulting/images/scan_huba66da4fdbcd263f1dbed5daa5b10989_2253212_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As tradition encourages we were hoping to share our good news after the first scan at 12 weeks….we never got to 12 weeks… in fact we never got to 3 weeks We experienced a miscarriage on Christmas Eve last year. I spent the holidays putting on a brave face, trying to behave like nothing had happened, for my sanity, for my son, for us. Inside I was distraught, I rarely get a moment to myself, but when I did, I found myself sobbing, feeling an overwhelming sense of grief. Confused as to what had happened. What had I done wrong? Why had this happened? Did I run too fast for the bus? Did I over exert myself carrying shopping? Did I check the date on that yoghurt that I ate yesterday? Will this consuming fear of going to the toilet ever subside? Will I ever feel like me again? Will this feeling that my body has let me down ever go away?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pregnancy is beautiful and inspiring, and wonderful. Bursting with hope, expectation and dreams. Carrying a life, growing a life, sustaining and nurturing a life is beyond description. Your life changes the moment you read that pee stick, the moment you realise that a life is beginning to take shape. Your imagination begins to run away with itself. Names, hair colour, eye colour, is it going to be a boy or a girl, who will the baby look like, what colour scheme will the nursery have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent 5 gruelling hours waiting to be seen in a soulless hospital in Switzerland that resembled a burnt down housing estate in Peckham. I sat in the cold waiting room watching my son play with the water dispenser and throw all the leaflets neatly piled on the table in the bin, as he joyfully sang ‘tidy up tidy up’ .When I was called in the doctor asked me if I was sure I had been pregnant and did I feel pregnant? That question was like someone sucker punched me in the abdomen…what did she mean was I sure??! Would anyone lie in this situation?!!! She examined me and sent me home as though I had complained of a common cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among women who know they’re pregnant, it’s estimated about 1 in 8 pregnancies will end in miscarriage. 1 in 8 is a shocking statistic considering I only know two people who’ve told me they have experienced miscarriage. I’m not sure why we don’t talk about it, but I wish we did. I wish we spoke about our fears and shared our experiences. It makes us stronger, comforted, better equipped, and helps us to put things in perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got pregnant again, I wish someone told me it was normal to be anxious, to fear going to the toilet daily. To worry yourself into a state of immobilisation. Talking and sharing helps. Someone may find comfort in your story, someone may be going through the same pain and feel lost and alone. Miscarriage isn’t shameful, or embarrassing…it happens to so many of us…men feel it too…it’s out of our control… and takes life altering strength to keep on when you just want to disappear. I share this because I am not ashamed, I am proud that we found strength to persevere, we found healing and I’m grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up I didn’t know if I would ever have children, I guess I never dreamed it would happen. Some spend their lives dreaming and hoping and one miscarriage after another their hopes disappear. There is fulfilment without children, there are so many wonderful opportunities and experiences in the world. Focus on what you have, your blessings, what makes you happy, what makes you smile. There are so many unwanted children that need a home, not enough of us consider adoption. And not all of us are meant to be parents…that’s ok too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I’m in week 8 of being a mother of two….still yet to wake up feeling like I know what I’m doing, or even should be doing….thought that might have happened by now… I’m so grateful for my daughter, she’s an absolute gem. Sleeps, eats, shits, repeats. What more could I ask for?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/adulting/images/olivia_hu204fd731cf5242deb99667415d1deaa8_1969185_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s pretty much a model baby, she’s not the problem, it’s me and trying to work out how on earth I am going to keep two under 3’s alive! My toddler has been ok ish….he’s absolutely in love with the newborn, surprisingly the novelty hasn’t quite worn off yet and he doesn’t think we’re taking her back for a refund! I’ve heard some scary horror stories of toddlers and ‘welcoming’ a new born and thankfully we haven’t had to manage that kind of jealousy. He hasn’t attempted to throw her in the bin or put her in the toilet…so we’re good!! Parents of multiple children, I salute you! Single parents of multiple children…I prostrate…are you even human?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My toddler does however think he’s the newest member of WWF and that my daughter is a potential prop for his wrestling, so the majority of my day is spent keeping the toddler at bay from the newborn, boisterous hugs and belly flops are not welcome! I’m still telling my toddler that the baby’s cot is not the most ideal place for his supersize noisy ambulance and isn’t really the most appropriate place to practice diving from…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://tinualikor.com/blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
    srcset=&#34;
    
    /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_395x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 395w,
          /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_790x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 790w,
          /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_1580x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1580w,
          /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_2370x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2370w,
          /blog/adulting/images/baddass_hu1b998023220b3bd340e6ed1e262c8ad1_2220213_3160x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 3160w

    &#34;
    sizes=&#34;
    (min-width: 830px) 790px,
    100vw&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than bucket loads of patience and repeating ‘be gentle’ and ‘soft hands’ like it’s going out of fashion there are a few things we did to try and prepare our loving toddler for the arrival of his sister. Firstly, everything we could change we changed at least 4 months before she was born. From the stories I’ve heard of toddlers battling for attention and displaying negative behavioural responses to new siblings it just seems like a human. emotionally charged response to a huge change, a change in hierarchy, a change in attention, focus, time, routine. So implementing these changes in stages and trying to remove the connection with the arrival of the new baby seemed liked the best solution. We changed my sons bed, moving him out of his cot and into a bed. We started using a double pram with just him in it. We put him into nursery a few days a week and generally talk about the baby in gentle conversations about his role as a big brother and how important he will be. So my son doesn’t associate any of those changes with the arrival of his sister. She hasn’t ‘taken’ anything that used to be his. Change can create resentment and hostility and that’s what I wanted to avoid. Now I need to work on ensuring that now she is here I create regular one on one time with my toddler. Mummy and Joshua time, where the baby isn’t hanging off my boob, and Joshua gets undiluted Mummy time. The baby sling is my new best friend. I can see this being a very steep learning curve…any tips throw them my way!!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</content:encoded>
            </item>
        
        
    </channel>
</rss>